<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Office365 on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/office365/</link><description>Recent content in Office365 on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 11:06:28 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/office365/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>New tutorial: build your custom provisioning solution for Office 365</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/new-tutorial-build-your-custom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 11:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/new-tutorial-build-your-custom/</guid><description>&lt;p>I couple of days ago I had the opportunity to animate a workshop with the amazing Franck Cornu at the Modern Workplace Conference Paris.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We decided to make all the labs available under PnP for you to learn new technologies and patterns.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you follow the steps described in the labs, you will learn about technologies like Azure Logic Apps, Azure Functions, the Microsoft Graph, Azure Durable Functions, SharePoint WebHook, PnP Provisioning and much more.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at the European SharePoint Conference 2019 - SPFx &amp; DevOps</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-european-share-2019-10-01-18-14-00/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 18:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-european-share-2019-10-01-18-14-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>The ESPC is one of the biggest technology events in Europe and the biggest with focus on Office 365, SharePoint and Azure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An interesting particularity of this event, they move to a different European capital each year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This years edition will be from &lt;strong>December 2nd to 5th in Prague&lt;/strong> and I&amp;rsquo;m honored to be invited to speak again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting two sessions:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>How to do DevOps with the SharePoint Framework and why it matters?&lt;/strong> This session will be an introduction to DevOps practices and an application of the core principles in a SharePoint Framework context.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at the European SharePoint Conference 2018 and free discount for you!</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-european-share-2018-08-26-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-european-share-2018-08-26-08-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-european-share-2018-08-26-08-00-00/4.png" alt="4.png">
I am delighted to announce I have been selected to speak at the European SharePoint Conference 2018. &lt;strong>This event will take place in Copenhagen, Denmark from the 26th to the 29th of November.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I will be speaking about “&lt;strong>Migrate your custom components to the SharePoint Framework&lt;/strong>”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“&lt;em>It’s the 3rd model Microsoft has come with to customize SharePoint in less than 5 years. You may still have add-ins/apps or even solutions running in production and you’re asking yourself what to do about all that?&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Less than three weeks before the #SPSMontreal 2018!</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/less-than-three-weeks-before-t/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/less-than-three-weeks-before-t/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://baywet.github.io/less-than-three-weeks-before-t/9.jpg" alt="9.jpg">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This year again I have the privilege to be part of the organizing committee for SharePoint Saturday Montréal 2018 taking place June the 2nd at Cégep du vieux Montréal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s free, it’s the occasion to learn a lot, not only about SharePoint but also about Office 365 and Azure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This year in a few numbers:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>25 sessions (in English and French)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Keynote by the Great Serge Tremblay&lt;/li>
&lt;li>16 Microsoft MVP (Most Valuable Professional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 MSP (Microsoft Student Partner)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5 MCT (Microsoft Certified Trainers)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>9 partners&lt;/li>
&lt;li>200 attendees (planned)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Besides the content, it’s also the occasion to develop your network, eat some Schwartz (smoked meat) and “SharePint” (Share a pint) !&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Detroit 2017</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-11-16-17-26-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 17:26:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-11-16-17-26-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Detroit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll give a speech about “&lt;strong>Improving DevOps using Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Business Productivity Tools and more&lt;/strong>” and I&amp;rsquo;ll be &lt;strong>co-presenting the session with my friend &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HCroitoru" title="twitter profile">Haniel Croitoru&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>We&amp;rsquo;ll explore together how DevOps practices impact and improve solutions delivery for your customers and for the best. With real life scenarios and experience for the field we&amp;rsquo;ll show you how you can get started and what to expect out of it.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Brussels 2017</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-07-13-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-07-13-08-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Brussels.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll give a speech about the Azure functions and Microsoft flow “&lt;strong>Introduction to Azure Functions and Flow&lt;/strong>”.
Flow and Azure Functions are two new tools you now have for rapid applications development. It’s a revolution that changes the way of building and delivering modern applications. Instead of shipping a monolithic bloc, which can take up to a few months, we’ll now deliver each feature as a part of the solution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Re-awarded Microsoft MVP for year 2017 2018</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/re-awarded-microsoft-mvp-for-y/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/re-awarded-microsoft-mvp-for-y/</guid><description>&lt;p>You may not know it but Microsoft has changed the organization of the MVP program during these last few years.
They used to nominate new MVP’s every 3 months and renew people every year on anniversary date.
One of the changes the brought to the program is around the renew and nomination cycles. New MVP’s are awarded every month and existing ones are renewed all together every year in July.
I used to be an “April MVP” and I was used to blogging about my renewal in April.
I’m pleased to announce I’ve been renewed MVP for year 2017-2018 on the Office Servers and Services category.
Let’s go for another year :)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Ottawa 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-11-29-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-11-29-14-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Ottawa.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll give a speech about the graph “Making Graph data useful to your company”. We’ll talk about the Graph, delve, yammer, machine learning and a lot of other interesting concepts and the conversation will be aimed towards developers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re in the area Saturday December the 3rd 2016 don’t hesitate to register to the event.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Brussels 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-09-22-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-09-22-14-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year I have the privilege to speak at SPS Brussels&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll give a speech about “setting up your release pipeline for office 365/SharePoint”. (aka devops)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We’ll see together how you can leverage azure and visual studio team services to implement devops processes and increase quality and save time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re in the area on Oct the 15th don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions. This is a good occasion to expand your network, learn a lot of things and to spend a good day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Oslo 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-09-15-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-09-15-14-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year I have the privilege to speak at SPS Oslo&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll give a speech about “setting up your release pipeline for office 365/SharePoint”. (aka devops)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We’ll see together how you can leverage azure and visual studio team services to implement devops processes and increase quality and save time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re in the area on Oct the 22nd don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions. This is a good occasion to expand your network, learn a lot of things and to spend a good day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Detroit 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-09-09-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-09-09-14-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year I have the privilege to speak at SPS Detroit&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll give a speech about “setting up your release pipeline for office 365/SharePoint”. (aka devops)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We’ll see together how you can leverage azure and visual studio team services to implement devops processes and increase quality and save time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re in the area On Sept the 10th don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions. This is a good occasion to expand your network, learn a lot of things and to spend a good day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Determine whether or not a SharePoint library is running with the new experience</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/determine-whether-or-not-a-sha/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/determine-whether-or-not-a-sha/</guid><description>&lt;p>Microsoft just released the new experience for SharePoint libraries and I know a lot of you built custom look and feel and/or components on top of the library ui. (I’m thinking in particular about ScriptLink actions)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You might be in a situation where the code you need to run will be different depending on the experience being used.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a little bit of research, here is an example of solution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Calgary 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-04-04-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-04-04-14-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year I have the privilege to speak at SPS Calgary (first time!!). I’ll give a speech about “Make Graph data useful for your company”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We’ll see how we can leverage the new Microsoft Graph API and Machine Learning tools to build “clever” applications for our business.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re in the area Saturday April the 23rd 2016 don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions. This is a good occasion to expand your network, learn a lot of things and to spend a good day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Houston 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-04-01-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-04-01-14-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year I have the privilege to speak at SPS Houston (first time!!). I’ll give a speech about “Setting up your release pipeline for SharePoint and Office 365 developments”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We’ll see how you can automate all the things to make your development team more productive and more efficient. For that we’ll see how to set up build and release definitions and how you can leverage both azure and on premises environments&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SharePoint apps (add-ins) JavaScript disappeared</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/sharepoint-apps-add-ins-javasc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 04:09:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/sharepoint-apps-add-ins-javasc/</guid><description>&lt;p>At Negotium we recently came across a weird problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let’s assume you previously built a Provider hosted app for SharePoint.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now let’s assume you updated to the latest version of the SDK (April/May update)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally let’s assume your tenant has been updated recently (v16.0.4121.1212 or above)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s likely that you are loading SP.*.js files and MicrosoftAjax.js the way it used to be recommended by Microsoft per say: &amp;lt;HostWebUrl&amp;gt;/_layouts/15/jsfile.js or &amp;lt;AppWebUrl&amp;gt;/_layouts/15/jsfile.js.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SPBizConf</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-spbizconf/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 22:58:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-spbizconf/</guid><description>&lt;p>The SPBizConf (&lt;a href="https://www.spbizconf.com/">https://www.spbizconf.com/&lt;/a> ) will happen on June 17th and 18th of 2015.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This conference is mostly oriented towards business users (with a bit of technical content) and is free and online.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Don’t wait to sign up!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll have the opportunity to give a session about the Graph. We’ll have a theoretical part to ensure everybody has got basis, a part talking about Microsoft’s Graph and Microsoft’s vision around the Graph to wrap up with a part with real business cases and explain how you could use it in your company.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Presenting at the MVP Showcase 2014</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/presenting-at-the-mvp-showcase/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2014 03:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/presenting-at-the-mvp-showcase/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>As some of you know, this is my first year as an MVP. Next week will be the MVP summit and I’m very exited about it.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For those whom don’t know it, Microsoft is actually bringing 1800+ persons from all around the world to their headquarters so they can share information with them and gather feedback.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have a huge week coming up, well I can’t really say anything more about it, pretty much everything is under NDA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Have all the tools of a first class startup's in 10 min</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/have-all-the-tools-of-a-first/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2014 04:00:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/have-all-the-tools-of-a-first/</guid><description>&lt;p>Through my career I had the chance to be involved in several startups or small businesses trying to create a product or digital service. However a question arises very quickly:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>How to have effective working tools while minimizing the financial impact?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And by impact financial I also mean the time spent to implement, because it is time that it not spent on its core business, or more generally to create added value.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Availability of office 365 Samples and SDK on Github</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/availability-of-office-365-sam/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 16:53:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/availability-of-office-365-sam/</guid><description>&lt;p>For those who have not seen it yet Microsoft teams who work on Office 365 have created a hub on GitHub.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/officedev">https://github.com/officedev&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What are you going to find there?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Examples of code made by Microsoft and the community&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Demonstrations presented during the sessions from Microsoft and the community&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Part of the &amp;lsquo;documents&amp;rsquo; sources for the MSDN documentation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SDK for &amp;rsquo;third&amp;rsquo; platforms (IOS, android&amp;hellip;)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>…&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The message behind that is Microsoft is investing in the community and wants to create a single place where developers (from any platform) can meet to participate in the projects together and share content. Therefore do not hesitate to have a look and to submit content / patches / projects.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The roadmap for Office 365 is available</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/the-roadmap-for-office-365-is/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2014 04:29:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/the-roadmap-for-office-365-is/</guid><description>&lt;p>For those who are interested in knowing what&amp;rsquo;s upcoming on office 365, Microsoft recently shared publicly the roadma.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can see what Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s teams are developing directly from this page, which will be updated on regular basis &lt;a href="https://office.microsoft.com/en-us/products/office-365-roadmap-FX104343353.aspx">https://office.microsoft.com/en-us/products/office-365-roadmap-FX104343353.aspx&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://officeblogswest.blob.core.windows.net/wp-content/2014/06/improvingvisibility_01.png" alt="screen roadmap">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Auto-hosted applications are deprecated</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/auto-hosted-applications-are-d/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2014 19:31:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/auto-hosted-applications-are-d/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="reminders">Reminders&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Auto-hosted apps are &lt;strong>only available for SharePoint online&lt;/strong> (office 365), it bundles and provisions at each installation an &lt;strong>azure web site&lt;/strong>(and eventually a sql azure database).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That made &lt;strong>hosting&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>tenancy management&lt;/strong> (isolating customers’ data) and &lt;strong>authentication&lt;/strong>way easier because most of the configuration part was automated.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="announce">Announce&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We’ve been wondering how these apps were going to evolve for a while. Indeed SharePoint 2013 came out more than a year ago in production on office 365 and we still were not able to:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Outstanding announcements of the SharePoint Conference 2014 for Office 365</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/outstanding-announcements-of-t/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2014 02:38:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/outstanding-announcements-of-t/</guid><description>&lt;p>Microsoft has given much information during the SharePoint Conference 2014. It is sometimes difficult to not miss something, so I made a summary of information that marked me.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="storage-evolution-1-tb-and-beyond">Storage evolution 1 TB and beyond!&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>During the SharePoint Conference 2014 Microsoft announced a significant change in the limitations of SharePoint Online Storage: 1 TB Max per site collection (including the &amp;ldquo;mysite&amp;rdquo; or onedrive for business) and unlimited storage (understanding billed per GB) by tenant.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Anonymous access for SharePoint autohosted apps</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/anonymous-access-for-sharepoin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 17:03:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/anonymous-access-for-sharepoin/</guid><description>&lt;p>These days I’ve been working on an auto hosted app for SharePoint (office 365 actually).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I had to grant an anonymous access to one of the pages without requiring clients to give anonymous access to their SharePoint site. But I still needed to read a few properties from the App Web web site (the SPWeb provisioned by SharePoint when installing an app)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I had to play around a lot but I finally found the solution:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SharePoint Auto hosted app and ASP.NET MVC</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/sharepoint-auto-hosted-app-and/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 04:16:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/sharepoint-auto-hosted-app-and/</guid><description>&lt;p>Code apps they said, it will be easier they said…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Visual Studio 2013 comes with a new project model : SharePoint autohosted app ASP.NET MVC (Cool!)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m fond of SharePoint, I like MVC, why not mixing them?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Short reminder, SharePoint autohosted apps are only available for Office 365. Technically Office 365 will create an Azure website on demand when app is deployed. The potential cost overhead will be billed directly to the tenant owner.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>