<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Online on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/online/</link><description>Recent content in Online on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 11:06:28 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/online/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Counting Down to ESPC20 Online</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-espc2020/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-espc2020/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="thecountdown-ison-to-espc20-online--only-7-weeks-to-go">The countdown is on to ESPC20 Online – only 7 weeks to go!&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>ESPC20 Online is a new virtual conference offering you affordable, world-class Microsoft 365 learning at your fingertips, from wherever you are in the world. Tune in live Oct 14th &amp;amp; 15th or catch up on-demand across 100+ sessions from SharePoint, Office 365 &amp;amp; Azure experts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Join me for my ESPC20 Online session: &lt;strong>Build Responsive Applications at Scale using Microsoft Graph Change Notifications with Resource Data&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SystemUpdate method available in CSOM at last!!!</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/systemupdate-method-available/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/systemupdate-method-available/</guid><description>&lt;p>That’s good news for SharePoint developers, the SystemUpdate method is finally available in Client Side Object Model.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Indeed, Microsoft has recently released an update for nugget packages and the method is part of the new stuff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://dev.office.com/blogs/new-sharepoint-csom-version-released-for-Office-365-august-2016-updated">https://dev.office.com/blogs/new-sharepoint-csom-version-released-for-Office-365-august-2016-updated&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s an important method because it allows you to update a list item without changing modification date, author, publishing and versioning information.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moreover, we’re numerous SharePoint developers migrating a lot of full trust solutions to SharePoint Add-ins, some of which were using this method and in some cases we have only an app-only context. Usage of this method instead of the regular update method will avoid having documents last updated by “SharePoint App”.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Determine whether or not a SharePoint library is running with the new experience</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/determine-whether-or-not-a-sha/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/determine-whether-or-not-a-sha/</guid><description>&lt;p>Microsoft just released the new experience for SharePoint libraries and I know a lot of you built custom look and feel and/or components on top of the library ui. (I’m thinking in particular about ScriptLink actions)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You might be in a situation where the code you need to run will be different depending on the experience being used.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a little bit of research, here is an example of solution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Programmatically add permissions to “everyone” in SharePoint Online</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/programmatically-add-permissio/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/programmatically-add-permissio/</guid><description>&lt;p>At some point you may want to add permissions to the “everyone” “groupe” of SharePoint.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Indeed this will allow you to set permissions to all users already having access to this site (because they are already members of other groups or already have permissions). This “group” is different of “NT AUTHORITY\authenticated users » which represents successfully identified users (bigger group).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The only thing is that “group” is in fact a user, so it’s helpless to iterate on every group of the site collection hoping to find it. It’s in fact a special user. To find it just use it’s login: &amp;ldquo;c:0(.s|true&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New Microsoft Conference: the AzureCon</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/new-microsoft-conference-the-a/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/new-microsoft-conference-the-a/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hi everybody!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Short post to let you know that Microsoft recently announced a new event: the AzureCon. First edition on Sept the 29th.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This free online event will focus on Microsoft’s cloud technologies (mostly Azure) and will be about news and things to come on the platform.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Great speakers, awesome content, this is the occasion for you to learn a lot about Azure technologies and their usage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This conference should happen multiple times a year (approximately 4), main reason being: ”with releases and updates every 3 weeks for each service, we simply couldn’t wait for an annual event to announce everything like we do with Ignite and Build” (Microsoft Azure Product Manager)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaker at Collab365</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaker-at-collab365/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaker-at-collab365/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://baywet.github.io/speaker-at-collab365/83.jpg" alt="83.jpg">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve been greatly honored being selected to be speaker at collab 365.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This event directly comes from the sp24 with the spbiz which happened a few months from now. It’s a free online event which will take place on October the 8th during 24 hours all around the globe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Adding to the fact I’ll be speaking at this event among other great speakers, I also have the great privilege to give 4 sessions (oh yeah!).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SPBizConf</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-spbizconf/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 22:58:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-spbizconf/</guid><description>&lt;p>The SPBizConf (&lt;a href="https://www.spbizconf.com/">https://www.spbizconf.com/&lt;/a> ) will happen on June 17th and 18th of 2015.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This conference is mostly oriented towards business users (with a bit of technical content) and is free and online.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Don’t wait to sign up!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll have the opportunity to give a session about the Graph. We’ll have a theoretical part to ensure everybody has got basis, a part talking about Microsoft’s Graph and Microsoft’s vision around the Graph to wrap up with a part with real business cases and explain how you could use it in your company.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MVP Virtual Conference</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/mvp-virtual-conference/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 22:34:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/mvp-virtual-conference/</guid><description>&lt;p>American (US, Canada, Latin…) Microsoft MVP’s are organizing a two days free online conference on May the 14th and the 15th.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to know which sessions will be available you can click here&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://mvp.microsoft.com/en-us/virtualconference-agenda.aspx">https://mvp.microsoft.com/en-us/virtualconference-agenda.aspx&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To register to the event &lt;a href="https://mvp.microsoft.com/en-us/virtualconference-sessions.aspx">https://mvp.microsoft.com/en-us/virtualconference-sessions.aspx&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll be the moderator for Sébastien Levert’s session “introduction to AngularJS applications in Office 365”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a great opportunity to connect with experts from all around the world.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>