<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tools on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/tools/</link><description>Recent content in Tools on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 07:59:57 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Git Migration – cleaning up TFS references</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/git-migration-cleaning-up-tfs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/git-migration-cleaning-up-tfs/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently had to migrate multiple source repositories from TFS to GIT (Git on vsonline). To do so I used Git Tfs &lt;a href="https://github.com/git-tfs/git-tfs">https://github.com/git-tfs/git-tfs&lt;/a> which does the job and is well documented &lt;a href="https://github.com/git-tfs/git-tfs/blob/master/doc/usecases/migrate_tfs_to_git.md">https://github.com/git-tfs/git-tfs/blob/master/doc/usecases/migrate_tfs_to_git.md&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There’s one step where they instruct you to remove *.vspscc and *.vssscc files and to clean up *.sln and *.*proj files from TFS references.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This will prevent Visual Studio from trying to reconnect to TFS every time you open the project/solution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Office developers tools november 2014 update</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/office-developers-tools-novemb/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 01:56:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/office-developers-tools-novemb/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you work in SharePoint development you probably already have noticed that the tools are getting a new update.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With previous versions Microsoft.SharePoint.Client.Search and Microsoft.SharePoint.Client.Search.Applications dll’s were not included (it most likely has been forgotten)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You then had two solutions:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Ensure that all developers had SharePoint binaries installed on their machines&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Embed a copy of the dll taken from a SharePoint machine&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Both solutions were not very practical.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These dlls are now included for version 15 and 16 located here C:\Program Files\Common Files\microsoft shared\Web Server Extensions\&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Have all the tools of a first class startup's in 10 min</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/have-all-the-tools-of-a-first/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2014 04:00:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/have-all-the-tools-of-a-first/</guid><description>&lt;p>Through my career I had the chance to be involved in several startups or small businesses trying to create a product or digital service. However a question arises very quickly:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>How to have effective working tools while minimizing the financial impact?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And by impact financial I also mean the time spent to implement, because it is time that it not spent on its core business, or more generally to create added value.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Migrating Team Foundation Server 2010 to Visual Studio Online: difference of process model</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/migrating-team-foundation-serv/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 03:54:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/migrating-team-foundation-serv/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="context">Context&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In my company (&lt;a href="https://www.negotium.com/">www.negotium.com&lt;/a> ) we are trying to achieve a significant migration for us people of development: TFS 2010 to visual studio online (ex tfs online).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This will bring many new opportunities and tools to our way of developing and it will allow our IT Department to decommission a (several in fact) machine. I&amp;rsquo;m preparing a more complete article on the benefits of the solution online from the online edition.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>