<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pnp on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/pnp/</link><description>Recent content in Pnp on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 11:06:28 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/pnp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>New tutorial: build your custom provisioning solution for Office 365</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/new-tutorial-build-your-custom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 11:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/new-tutorial-build-your-custom/</guid><description>&lt;p>I couple of days ago I had the opportunity to animate a workshop with the amazing Franck Cornu at the Modern Workplace Conference Paris.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We decided to make all the labs available under PnP for you to learn new technologies and patterns.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you follow the steps described in the labs, you will learn about technologies like Azure Logic Apps, Azure Functions, the Microsoft Graph, Azure Durable Functions, SharePoint WebHook, PnP Provisioning and much more.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Recording available PnP Call December 5th - Office 365 CLI externalize</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/recording-available-pnp-call-d/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 10:56:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/recording-available-pnp-call-d/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was invited to demonstrate the new Office 365 CLI externalize command during on the of recent PnP calls.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can watch the full call &lt;a href="https://developer.microsoft.com/en-us/office/blogs/sharepoint-framework-community-call-recording-5th-of-december-2019/">here&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a reminder this new command allows you to scan a SPFx project and get the external configuration automatically.
Doing this reduces greatly the size of your solutions, improving performances for end users.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can watch the command in action below and read the documentation &lt;a href="https://pnp.github.io/office365-cli/cmd/spfx/project/project-externalize/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Customizing page layouts, master pages and image renditions in SharePoint Online</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/customizing-page-layouts-maste/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/customizing-page-layouts-maste/</guid><description>&lt;p>Microsoft recently made changes around look and feel customizations for SharePoint Online.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you create a new site collection and try to edit page layouts, master pages or even image renditions, there’s a high chance you’ll get an access denied error message. That even if you’re site collection administrator.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Investigating further and checking your permissions on the master page gallery library, you will notice that every and each user has a “deny” permission for “Add and Customize Pages”. That permission level is not one of the originals we’re used to in SharePoint.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Publishing SharePoint Image renditions with PnP Provisioning</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/publishing-sharepoint-image-re/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/publishing-sharepoint-image-re/</guid><description>&lt;p>A couple of days ago, I had to work again with Image Renditions in SharePoint. We’re developing a intranet for one of our customer and that solution partially relies on publishing features.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just as a reminder, image renditions were introduced back in 2013 to help you serve the most optimized version of an image without having the information workers caring about sizes and whatnot or without you having to resize images with code.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>