<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nyc on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/nyc/</link><description>Recent content in Nyc on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 11:06:28 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/nyc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday New York City 2018</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-06-27-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-06-27-08-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-06-27-08-00-00/8.jpg" alt="8.jpg">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS NYC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll give a speech about “&lt;strong>Migrate your custom components to the SharePoint Framework&lt;/strong>”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Together we will see how you can transition from either the server-side object model or the add-ins development fashions to the modern SharePoint Framework approach. This session is mostly meant for developers and technical architects who are curious about getting started on the new model and that might have legacy applications.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday New York City 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-05-25-01-11-00/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 01:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-05-25-01-11-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS NYC&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.spsevents.org/city/nyc/nyc2015">https://www.spsevents.org/city/nyc/nyc2015&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My session will be about the importance of metadata in your company.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We’ll start by some reminders around the theory and describe what are the advantages and disadvantages of different types of each. Then we’ll see what’s currently supported by SharePoint and what are the available tools. Finally we’ll talk about why it is so important that you set this up in your companies, how it can improve findability of content and how it will help you to move to the Graph.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>