<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Error on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/error/</link><description>Recent content in Error on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 07:59:57 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/error/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>unable to find version '3.1.2' of package 'appforsharepointonlinewebtoolkit'</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/unable-to-find-version-312-of/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/unable-to-find-version-312-of/</guid><description>&lt;p>With office development tools for visual studio 2015 (and probably with august 2015 update for vs 2013 too, but I haven’t tried it), you may run into the following error:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>unable to find version &amp;lsquo;3.1.2&amp;rsquo; of package &amp;lsquo;appforsharepointonlinewebtoolkit&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And so while doing an “update-package” in nuget console or if you have a restore packages step in your build process. (mandatory if like me you don’t include the packages folder into source control).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>(English) The name 'InitializeControl' does not exist in the current context Controles utilisateur, SharePoint 2013 and Ressources</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/the-name-initializecon/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2013 21:21:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/the-name-initializecon/</guid><description>&lt;p>This article is written for SharePoint developers who already developed multilingual webparts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is a good practice to localize an application when you develop for SharePoint, which will make the adding of a new language easier.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When we developed for SharePoint 2010 we used to put resources files in hive/config/resources (and then run a stsadm –o copyappbincontent or automate it via a timerjob when activating features)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Or we used to create an empty SharePoint solution element in which we added our files and indicated that the deployment target was the appglobalresources folder (see &lt;a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/296003/deploy-a-resource-file-to-app-globalresource-folder-on-activation">https://stackoverflow.com/questions/296003/deploy-a-resource-file-to-app-globalresource-folder-on-activation&lt;/a> for more details)&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>