<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Moving to a new location and celebrating a decade of blogging</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/new-blog-location/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/new-blog-location/</guid><description>Welcome to my new blog! Welcome to my new blog on github.io, powered by open source. I&amp;rsquo;ll be shutting down the old one so make sure you update your RSS subscriptions.
10 years of blogging Can you believe it? I&amp;rsquo;ve been blogging for 10 years now! At the time I was almost a Microsoft Student Partner and my first blog post (in French) was about cloud computing (which was a new thing back then).</description></item><item><title>Joining Microsoft as a Program Manager on the Microsoft Graph</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/joining-microsoft-as-a-program/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 11:22:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/joining-microsoft-as-a-program/</guid><description>TL; DR I’ll be starting at Microsoft as a Program Manager on the Microsoft Graph in January. This is an exiting change and I’d like to take the time to thank 2toLead for the amazing last few years.
New role I’m exited to announce I’ll be starting at Microsoft in January as a Program Manager on the Microsoft Graph (and other Microsoft Identity Platform topics). I’ll be part of the MIP organization and in the extended team of brilliant people like Yina Arenas, Jeremy Thake, Darrel Miller and many more.</description></item><item><title>New tutorial: build your custom provisioning solution for Office 365</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/new-tutorial-build-your-custom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 11:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/new-tutorial-build-your-custom/</guid><description>I couple of days ago I had the opportunity to animate a workshop with the amazing Franck Cornu at the Modern Workplace Conference Paris.
We decided to make all the labs available under PnP for you to learn new technologies and patterns.
If you follow the steps described in the labs, you will learn about technologies like Azure Logic Apps, Azure Functions, the Microsoft Graph, Azure Durable Functions, SharePoint WebHook, PnP Provisioning and much more.</description></item><item><title>Recording available PnP Call December 5th - Office 365 CLI externalize</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/recording-available-pnp-call-d/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 10:56:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/recording-available-pnp-call-d/</guid><description>I was invited to demonstrate the new Office 365 CLI externalize command during on the of recent PnP calls.
You can watch the full call here
As a reminder this new command allows you to scan a SPFx project and get the external configuration automatically. Doing this reduces greatly the size of your solutions, improving performances for end users.
You can watch the command in action below and read the documentation here.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at the European SharePoint Conference 2019 - SPFx &amp; DevOps</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-european-share-2019-10-01-18-14-00/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 18:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-european-share-2019-10-01-18-14-00/</guid><description>The ESPC is one of the biggest technology events in Europe and the biggest with focus on Office 365, SharePoint and Azure.
An interesting particularity of this event, they move to a different European capital each year.
This years edition will be from December 2nd to 5th in Prague and I&amp;rsquo;m honored to be invited to speak again.
I&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting two sessions:
How to do DevOps with the SharePoint Framework and why it matters?</description></item><item><title>Recording available: Microsoft Graph September Community call - Provisioning demo</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/recording-available-microsoft/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 14:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/recording-available-microsoft/</guid><description>Last September I was invited to speak again on the Microsoft Graph Community call. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know about it, this free online monthly call brings together Microsoft Product Team members and Community members demonstrating new capabilities and real world examples.
It is a great way to catch up on the latest news and I highly recommend you attend it if you work with the Microsoft Graph or would like to.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Ottawa 2019</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2019-10-01-14-12-00/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 14:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2019-10-01-14-12-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Ottawa and I&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting &amp;ldquo;Introduction To The Microsoft Graph: Getting Started Quickly &amp;amp; Getting The Most Out Of It&amp;rdquo;.
Together we will cover the basics of the Microsoft Graph, the Microsoft Identity Platform, the value it provides to developers and how to get started.
If you’re in the area Saturday October the 5th 2019 don’t hesitate to register to the event.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at Microsoft Build 2019</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-microsoft-build-20/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-microsoft-build-20/</guid><description>I am deeply honoured and humbled to announce I have been selected to speak at the Microsoft Build 2019, which will be happening from May 6th to 8th in Seattle.
The subject is going to be a bit different from my usual speaking area however, we will be talking aboutIoT, health and wellbeing.
Here is the abstract of the session.
Using IoT to improve people’s health and brain power
The office space is a hostile environment for our bodies and health.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Fest DC 2019</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-fest-dc-2019-04-18-07-35-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 07:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-fest-dc-2019-04-18-07-35-00/</guid><description>SharePoint Fest Washington DC 2018 is happening from April 29th to May the 3rd. This event will feature 2 days pre-conference workshops and 3 days of conference. You can find more information about it on the website. I&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting three sessions:
DEV104 - Migrate your custom components to the SharePoint Framework
Migrate your custom components to the SharePoint Framework.
It’s the 3rd model Microsoft has come with to customize SharePoint in less than 5 years.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Houston 2019</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2019-04-02-02-00-00/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2019-04-02-02-00-00/</guid><description>It is the second time in a few years I have the ooportunity to speak at the SharePoint Saturday Houston.
I’ll give a speech about &amp;ldquo;Automating Provisioning For Your Digital Workplace: With Azure Durable Functions &amp;amp; Microsoft Graph&amp;rdquo;
Together we will see how you can improve your provisioning workflows and automate most of it leveragingAzure Durable Functions and the Microsoft Graph. This session is geared mostly towards developers but also for IT pros and deciders that want to gain insights on how to combine business processes and provisioning.</description></item><item><title>SharePoint Framework 1.8.0 and unit testing: bad Karma</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/sharepoint-framework-180-and-u/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/sharepoint-framework-180-and-u/</guid><description>Sorry, I had to make the pun…. When the SharePoint Framework originally shipped, the tooling included KarmaJSto write unit tests.
KarmaJS received a lot of complaints about performance, capabilities, modern JavaScript support… This especially if you use is in combination with PhantomJS, a headless web browser project that has been abandoned a long time ago now which also shipped with SPFx.
While some peoplehave been arguing for a choice in unit testing framework with SPFx like we (almost) have choice in web frameworks, we saw little movement on that front over the last years.</description></item><item><title>SharePoint Framework and DevOps Practices: New Documentation, New Samples</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/sharepoint-framework-and-devop/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/sharepoint-framework-and-devop/</guid><description>TL; DR; With the release of Azure DevOps, there’s some new SPFX documentation to set up your CI/CD pipeline in Azure DevOps. Have a look and share your thoughts. Your feedback is always welcome! The Patterns and Practices Initiative also includes a newly reorganized DevOps repository for tools and samples around SharePoint Framework Build and Deploy Practices.
The long story My journey into the SharePoint DevOps world I have been working around Application Lifecycle Management (ALM), Continuous Integration (CI), Continuous Deployment (CD) and DevOps practices in the SharePoint/Azure/Office 365 ecosystem for several years.</description></item><item><title>Guest of the Intrazone podcast</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/guest-of-the-intrazone-podcast/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/guest-of-the-intrazone-podcast/</guid><description>As 2018 is concluding (we’ll be in 2019 by the time this blog post is published), I’ve taken a few days off to rest, spend time with the family, play video games, read, watch movies and… catch up on my blog posts writing.
Almost a month ago now I was presenting at the SharePoint Saturday Toronto, huge thanks to Eric Riz, Kanwal Khipple and Noorez Khamiz for organizing the event! More importantly, they had to find a new venue at the last minute because the original one was forced to closed done for a few days and they pulled it off!</description></item><item><title>Presenting at the Microsoft Ignite Tour Toronto</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/presenting-at-the-microsoft-ig/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/presenting-at-the-microsoft-ig/</guid><description>The Microsoft Ignite tour is a series of events that take place in cities around the world. This series of events is organized by Microsoft and presenters are picked among Microsoft Employees, Regional Directors and MVPs.
I’ll have the opportunity to present one session “How to do DevOps with the SharePoint Framework and why it matters?”. During this session we will explore together how you can setup your continuous integration and continuous deployment pipeline leveraging Azure DevOps (formerly Visual Studio Team Services).</description></item><item><title>Speaking at Granite State SharePoint Users Group</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-granite-state-shar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-granite-state-shar/</guid><description>On January the 3rd I’ve been invited to speak (virtually) at the Granite State SharePoint Users group. I’ll be presenting the session “The Microsoft Graph and the SharePoint Framework on steroids with Azure Functions”.
This session will demonstrate how you can tap into a wealth of data and insights from the Microsoft Graph, interact with the user using the SharePoint Framework and extend components with complex line of business logic leveraging serverless Azure Functions.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Toronto 2018</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-11-20-09-00-00/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-11-20-09-00-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Toronto.
I’ll give a speech about “Migrate your custom components to the SharePoint Framework”.
Together we will see how you can transition from either the server-side object model or the add-ins development fashions to the modern SharePoint Framework approach. This session is mostly meant for developers and technical architects who are curious about getting started on the new model and that might have legacy applications.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Ottawa 2018</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-10-10-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-10-10-08-00-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Ottawa. It has become a regular event for me. This SPS is really dear to me because not only I get to see a lot of Canadian MVPs friends but it also was the first event ever I was presenting in (a broken) English a long time ago.
This year I&amp;rsquo;ll present &amp;ldquo;The Microsoft Graph and SharePoint Framework under steroids with Azure functions&amp;rdquo; or how these three technologies really represent a power trio to build customizations in Office 365.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday New England 2018</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-08-27-05-00-00/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-08-27-05-00-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS New England.
I’ll give a speech about “Improving DevOps using Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Business Productivity Tools and more” and I&amp;rsquo;ll be co-presenting the session with my friend Haniel Croitoru.
We&amp;rsquo;ll explore together how DevOps practices impact and improve solutions delivery for your customers and for the best. With real life scenarios and experience for the field we&amp;rsquo;ll show you how you can get started and what to expect out of it.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at the European SharePoint Conference 2018 and free discount for you!</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-european-share-2018-08-26-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-european-share-2018-08-26-08-00-00/</guid><description>I am delighted to announce I have been selected to speak at the European SharePoint Conference 2018. This event will take place in Copenhagen, Denmark from the 26th to the 29th of November.
I will be speaking about “Migrate your custom components to the SharePoint Framework”.
“It’s the 3rd model Microsoft has come with to customize SharePoint in less than 5 years. You may still have add-ins/apps or even solutions running in production and you’re asking yourself what to do about all that?</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Pittsburgh 2018</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-08-23-05-00-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-08-23-05-00-00/</guid><description>I Have the pleasure to announce I have been selected to speak at SPS Pittsburgh 2018.
I’ll give a speech about the graph “How to do Dev-Ops with the SharePoint Framework and why it matters”.
Together we’ll see why it’s important to follow the DevOps processes, methodologies, and philosophy and how to implement it for the SharePoint Framework with Visual Studio Team Services (or TFS). Go from the original idea to production automating as much as possible!</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Fest Seattle 2018</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-fest-se/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-fest-se/</guid><description>SharePoint Fest Seattle 2018 is happening from August 20th to 24th. This event will feature 2 days pre-conference workshops and 3 days of conference. You can find more information about it on the website. I’ve been selected amongst 74 other speakers (including people from Microsoft product teams!!) to present this year two sessions:
AZR203 - Azure Functions In The Real World: Lessons Learned &amp;amp; Best Practices “Azure Functions is one of the most powerful new solutions provided by Microsoft.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Charlotte 2018</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-08-06-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-08-06-08-00-00/</guid><description>I Have the pleasure to announce I have been selected to speak at SPS Charlotte 2018.
I’ll give a speech about the graph “How to do Dev-Ops with the SharePoint Framework and why it matters”.
Together we’ll see why it’s important to follow the DevOps processes, methodologies, and philosophy and how to implement it for the SharePoint Framework with Visual Studio Team Services (or TFS). Go from the original idea to production automating as much as possible!</description></item><item><title>Guest on the Microsoft Graph Community call (June): The Online Meeting Solution</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/guest-on-the-microsoft-graph-c/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/guest-on-the-microsoft-graph-c/</guid><description>I must admit I’ve not been on page lately for the blog posts. However, I had the privilege (among other great speakers) to present during the Microsoft Graph Community call for the month of June.
Microsoft Graph Community calls are online webinar organized by the Microsoft Graph Team. The Team usually presents announcements and then allows time for community speakers to presents discoveries, real life solutions and lessons learnt with the Microsoft Graph.</description></item><item><title>Guest on the Microsoft 365 Dev Podcast: Microsoft Graph Open Extensions and Calendering</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/guest-on-the-microsoft-365-dev/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/guest-on-the-microsoft-365-dev/</guid><description>Last week I had the honor to be a guest on the Microsoft 365 Dev Podcast hosted by Jeremy Thake and Paul Schaeflein.
It was the second time I was invited on a podcast (the first one being in French about devops), this is a fun exercise where the content is delivered as a discussion between the hosts and the guests.
During this episode we discussed about two main topics:</description></item><item><title>Not Office Servers and Services MVP anymore, becoming Office development MVP</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/not-office-servers-and-service/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/not-office-servers-and-service/</guid><description>Renewed as MVP and changed category I have the pleasure to announce I’ve been renewed as a Microsoft MVP, for the fifth year in a row (time flies, I’m getting old). A slight change this time, my award is Office development.
Over the years I’ve been a SharePoint MVP, an Office Servers and Services MVP and now an Office development MVP.
Originally Microsoft had it’s MVPs organized by products, which made a lot of sense in a on premises world which required a deep knowledge in something very specific.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday New York City 2018</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-06-27-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-06-27-08-00-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS NYC.
I’ll give a speech about “Migrate your custom components to the SharePoint Framework”.
Together we will see how you can transition from either the server-side object model or the add-ins development fashions to the modern SharePoint Framework approach. This session is mostly meant for developers and technical architects who are curious about getting started on the new model and that might have legacy applications.</description></item><item><title>Less than three weeks before the #SPSMontreal 2018!</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/less-than-three-weeks-before-t/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/less-than-three-weeks-before-t/</guid><description>This year again I have the privilege to be part of the organizing committee for SharePoint Saturday Montréal 2018 taking place June the 2nd at Cégep du vieux Montréal.
It’s free, it’s the occasion to learn a lot, not only about SharePoint but also about Office 365 and Azure.
This year in a few numbers:
25 sessions (in English and French) 1 Keynote by the Great Serge Tremblay 16 Microsoft MVP (Most Valuable Professional) 1 MSP (Microsoft Student Partner) 5 MCT (Microsoft Certified Trainers) 9 partners 200 attendees (planned) Besides the content, it’s also the occasion to develop your network, eat some Schwartz (smoked meat) and “SharePint” (Share a pint) !</description></item><item><title>Speaking at the #Techorama Belgium 2018 about the #MicrosoftGraph</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-techorama-belg/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-techorama-belg/</guid><description>This year again I have the honour to be selected to speak at the Techorama Belgium 2018.
It is a paid event taking place at the Kinepolis Antwerp (attending/speaking in a cinema theater is really cool!) from May 23rd and 24th. They have a great content, great speakers (many folks from Microsoft or other MVPs) and if you haven’t booked your ticket yet, I suggest you do!
I’ll be giving two sessions that are related:</description></item><item><title>Internet Explorer compatibility mode is changing on SharePoint Online</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/internet-explorer-compatibilit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/internet-explorer-compatibilit/</guid><description>The history being this situation…. Internet Explorer has been a corporate browser for two decades now. And many of us remember the dark ages of web development when we needed to have “IE compatible code” and “web compatible code”.
As many companies invested deeply in the browser building portals that worked with specific versions, Microsoft provided a decade ago a compatibility mode, allowing the browser to “behave” like a former version of itself and stay compatible with websites that had not been updated.</description></item><item><title>Git: fork/import/manual copy, keep it clean</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/git-forkimportmanual-copy-keep/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/git-forkimportmanual-copy-keep/</guid><description>Part of my role at 2toLead is to help set guidance around best source management practices either internally or for our customers. One of the questions I get often is: Should I fork this repository or do something else with it?
It’s hard to get clear and simple guidance on the web so I thought I’d take a stab at it.
As we’re using Visual Studio Team Services, my examples and screenshots will be based on it, but it really applies to any git service like Github or internal git servers.</description></item><item><title>New SharePoint Framework PnP Samples available: using the Skype UCWA Web SDK to subscribe to people’s status</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/new-sharepoint-framework-pnp-s/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/new-sharepoint-framework-pnp-s/</guid><description>TL;DR; I added two new SharePoint framework WebParts PnP sample to demonstrate how to use the Unified Communications Web API JavaScript SDK from Skype for business. This SDK allows you to do things like subscribe to a person status, start instant messaging conversations, calls…
To get a look:
The plain JS sample The reactJS + Office UI Fabric React sample(persona card) Long version I recently had the occasion to make my first contribution to PnP (besides creating issues and helping investigate those).</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Fest DC (Washington) 2018</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-fest-dc-2018-01-05-09-00-00/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-fest-dc-2018-01-05-09-00-00/</guid><description>SharePoint Fest DC (Washington) 2018 is happening from March 26th to March 30th. This event will feature 2 days pre-conference workshops and 3 days of conference. You can find more information about it on the website. I’ve been selected amongst 44 other speakers to present this year two sessions:
AZR204 – Microsoft Graph and SharePoint framework under steroids with Azure Functions “Modern development means client side first, backend second. However, there are still cases where you might need some backend processing, for long running operations, heavy computing consuming tasks or security concerns.</description></item><item><title>Full version of lodash now available in the SharePoint Framework</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/full-version-of-lodash-now-ava/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/full-version-of-lodash-now-ava/</guid><description>TL; DR; Microsoft replaced @types/es6-collections by the es2015.collection library in version 1.4.0 of the packages. Those had a conflicting definition of weakmap which caused issues with packages like lodash.
Long version Microsoft recently release v1.4.0 of the SharePoint Framwork and it’s packages. It contains a lot of improvements and one of those probably went unnoticed by many of us.
@types/es6-collections has been replaced by es2015.collection library (native, comes with the compiler/JS Engines).</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Detroit 2017</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-11-16-17-26-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 17:26:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-11-16-17-26-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Detroit.
I’ll give a speech about “Improving DevOps using Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Business Productivity Tools and more” and I&amp;rsquo;ll be co-presenting the session with my friend Haniel Croitoru.
We&amp;rsquo;ll explore together how DevOps practices impact and improve solutions delivery for your customers and for the best. With real life scenarios and experience for the field we&amp;rsquo;ll show you how you can get started and what to expect out of it.</description></item><item><title>Using PnP PowerShell on Visual Studio Team Services (VSTS) Hosted Agent</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/using-pnp-powershell-on-visual/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/using-pnp-powershell-on-visual/</guid><description>Visual Studio Team Services (VSTS) provides great Continuous Integration (CI) and Continuous Deployment (CD) functionalities you can leverage to implement DevOps pipelines and automation with your custom developments.
If your custom solutions rely on PnP PowerShell during their build and/or deployment processes, you will need PnP PowerShell to be installed on the agent. Unfortunately the Hosted Agents do not have PnP PowerShell installed by default. Note: that documentation only applies to the Hosted and Hosted 2017 agents, the Linux Hosted Agent is not supported at the moment</description></item><item><title>Determine your technical debt using SonarQube - Conclusion</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-10-06-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-10-06-08-00-00/</guid><description>Installing and setting up SonarQube may seem quite complex and tedious.
I hope that this series has helped you to go faster implementing it.
Now, you can clearly identify your technical debt and take actions to improve the quality of your developments.
It is obvious that when a thousand problems appear in the code at once, it can be discouraging, just keep this in mind:
There are false positives, make a first pass to ignore/exclude those</description></item><item><title>Determine your technical debt using SonarQube - Bonus SonarLint extension configuration</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-10-04-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-10-04-08-00-00/</guid><description>TL; DR You can display SonarQube static analysis results live in Visual Studio error and information console using the same rules set as the SonarQube project.
Installing the extension
Just go to https://www.sonarlint.org/VisualStudio/index.html and proceed with the installation.
Binding the Visual Studio solution to the SonarQube analysis From the Team Explorer click SonarQube
Click on connect.
(if you obtain a certificate error, you must install the self-signed certificate of the SonarQube server on your machine)</description></item><item><title>Determine your technical debt using SonarQube - Monitoring the results</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-10-02-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-10-02-08-00-00/</guid><description>TL; DR Static analysis errors will appear as of the warnings in the compilation section. A static analysis badge will also appear on the build report and you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to have detailed and comprehensive information from SonarQube.
Information incorporated with the build When displaying the details of a build, you&amp;rsquo;ll now find a new section dedicated to SonarQube. Within that section, besides the quality badge, you&amp;rsquo;ll also find a link to the static analysis results details.</description></item><item><title>Determine your technical debt using SonarQube - Creating the SonarQube project</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-29-08-00-00qwqw/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-29-08-00-00qwqw/</guid><description>TL; DR SonarQube allows you to create projects. These projects will hold your code analysis results. You can configure a SQ project for each code repository or even for each branch to have different deltas. (ex my master builds every month, I want to see changes to the monthly and my dev builds daily so I want to see evolution on a day by day basis).
Creating the project Go to &amp;ldquo;configuration&amp;rdquo;-&amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;Projects&amp;rdquo;-&amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;Management&amp;rdquo; then &amp;ldquo;create project&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Determine your technical debt using SonarQube - Updating your build definitions</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-29-08-00-00labd/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-29-08-00-00labd/</guid><description>TL; DR Static analysis will be executed when building your source base using the central build machine. You have two options to set this up with VSTS:
Your project is &amp;ldquo;Visual Studio&amp;quot; related and leverages sln and cs/vb proj files: in that case you can leverage integrated pre and post build tasks provided by the SonarQube VSTS extension. Your project is not build using msbuild: in that case you must leverage the SonarQube CLI task.</description></item><item><title>Determine your technical debt using SonarQube - Creating and configuring a service account for VSTS in SonarQube</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-27-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-27-08-00-00/</guid><description>TL; DR To prevent anyone from sending analysis results to our SonarQube installation, we need to secure the access to its services. To do so, we&amp;rsquo;ll configure a service account.
Creating the service account From SonarQube, go to administration, security, users, and add an account.
Next click on the &amp;ldquo;tokens&amp;quot; cell for the account we just created an generate a new personal access token.
You can also refer to that documentation if you&amp;rsquo;re not sure how to generate a PAT https://docs.</description></item><item><title>Determine your technical debt using SonarQube - Setting up Azure Active directory for authentication</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-25-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-25-08-00-00/</guid><description>TL; DR We will install and configure an add-on to delegate authentication to Azure Active Directory. This will allow our developers to use the same account between Visual Studio Team Services and SonarQube.
Configuration of the authentication module
Since version 5.4 SonarQube provides an additional plugin relying on the OAuth protocol to communicate with AAD. This will allow the users to leverage their corporate account to access SonarQube, providing SSO and simplifying the administrators job by having a central identity repository.</description></item><item><title>Determine your technical debt using SonarQube - Adding modules</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-22-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-22-08-00-00/</guid><description>TL; DR Static analysis works by leveraging rules. These rules are grouped by language or language categories in modules that you can install. In addition to providing support for the subsequent languages, these modules can extend the native capabilities of SonarQube.
Most of them are free, some are subject to commercial licenses.
Installing Add-ons Open SonarQube and go to configuration, system, search for and install the modules that you&amp;rsquo;re interested in.</description></item><item><title>Determine your technical debt using SonarQube - Opening SonarQube’s ports</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-20-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-20-08-00-00/</guid><description>TL; DR Open ports 22, 9000, 80 and 443 inbound on the VM.
Details of the opening of ports Rather than repeating what is already documented, I will provide you with the link
https://Github.com/baywet/azure-docker-SonarQube#step-2-opening-firewall-ports
It is necessary to open the ports 22, 80, 443 and 9000 allowing respectively to access the machine remote shell, load http and https content, and access the management console.</description></item><item><title>Determine your technical debt using SonarQube - Installing the machine</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-18-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-18-08-00-00/</guid><description>TL; DR We will update the machine, install docker, and provision the containers we need.
Installation of docker and updating the machine Connect to the machine using SSH (Putty is a very good client for windows) and run the following commands:
https://Github.com/baywet/azure-docker-SonarQube#step-4-Setup-docker
Setting up containers, creating the certificates The containers are the components of our system managing the web traffic and providing the SonarQube service.
To secure connections, we will also generate self-signed SSL certificates which is not the easiest thing to do when someone is not used to working with linux environments.</description></item><item><title>Determine your technical debt using SonarQube - Creating the database</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-15-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-15-08-00-00/</guid><description>TL; DR Create a db sql azure with collation set to SQL_Latin1_General_CP1_CS_AS.
Details of the database creation The SQL Azure database creation steps are already well described, crucial detail: use the following collation: SQL_Latin1_General_CP1_CS_AS. (and use a blank template)
https://Github.com/baywet/azure-docker-SonarQube#step-3-create-the-azure-SQL-database
Keep the database access settings (FQDN of the server, username, password, the database name) somewhere, we will need those later.
Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to open the firewall of the SQL Server for connections from Azure.</description></item><item><title>Determine your technical debt using SonarQube - Provisioning the SonarQube VM</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-13-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-13-08-00-00/</guid><description>TL; DR We&amp;rsquo;ll provision a ubuntu server in Azure, and install Putty and WinSCP on your local machine
Details of provisioning Here is a link to a documentation explaining how to do it
https://Github.com/baywet/azure-docker-SonarQube#step-1-create-the-virtual-machine-in-Azure
This is! the machine is being provisioned!
Meanwhile take the opportunity to download a SSH terminal if you don&amp;rsquo;t have one, I recommend https://www.PuTTY.org/ (you can also install WinSCP that will also provide a GUI to transfer files)</description></item><item><title>Determine your technical debt using SonarQube - What parts to use?</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-11-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-11-08-00-00/</guid><description>TL; DR Planning, Sources, Build, deployment, testing: VSTS. Analysis: Azure VM (SonarQube), Azure SQL.
Parts of our software factory Because we use a maximum of services cloud at 2toLead I realized the following installation:
Source control: VSTS (git or tfsvc, doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter) Build system: build 2015 VSTS Build machine: provided by VSTS as a service SonarQube machine: Ubuntu Server hosted in Azure Data SonarQube: Azure SQL Database, 10 DTU Note that to facilitate the management of the SonarQube &amp;ldquo;box&amp;quot; we are going to install Docker on the ubuntu machine.</description></item><item><title>Determine your technical debt using SonarQube - Static analysis</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-08-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-08-08-00-00/</guid><description>TL; DR Static analysis allows you to understand weaknesses of your code based on a set of rules. You can have it run automatically on a server or from the IDE.
Introduction to static analysis The principle of static analysis is to take advantage of rules set more or less complex, those will detect patterns in the code that are problematic, categorize their importance and suggest a resolution.
A few examples:</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Ottawa 2017</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-09-07-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-09-07-08-00-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Ottawa.
I’ll give a speech about the graph “Migrate your custom components to the SharePoint Framework ”. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how you can migrate your existing investments in SharePoint development (either full trust solutions or add-ins) to the new SharePoint framework. Migrating these components will not only help you make sure you stay ahead of the technology but will also improve users experience and help migrating to Office 365.</description></item><item><title>Determine your technical debt using SonarQube - Introduction</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-06-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-06-08-00-00/</guid><description>TL; DR This series will explain *how to set up an automated code quality analysis* which is almost free of charge with Visual Studio Team Services, Docker, Azure, and SonarQube.
Preamble There is bad quality code in every development project. This goes from the quick and dirty hack we are not proud of, to the long-forgotten code written by a developer who quit the company.
The problem with this code is that it will eventually accumulate and slow down the pace of new features delivery.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Brussels 2017</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-07-13-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-07-13-08-00-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Brussels.
I’ll give a speech about the Azure functions and Microsoft flow “Introduction to Azure Functions and Flow”. Flow and Azure Functions are two new tools you now have for rapid applications development. It’s a revolution that changes the way of building and delivering modern applications. Instead of shipping a monolithic bloc, which can take up to a few months, we’ll now deliver each feature as a part of the solution.</description></item><item><title>Re-awarded Microsoft MVP for year 2017 2018</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/re-awarded-microsoft-mvp-for-y/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/re-awarded-microsoft-mvp-for-y/</guid><description>You may not know it but Microsoft has changed the organization of the MVP program during these last few years. They used to nominate new MVP’s every 3 months and renew people every year on anniversary date. One of the changes the brought to the program is around the renew and nomination cycles. New MVP’s are awarded every month and existing ones are renewed all together every year in July. I used to be an “April MVP” and I was used to blogging about my renewal in April.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday New York City 2017</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-07-06-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-07-06-08-00-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS NYC. I’ll give a speech about the SharePoint Framework and devops methodologies “Is it possible to do devops with the SharePoint framework?”. You had it all right with solutions and add-ins. Your release pipeline was set up. Do new technologies and methodologies mean starting over? Don’t panic I’m here to help! Together we’ll see how to set up a devops pipeline for SPFX developments with:</description></item><item><title>SharePoint Framework in my own words</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/sharepoint-framework-in-my-own/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/sharepoint-framework-in-my-own/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re following the SharePoint community, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard of the &amp;ldquo;SharePoint framework in his own words&amp;rdquo; video series. https://www.voitanos.io/ is behind that initiative
( @andrewconnell founded voitanos recently)
The idea is to get the thoughts from the community and people who have been around the SharePoint development for a few years. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know that series I&amp;rsquo;d encourage you to check it out and I also hope that the product team behind the framework is listening the that super valuable feedback.</description></item><item><title>Update to _spPageContextInfo type definitions - new properties available</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/update-to-sppagecontextinfo-ty/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 07:07:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/update-to-sppagecontextinfo-ty/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re building modern SharePoint components (Framework or not), there&amp;rsquo;s a high chance you&amp;rsquo;re using TypeScript.
In that case you&amp;rsquo;re probably using @types/SharePoint to provide auto-completion as well as some level of understanding for the compiler of what&amp;rsquo;s going on.
There&amp;rsquo;s one object in particular that SharePoint hydrates for us to give some understanding of where the user is and what he/she is doing: _spPageContextInfo.
A lot of properties were missing in those type definitions, old stuff like the web Id but also new things coming from SharePoint Online like canUserCreateMicrosoftForm.</description></item><item><title>Customizing page layouts, master pages and image renditions in SharePoint Online</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/customizing-page-layouts-maste/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/customizing-page-layouts-maste/</guid><description>Microsoft recently made changes around look and feel customizations for SharePoint Online.
If you create a new site collection and try to edit page layouts, master pages or even image renditions, there’s a high chance you’ll get an access denied error message. That even if you’re site collection administrator.
Investigating further and checking your permissions on the master page gallery library, you will notice that every and each user has a “deny” permission for “Add and Customize Pages”.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at Techorama Belgium 2017</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-techorama-belgium/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-techorama-belgium/</guid><description>Techorama is a 2-day event that takes place in Antwerp, Belgium from May 22nd to May 24th.
They lined up great speakers from Microsoft and other big industry players, checkout the agenda here https://techorama.be/agenda/
I have the pleasure to announce I’ve been selected and I’ll be giving two sessions:
Set up your DevOps process for SharePoint/Office365
Migrate your custom components to the SharePoint framework
Tickets are still available so if you are in the area or can travel there I would strongly suggest you check-it out!</description></item><item><title>Publishing SharePoint Image renditions with PnP Provisioning</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/publishing-sharepoint-image-re/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/publishing-sharepoint-image-re/</guid><description>A couple of days ago, I had to work again with Image Renditions in SharePoint. We’re developing a intranet for one of our customer and that solution partially relies on publishing features.
Just as a reminder, image renditions were introduced back in 2013 to help you serve the most optimized version of an image without having the information workers caring about sizes and whatnot or without you having to resize images with code.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Vancouver 2017</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-03-09-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-03-09-14-00-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Vancouver.
I’ll give a speech about the SharePoint Framework and devops methodologies “Is it possible to do devops with the SharePoint framework?”.
You had it all right with solutions and add-ins. Your release pipeline was set up. Do new technologies and methodologies mean starting over?
Don’t panic I’m here to help! Together we’ll see how to set up a devops pipeline for SPFX developments with:</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Calgary 2017</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-03-07-16-00-00/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-03-07-16-00-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Calgary.
I’ll give a speech about the Azure functions and Microsoft flow “Introduction to Azure Functions and Flow”.
Flow and Azure Functions are two new tools you now have for rapid applications development. It’s a revolution that changes the way of building and delivering modern applications. Instead of shipping a monolithic bloc, which can take up to a few months, we’ll now deliver each feature as a part of the solution.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at Aos Tours Ottawa and Toronto</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-aos-tours-ottawa-a/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2017 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-aos-tours-ottawa-a/</guid><description>I’ll have the privilege to speak at next AOS (Azure, Office 365, SharePoint) in Ottawa (8th) and Toronto (10th).
I’ll present in English: Introduction to Azure Functions and Flow
Flow and Azure Functions are two new tools you now have for rapid applications development. It’s a revolution that changes the way of building and delivering modern applications. Instead of shipping a monolithic bloc, which can take up to a few months, we’ll now deliver each feature as a part of the solution.</description></item><item><title>Joining 2ToLead</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/joining-2tolead/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/joining-2tolead/</guid><description>Big step for me during this 2016 celebrations season as I decided to leave Negotium for 2ToLead
Good Bye Negotium Since I joined AlphaMosaik more than four years ago (I originally joined only for 18 months huh…), by the acquisition by Negotium and up to this day my working environment and the company I was part of changed a lot.
This company allowed me to maturate and to learn a lot on cultural, personal and professional aspects.</description></item><item><title>Troubleshooting load balancing issues with SharePoint</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/troubleshooting-load-balancing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/troubleshooting-load-balancing/</guid><description>A few weeks ago, I’ve had to get hands on a customer’s SharePoint farm showing performance problems. They also had inconsistencies with display data between multiple calls.
I quickly suspected a configuration issue for the load balancer dispatching calls between the front-end servers. However, I only had access to the SharePoint farm and I had to provide data so the network team so they could start investigating.
Hence the question: how can we determine which server served the request between multiple calls?</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Ottawa 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-11-29-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-11-29-14-00-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Ottawa.
I’ll give a speech about the graph “Making Graph data useful to your company”. We’ll talk about the Graph, delve, yammer, machine learning and a lot of other interesting concepts and the conversation will be aimed towards developers.
If you’re in the area Saturday December the 3rd 2016 don’t hesitate to register to the event.
Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions.</description></item><item><title>Old English posts migrated to this blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/old-english-posts-migrated-to/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/old-english-posts-migrated-to/</guid><description>Everything is in the title. My French blog has been running for more than six years now (gee, I’m getting old).
From 2013 to 2014, before I decided to open an English dedicated blog, I was posting every blog entry in English and in French.
Over time it got messy for both communities so I decided to open this blog. But I couldn’t move the old content to this new blog without having to spend hours doing so.</description></item><item><title>Update: continuous integration for dot net core</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/update-continuous-integration/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/update-continuous-integration/</guid><description>A few months ago I published articles about continuous integration for dot net core projects.
Obviously it was really early in this “new framework” lifecycle (we were still on a beta version back then) and the tooling plus processes evolved a lot since.
Good news is you don’t need anymore a complex and often crashing powershell script. You don’t need anymore special tasks either other than standard command line and azure publishing tasks.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Brussels 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-09-22-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-09-22-14-00-00/</guid><description>This year I have the privilege to speak at SPS Brussels
I’ll give a speech about “setting up your release pipeline for office 365/SharePoint”. (aka devops)
We’ll see together how you can leverage azure and visual studio team services to implement devops processes and increase quality and save time.
If you’re in the area on Oct the 15th don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions.</description></item><item><title>SystemUpdate method available in CSOM at last!!!</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/systemupdate-method-available/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/systemupdate-method-available/</guid><description>That’s good news for SharePoint developers, the SystemUpdate method is finally available in Client Side Object Model.
Indeed, Microsoft has recently released an update for nugget packages and the method is part of the new stuff.
https://dev.office.com/blogs/new-sharepoint-csom-version-released-for-Office-365-august-2016-updated
It’s an important method because it allows you to update a list item without changing modification date, author, publishing and versioning information.
Moreover, we’re numerous SharePoint developers migrating a lot of full trust solutions to SharePoint Add-ins, some of which were using this method and in some cases we have only an app-only context.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Olso 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-09-15-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-09-15-14-00-00/</guid><description>This year I have the privilege to speak at SPS Olso
I’ll give a speech about “setting up your release pipeline for office 365/SharePoint”. (aka devops)
We’ll see together how you can leverage azure and visual studio team services to implement devops processes and increase quality and save time.
If you’re in the area on Oct the 22nd don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Detroit 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-09-09-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-09-09-14-00-00/</guid><description>This year I have the privilege to speak at SPS Detroit
I’ll give a speech about “setting up your release pipeline for office 365/SharePoint”. (aka devops)
We’ll see together how you can leverage azure and visual studio team services to implement devops processes and increase quality and save time.
If you’re in the area On Sept the 10th don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions.</description></item><item><title>New tasks to build/release dotnetcore project with vsts</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/new-tasks-to-buildrelease-dotn/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 14:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/new-tasks-to-buildrelease-dotn/</guid><description>A few months ago I wrote a series of articles on how to set up a release pipeline for dnx/dotnetcore projects with vsts targeting azure web apps.
This series would require you to use a few scripts to build and publish the website executing them using powershell tasks in the build definition.
You don’t need to do that anymore because two new extensions are available on the marketplace:
I’ve been able to replace most of my scripts using VSTS DNX Tasks</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday New York City 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-07-30-09-28-00/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2016 09:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-07-30-09-28-00/</guid><description>This year I have the privilege to speak at SPS New York City.
I’ll give a speech about “setting up your release pipeline for office 365/SharePoint”.
We’ll see together how you can leverage azure and visual studio team services to implement devops processes and increase quality and save time.
I&amp;rsquo;ll also be giving Sebastien Levert&amp;rsquo;s session “deep dive in Microsoft graph” as he can&amp;rsquo;t make it to the event.
If you’re in the area today (I know it&amp;rsquo;s short notice) don’t hesitate to register to the event.</description></item><item><title>Determine whether or not a SharePoint library is running with the new experience</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/determine-whether-or-not-a-sha/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/determine-whether-or-not-a-sha/</guid><description>Microsoft just released the new experience for SharePoint libraries and I know a lot of you built custom look and feel and/or components on top of the library ui. (I’m thinking in particular about ScriptLink actions)
You might be in a situation where the code you need to run will be different depending on the experience being used.
After a little bit of research, here is an example of solution.</description></item><item><title>Building SharePoint 2016 WSP/FTC projects</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/building-sharepoint-2016-wspft/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/building-sharepoint-2016-wspft/</guid><description>WIth the release of SharePoint 2016 and the new MinRole feature, a lot of you would like to test migration of their custom solutions (Full Trust Code)
In order to do so, you need a 2016 dev machine (vs 2015 up to date with the latest version of the office sdk) and to install on top of that the office sdk preview 2.
https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=51683&amp;amp;WT.mc_id=rss_alldownloads_all&amp;amp;utm_source=twitterfeed&amp;amp;utm_medium=twitter
Then you only need to update references and targeted versions.</description></item><item><title>Renewed as MVP for 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/renewed-as-mvp-for-2016/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/renewed-as-mvp-for-2016/</guid><description>Hi,
For those of you who do not follow me on social media and don’t know it yet, I honored to announce I’ve be renewed as a Microsoft MVP for year 2016.
Due to recent modifications in the program, I’m transitioning to Office Servers and Services
I’m really excited by this upcoming year of coding, sharing, conferences and meeting people!!
See you soon</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Calgary 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-04-04-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-04-04-14-00-00/</guid><description>This year I have the privilege to speak at SPS Calgary (first time!!). I’ll give a speech about “Make Graph data useful for your company”.
We’ll see how we can leverage the new Microsoft Graph API and Machine Learning tools to build “clever” applications for our business.
If you’re in the area Saturday April the 23rd 2016 don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Houston 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-04-01-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-04-01-14-00-00/</guid><description>This year I have the privilege to speak at SPS Houston (first time!!). I’ll give a speech about “Setting up your release pipeline for SharePoint and Office 365 developments”.
We’ll see how you can automate all the things to make your development team more productive and more efficient. For that we’ll see how to set up build and release definitions and how you can leverage both azure and on premises environments</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Montréal 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-03-30-15-36-54/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 15:36:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-03-30-15-36-54/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Montréal
I also had the occasion to help organize the event this year, it’s been an interesting experience so far and I’d like to thank Serge, Nico, Luc, Seb and Fabrice for their implication in that project, it’s much more work than what we think!
This time I’ll talk about setting up your release pipeline for SharePoint/Office 365 developments in Visual Studio Online (Team Foundation Services).</description></item><item><title>Controlled update of SQL databases Schema with Entity Framework Code First in a continous delivery process</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/controlled-update-of-sql-datab/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/controlled-update-of-sql-datab/</guid><description>Introduction Entity Framework is a well-known technology in the ORM domain for the .NET world.
Note: Object Relational Mapping, this is the part between data persistence unit and some more “high level” code.
When you start a new entity framework project you have a few different ways to do it, one of which being “code first”. It means our code will drive the SQL Schema evolution (which simplifies a lot of things and allows you to focus on business and not technical implementation).</description></item><item><title>Units tests using xUnit and Visual Studio Team Services for DNX projects</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/units-tests-using-xunit-and-vi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/units-tests-using-xunit-and-vi/</guid><description>Introduction DNX will soon be released and there’ll be a growing number of developers wanting to write unit tests to improve the quality of developments.
Ideally you’d like to run these unit tests in a continuous integration process in order to make sure you didn’t introduce any regression/bug or degraded performances.
In .NET world you have many tools to write unit tests:
MSTest/VSTest
NUnit
xUnit</description></item><item><title>Error publishing asp.net 5 (core) websites to Azure</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/error-publishing-aspnet-5-core/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/error-publishing-aspnet-5-core/</guid><description>If you’re doing asp.net core development and if you’re trying to publish your website to an azure website you might run into the following error when implementing this documentation.
https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/Library/vs/alm/Build/azure/deploy-aspnet5?f=255&amp;amp;MSPPError=-2147217396
[error]Error: The specified credentials cannot be used with the authentication scheme &amp;lsquo;Basic&amp;rsquo;.
[error]Error: Default credentials cannot be supplied for the Basic authentication scheme.
[error]Parameter name: authType
This comes from the fact the provided script doesn’t support azure websies with multiple deployment slots.</description></item><item><title>Building DNX projects using home installed build agent (TFS, VSTS)</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/building-dnx-projects-using-ho/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/building-dnx-projects-using-ho/</guid><description>With DNX/DNU soon to be RTM there’ll be more and more developers eagers to build and deploy ASP.NET core 1 (formerly ASP.NET MVC 5) projects.
If the procedure is well described when you are using hosted agents (the ones microsoft runs for you on Azure), it’s a little more complex when you want to do it on a local agent.
https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/Library/vs/alm/Build/azure/deploy-aspnet5?f=255&amp;amp;MSPPError=-2147217396
On your agent’s machine you installed and updated visual studio and all the tools right?</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Vancouver 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-02-10-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-02-10-14-00-00/</guid><description>This year I have the privilege to speak at SPS Vancouver (first time!!). I’ll give a speech about the importance of metadata in your company (therefore in SharePoint/Office 365)
If you’re in the area Saturday March the 12th 2016 don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions. This is a good occasion to expand your network, learn a lot of things and to spend a good day.</description></item><item><title>Git Migration – cleaning up TFS references</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/git-migration-cleaning-up-tfs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/git-migration-cleaning-up-tfs/</guid><description>I recently had to migrate multiple source repositories from TFS to GIT (Git on vsonline). To do so I used Git Tfs https://github.com/git-tfs/git-tfs which does the job and is well documented https://github.com/git-tfs/git-tfs/blob/master/doc/usecases/migrate_tfs_to_git.md
There’s one step where they instruct you to remove *.vspscc and *.vssscc files and to clean up *.sln and *.*proj files from TFS references.
This will prevent Visual Studio from trying to reconnect to TFS every time you open the project/solution.</description></item><item><title>Automatically increment SharePoint feature version number during build with build 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/automatically-increment-sharep/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/automatically-increment-sharep/</guid><description>A few months ago Microsoft released a new automated build system with visual studio online /tfs 2015.
This new mechanism is way more open than previous XAML builds, tasks based and easier to customize.
One of the available tasks allows you to run a powershell script.
Let’s say that for one reason you want to increment automatically the version number of your SharePoint features when building.
If you have a quick look at the “.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Ottawa 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-11-10-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-11-10-14-00-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Ottawa. I’ll give a speech about the ALM capabilities for SharePoint/Office365 in Azure “Setting up your release pipeline for SharePoint in Azure”.
If you’re in the area Saturday November the 21st 2015 don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions. This is a good occasion to expand your network, learn a lot of things and to spend a good day.</description></item><item><title>Disabling SharePoint’s SEO features</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/disabling-sharepoints-seo-feat/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/disabling-sharepoints-seo-feat/</guid><description>I recently had a customer who wanted to disable SharePoint’s native SEO capabilities (Search Engine Optimization) including:
Sitemap generation Canonical url generation Metadata generation on pages Explicit titles generation Etc The main reason was he had very specific needs and wanted to implement his own custom SEO features.
The thing is that feature is hidden and enabled by default for any publishing site.
The simplest way to disable it then is using powershell, here is the command in case anyone else needs it.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday New Hampshire 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-10-23-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-10-23-14-00-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS New Hampshire. I’ll give a speech about the multilingualism capabilities of SharePoint “Translating SharePoint from beginning to ending”.
We’ll talk about how you can successfully implement an multilingual intranet, team sites or public sites using SharePoint.
If you’re in the area Saturday October the 24th 2015 don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions.</description></item><item><title>Programmatically add permissions to “everyone” in SharePoint Online</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/programmatically-add-permissio/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/programmatically-add-permissio/</guid><description>At some point you may want to add permissions to the “everyone” “groupe” of SharePoint.
Indeed this will allow you to set permissions to all users already having access to this site (because they are already members of other groups or already have permissions). This “group” is different of “NT AUTHORITY\authenticated users » which represents successfully identified users (bigger group).
The only thing is that “group” is in fact a user, so it’s helpless to iterate on every group of the site collection hoping to find it.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Toronto 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-09-11-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-09-11-14-00-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Toronto. I’ll give a speech about the graph “Making Graph data useful to your company”.
We’ll talk about the Graph, delve, yammer, machine learning and a lot of other interesting concepts and the conversation will be aimed towards developers.
If you’re in the area Saturday September the 19th 2015 don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions.</description></item><item><title>unable to find version '3.1.2' of package 'appforsharepointonlinewebtoolkit'</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/unable-to-find-version-312-of/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/unable-to-find-version-312-of/</guid><description>With office development tools for visual studio 2015 (and probably with august 2015 update for vs 2013 too, but I haven’t tried it), you may run into the following error:
unable to find version &amp;lsquo;3.1.2&amp;rsquo; of package &amp;lsquo;appforsharepointonlinewebtoolkit&amp;rsquo;
And so while doing an “update-package” in nuget console or if you have a restore packages step in your build process. (mandatory if like me you don’t include the packages folder into source control).</description></item><item><title>New Microsoft Conference: the AzureCon</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/new-microsoft-conference-the-a/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/new-microsoft-conference-the-a/</guid><description>Hi everybody!
Short post to let you know that Microsoft recently announced a new event: the AzureCon. First edition on Sept the 29th.
This free online event will focus on Microsoft’s cloud technologies (mostly Azure) and will be about news and things to come on the platform.
Great speakers, awesome content, this is the occasion for you to learn a lot about Azure technologies and their usage.
This conference should happen multiple times a year (approximately 4), main reason being: ”with releases and updates every 3 weeks for each service, we simply couldn’t wait for an annual event to announce everything like we do with Ignite and Build” (Microsoft Azure Product Manager)</description></item><item><title>.Net Library for Alchemy API</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/net-library-for-alchemy-api/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/net-library-for-alchemy-api/</guid><description>It has been several months I’ve been “playing” with multiple semantic analysis services. I especially discovered www.alchemyapi.com in April. One interested thing about them being that IBM recently acquired them.
Semantic analysis What is semantic analysis? It’s analyzing text data (or sometimes pictures too) and trying to understand the meaning of the content in order to extract metadata from it. It’s a little lit if I were to give you a document and ask you to read it and say “what concepts is it about?</description></item><item><title>Speaker at Collab365</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaker-at-collab365/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaker-at-collab365/</guid><description>I’ve been greatly honored being selected to be speaker at collab 365.
This event directly comes from the sp24 with the spbiz which happened a few months from now. It’s a free online event which will take place on October the 8th during 24 hours all around the globe.
Adding to the fact I’ll be speaking at this event among other great speakers, I also have the great privilege to give 4 sessions (oh yeah!</description></item><item><title>Deploying cloud service via new 2015 build templates</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/deploying-cloud-service-via-ne/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/deploying-cloud-service-via-ne/</guid><description>Introduction to the new build system Microsoft recently made a new build definitions model with the release of Visual Studio 2015 (TFS 2015’s bits are not yet available but this new build service is already available on Visual Studio Online).
Just as a reminder the “old” build models were based on two artifacts:
The build process template: defined via XAML, it allows you to configure the sequence for the build process.</description></item><item><title>Provisioning custom services for SharePoint</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/provisioning-custom-services-f/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2015 03:24:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/provisioning-custom-services-f/</guid><description>This article is targeting SharePoint full trust developers who have (will) developed a custom service (SPService) for SharePoint.
Indeed, if you are building a product for SharePoint like we’re doing at Negotium (www.oceanik.com www.theattributesolution.com ) you probably built a custom service application within your solution.
If that’s the case your custom service application probably relies on a dedicated custom SharePoint service to run its code (it can be a service within IIS or a windows service).</description></item><item><title>Shared dependencies resolution and SharePoint full trust development</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/shared-dependencies-resolution/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 20:03:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/shared-dependencies-resolution/</guid><description>Hi everybody,
At Negotium we’re building multiple SharePoint products (www.oceanik.com www.theattributesolution.com …)
We’ve recently had a complex issue. Let’s say these two products have a common dependency (newtonsoft.json in our case). Now let’s say both products are installed on a single farm and that for some reason you have to uninstall one of them.
When SharePoint will retract the wsp, it will retract all dll’s that were included within it. Including the common dependency the other product still needs.</description></item><item><title>SharePoint apps (add-ins) JavaScript disappeared</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/sharepoint-apps-add-ins-javasc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 04:09:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/sharepoint-apps-add-ins-javasc/</guid><description>At Negotium we recently came across a weird problem.
Let’s assume you previously built a Provider hosted app for SharePoint.
Now let’s assume you updated to the latest version of the SDK (April/May update)
Finally let’s assume your tenant has been updated recently (v16.0.4121.1212 or above)
It’s likely that you are loading SP.*.js files and MicrosoftAjax.js the way it used to be recommended by Microsoft per say: &amp;lt;HostWebUrl&amp;gt;/_layouts/15/jsfile.js or &amp;lt;AppWebUrl&amp;gt;/_layouts/15/jsfile.js.</description></item><item><title>Azure – Bug with azure web sites settings</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/azure-bug-with-azure-web-site/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 02:10:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/azure-bug-with-azure-web-site/</guid><description>Hi everybody,
For those who didn’t know it already, you can set the “appSettings” settings of your web application from the azure portal.
This technique has several advantages over the traditional xsl transformation:
Only the admin knows the settings, they are not on the source control Rich UI experience Settings can be “slot relative” (checkbox on the right), this allows you to have something like “this setting has this value in staging and that value in production which have to remain with each slot, even if I swap the deployments” I recnetly found a bug with that tool.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday New York City 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-05-25-01-11-00/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 01:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-05-25-01-11-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS NYC
https://www.spsevents.org/city/nyc/nyc2015
My session will be about the importance of metadata in your company.
We’ll start by some reminders around the theory and describe what are the advantages and disadvantages of different types of each. Then we’ll see what’s currently supported by SharePoint and what are the available tools. Finally we’ll talk about why it is so important that you set this up in your companies, how it can improve findability of content and how it will help you to move to the Graph.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Montréal 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-05-21-00-50-33/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:50:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-05-21-00-50-33/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Montréal
/montreal-sharepoint-saturday-2
I also had the occasion to help organize the event this year, it’s been an interesting experience so far and I’d like to thank Serge, Nico, Luc, Philippe, Seb, Fabrice and Alain for their implication in that project, it’s much more work than what we think!
My session will be about the importance of metadata in your company.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SPBizConf</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-spbizconf/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 22:58:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-spbizconf/</guid><description>The SPBizConf (https://www.spbizconf.com/ ) will happen on June 17th and 18th of 2015.
This conference is mostly oriented towards business users (with a bit of technical content) and is free and online.
Don’t wait to sign up!
I’ll have the opportunity to give a session about the Graph. We’ll have a theoretical part to ensure everybody has got basis, a part talking about Microsoft’s Graph and Microsoft’s vision around the Graph to wrap up with a part with real business cases and explain how you could use it in your company.</description></item><item><title>MVP Virtual Conference</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/mvp-virtual-conference/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 22:34:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/mvp-virtual-conference/</guid><description>American (US, Canada, Latin…) Microsoft MVP’s are organizing a two days free online conference on May the 14th and the 15th.
If you want to know which sessions will be available you can click here
https://mvp.microsoft.com/en-us/virtualconference-agenda.aspx
To register to the event https://mvp.microsoft.com/en-us/virtualconference-sessions.aspx
I’ll be the moderator for Sébastien Levert’s session “introduction to AngularJS applications in Office 365”
It’s a great opportunity to connect with experts from all around the world.</description></item><item><title>Maintaining your tech skills and free cinema</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/maintaining-your-tech-skills-a/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/maintaining-your-tech-skills-a/</guid><description>One of the best part of my job which is also the most difficult one is always having to learn new stuff.
It’s great to have the opportunity to learn new things every day, it keeps my job interesting and challenging through the years. It also adds a lot of pressure to deal with: we know that a developer who doesn’t try to stay up to date for a few years quickly becomes “obsolete”.</description></item><item><title>Maximum provided results to generate refiners</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/maximum-provided-results-to-ge/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2015 15:41:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/maximum-provided-results-to-ge/</guid><description>Since SharePoint 2010 you have the ability to improve the search experience in adding custom search refiners. Even better you can develop new ones if you want. As a reminder search refiners (or facets) are located on the left of the search result page and allow you to filter search results to have a faster access to relevant items. (file type, author, modification date…)
Here is some documentation if you’d like to know more about it.</description></item><item><title>Montreal SharePoint Saturday 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/montreal-sharepoint-saturday-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 23:17:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/montreal-sharepoint-saturday-2/</guid><description>Montreal will have a SharePoint Saturday this year too!
Just as a reminder SharePoint Saturdays are:
Free events Happening all around the world Dedicated to SharePoint/Office 365 On Saturdays With great sessions and awesome speakers Practical information This year’s edition will be on May the 23rd at “college maisonneuse”. You just have to register here https://www.spsevents.org/city/montreal/montreal2015
Last year the SPS MTL brought together 200 persons. This year will try to have even more people with 4 tracks (20 sessions total).</description></item><item><title>Automated build for SharePoint 2013 full trust solutions – Where are my solutions?</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/automated-build-for-sharepoint-2014-12-04-01-12-13/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2014 01:12:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/automated-build-for-sharepoint-2014-12-04-01-12-13/</guid><description>Another episode of my series about automated build of SharePoint full trust solutions with tfs 2013 and visual studio 2013.
/automated-build-for-sharepoint-2014-10-29-02-22-54
If you followed my posts you must have noticed you dll’s were built but you didn’t have any wsp.
This is because by default msbuild doesn’t package your solutions. That’s pity isn’t it?
Here is some documentation telling us to add IsPackaging=true to the build definition as a parameter.</description></item><item><title>Visual studio 2013 Update 4 and SharePoint full trust solutions automated build</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/visual-studio-2013-update-4-an/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/visual-studio-2013-update-4-an/</guid><description>Quick update on my serie about automated build for sharepoint full trust solutions.
If you take a look at the second error I’m describing hereyou will notice that you have to replace two lines in order to make it work.
With update 4 it looks like Microsoft is preparing full 64 bits support for visual studio. New fix lines are now
&amp;lt;Import Condition=&amp;#34;&amp;#39;$(Language)&amp;#39; == &amp;#39;C#&amp;#39;&amp;#34; Project=&amp;#34;$(MSBuildExtensionsPath32)\Microsoft\Windows Workflow Foundation\v3.5\Workflow.Targets&amp;#34; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Import Condition=&amp;#34;&amp;#39;$(Language)&amp;#39; == &amp;#39;VB&amp;#39;&amp;#34; Project=&amp;#34;$(MSBuildExtensionsPath32)\Microsoft\Windows Workflow Foundation\v3.</description></item><item><title>Office developers tools november 2014 update</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/office-developers-tools-novemb/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 01:56:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/office-developers-tools-novemb/</guid><description>If you work in SharePoint development you probably already have noticed that the tools are getting a new update.
With previous versions Microsoft.SharePoint.Client.Search and Microsoft.SharePoint.Client.Search.Applications dll’s were not included (it most likely has been forgotten)
You then had two solutions:
Ensure that all developers had SharePoint binaries installed on their machines Embed a copy of the dll taken from a SharePoint machine Both solutions were not very practical.</description></item><item><title>Presenting at the MVP Showcase 2014</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/presenting-at-the-mvp-showcase/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2014 03:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/presenting-at-the-mvp-showcase/</guid><description>As some of you know, this is my first year as an MVP. Next week will be the MVP summit and I’m very exited about it.
For those whom don’t know it, Microsoft is actually bringing 1800+ persons from all around the world to their headquarters so they can share information with them and gather feedback.
We have a huge week coming up, well I can’t really say anything more about it, pretty much everything is under NDA.</description></item><item><title>Automated build for SharePoint server (fulltrust) solutions with visual studio online</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/automated-build-for-sharepoint-2014-10-29-02-22-54/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2014 02:22:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/automated-build-for-sharepoint-2014-10-29-02-22-54/</guid><description>Introduction It has been a few articles I’ve been mentioning the fact that we (Negotium, the company I work for) have migrated to visual studio online (TFS Online). This service offers most of the features offered by the on premises version of Team Foundation Server 2013 and even some exclusive features.
If you have only a vague idea of what can do TFS2013/VSO and you want to learn more I very highly recommend Professional Application Lifecycle Management from Wrox.</description></item><item><title>Q&amp;A with the SharePoint MVP Experts Chat On Oct 29th @1pm EST or 10am PDT</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/qampa-with-the-sharepoint-mvp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 22:50:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/qampa-with-the-sharepoint-mvp/</guid><description>Hello everyone
Microsoft is launching a SharePoint MVP Expert Chats again! Have questions about SharePoint 2010 or 2013? Or SharePoint Online? Office 365? Please join us October 29th at 1pm EST or 10am PDT where you can have your questions answered live! We will be using the Reddit Ask Me Anything format. This is new to us but many of Microsoft teams are using this medium now. Please create a Reddit account beforehand so you can be ready to ask questions.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at the SharePoint Saturday Ottawa 2014 !</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-sharepoint-sat-2014-10-08-23-40-00/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 23:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-sharepoint-sat-2014-10-08-23-40-00/</guid><description>I’m proud to announce I’ll be speaking at the SharePoint Saturday Ottawa 2014. The event will be held close to Ottawa on November the 18th and you can get all the details here https://www.spsevents.org/city/ottawa/ottawa2014
I will be presenting this session with Fabrice Vaxelaire (AKA Great Venerable) and we’ll be talking about building your business portal in Office 365: Nowadays we have business tools and portals everywhere in the company, what are the benefits of having everything at one place?</description></item><item><title>Converting a protected by password certificate (pfx) to an unprotected one (snk)</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/converting-a-protected-by-pass/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2014 01:06:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/converting-a-protected-by-pass/</guid><description>At work I am trying to implement automated build for SharePoint (full trust) projects on visual studio online. (Expect to have several articles about this as and when I meet and solve errors)
When doing SharePoint development we have to sign assemblies with a certificate. When the project is initialized there are two options:
Certificate is protected by a password: (pfx extension) that was with first versions of SharePoint tooling, or if you have created the structure of (visual studio) solution yourself with several assemblies.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at the SharePoint Saturday New Hampshire 2014 !</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-sharepoint-sat-2014-10-01-23-34-03/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 23:34:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-sharepoint-sat-2014-10-01-23-34-03/</guid><description>I’m proud to announce I’ll be speaking at the SharePoint Saturday New Hampshire 2014. The event will be held in Nashua on October the 18th and you can get all the details here https://bit.ly/spsnh2014
I will be presenting this session with Fabrice Vaxelaire (AKA Great Venerable) and we’ll be talking about building your business portal in Office 365: Nowadays we have business tools and portals everywhere in the company, what are the benefits of having everything at one place?</description></item><item><title>Localizing JavaScript of a Full Trust solution</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/localizing-javascript-of-a-ful/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2014 03:58:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/localizing-javascript-of-a-ful/</guid><description>Introduction We, SharePoint developers of ancient times when &amp;ldquo;full trust&amp;rdquo; solutions ruled, have understood one thing: using JavaScript improves by far our solutions.
Indeed this allows to reduce the load of the servers and makes the user experience more &amp;ldquo;responsive&amp;rdquo;.
But what if you want to display messages in different languages depending on the user? In .NET (understand server-side) it is quite simple, just use of resources. (see one of my posts on the subject)</description></item><item><title>Why should you not include telerik controls in your SharePoint products?</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/why-should-you-not-include-tel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 03:32:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/why-should-you-not-include-tel/</guid><description>First and foremost this article is a feedback from the field of a very particular case of SharePoint development. Telerik products and components are very good and accelerate your developments (SharePoint or not) providing you advanced and customizable controls.
Some of you already know it, I work in a team that develops products for SharePoint (www.oceanik.com and the others one do not have yet dedicated sites, we still have work on the marketing).</description></item><item><title>Have all the tools of a first class startup's in 10 min</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/have-all-the-tools-of-a-first/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2014 04:00:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/have-all-the-tools-of-a-first/</guid><description>Through my career I had the chance to be involved in several startups or small businesses trying to create a product or digital service. However a question arises very quickly:
How to have effective working tools while minimizing the financial impact?
And by impact financial I also mean the time spent to implement, because it is time that it not spent on its core business, or more generally to create added value.</description></item><item><title>Migrating Team Foundation Server 2010 to Visual Studio Online: difference of process model</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/migrating-team-foundation-serv/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 03:54:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/migrating-team-foundation-serv/</guid><description>Context In my company (www.negotium.com ) we are trying to achieve a significant migration for us people of development: TFS 2010 to visual studio online (ex tfs online).
This will bring many new opportunities and tools to our way of developing and it will allow our IT Department to decommission a (several in fact) machine. I&amp;rsquo;m preparing a more complete article on the benefits of the solution online from the online edition.</description></item><item><title>Availability of office 365 Samples and SDK on Github</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/availability-of-office-365-sam/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 16:53:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/availability-of-office-365-sam/</guid><description>For those who have not seen it yet Microsoft teams who work on Office 365 have created a hub on GitHub.
https://github.com/officedev
What are you going to find there?
Examples of code made by Microsoft and the community Demonstrations presented during the sessions from Microsoft and the community Part of the &amp;lsquo;documents&amp;rsquo; sources for the MSDN documentation SDK for &amp;lsquo;third&amp;rsquo; platforms (IOS, android&amp;hellip;) … The message behind that is Microsoft is investing in the community and wants to create a single place where developers (from any platform) can meet to participate in the projects together and share content.</description></item><item><title>The roadmap for Office 365 is available</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/the-roadmap-for-office-365-is/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2014 04:29:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/the-roadmap-for-office-365-is/</guid><description>For those who are interested in knowing what&amp;rsquo;s upcoming on office 365, Microsoft recently shared publicly the roadma.
You can see what Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s teams are developing directly from this page, which will be updated on regular basis https://office.microsoft.com/en-us/products/office-365-roadmap-FX104343353.aspx</description></item><item><title>Selected for SharePoint Saturday New York City</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/selected-for-sharepoint-saturd/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2014 03:43:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/selected-for-sharepoint-saturd/</guid><description>Hi Everybody!
I’m pleased to announce you that I’ll be speaking at SharePoint Saturday New York City.
The event is free and will occur at Microsoft New York City’s office, on time square.
Check it out, is a very good opportunity to learn plenty of things if you can be there.
https://www.spsevents.org/city/NYC/NYC2014/sessions
See you soon!</description></item><item><title>Auto-hosted applications are deprecated</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/auto-hosted-applications-are-d/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2014 19:31:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/auto-hosted-applications-are-d/</guid><description>Reminders Auto-hosted apps are only available for SharePoint online (office 365), it bundles and provisions at each installation an azure web site(and eventually a sql azure database).
That made hosting, tenancy management (isolating customers’ data) and authenticationway easier because most of the configuration part was automated.
Announce We’ve been wondering how these apps were going to evolve for a while. Indeed SharePoint 2013 came out more than a year ago in production on office 365 and we still were not able to:</description></item><item><title>The former MSP becomes MVP</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/the-former-msp-becomes-mvp/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2014 01:37:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/the-former-msp-becomes-mvp/</guid><description>SharePoint MVP
You may already have heard about it on social network, I’m a SharePoint Server MVP since April the 1st.
I’m really proud to be a part of this awesome community counting Microsoft technologies best professionals and great communities’ contributors.
This incoming year will be full of events, community activities and projects.
I would like to thank:
Jean-Sébastien DUCHENE: Enterprise Client Management French MVP for his advises and for encouraging me to become an MVP (I thought I was not good enough to make it).</description></item><item><title>Write a review on infopath’s replacer!</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/write-a-review-on-infopaths-re/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 03:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/write-a-review-on-infopaths-re/</guid><description>Microsoft announced at the SharePoint Conference 2014 infopath&amp;rsquo;s discontinuity. They have not yet announced a successor to this technology since it is still under development on their side. (or maybe not even started to develop).
In order to better match SharePoint users’ expectations, Microsoft is conducting a major survey to find out what you want to see in SharePoint around forms.
If you have ideas / opinions, feel free to submit these.</description></item><item><title>Outstanding announcements of the SharePoint Conference 2014 for Office 365</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/outstanding-announcements-of-t/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2014 02:38:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/outstanding-announcements-of-t/</guid><description>Microsoft has given much information during the SharePoint Conference 2014. It is sometimes difficult to not miss something, so I made a summary of information that marked me.
Storage evolution 1 TB and beyond! During the SharePoint Conference 2014 Microsoft announced a significant change in the limitations of SharePoint Online Storage: 1 TB Max per site collection (including the &amp;ldquo;mysite&amp;rdquo; or onedrive for business) and unlimited storage (understanding billed per GB) by tenant.</description></item><item><title>Anonymous access for SharePoint autohosted apps</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/anonymous-access-for-sharepoin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 17:03:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/anonymous-access-for-sharepoin/</guid><description>These days I’ve been working on an auto hosted app for SharePoint (office 365 actually).
I had to grant an anonymous access to one of the pages without requiring clients to give anonymous access to their SharePoint site. But I still needed to read a few properties from the App Web web site (the SPWeb provisioned by SharePoint when installing an app)
I had to play around a lot but I finally found the solution:</description></item><item><title>Operating system compatibility of SharePoint 2010/2013 has evolved</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/operating-system-compatibility/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 02:40:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/operating-system-compatibility/</guid><description>Service pack 2 for SharePoint 2010 and Service pack 1 for SharePoint 2013 recently came out.
A support of 2012R2 at last ! Both service packs bring support for Windows Server 2012R2. This is a recurrent problematic for IT services. How to reduce the number of different versions of an operating system in order to make maintenance cheaper and easier?
Warning: “in place” upgrade of operating system for SharePoint 2013 is not supported by Microsoft.</description></item><item><title>Repackaging of SharePoint 2010 language packs</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/repackaging-of-sharepoint-2010/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2014 19:57:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/repackaging-of-sharepoint-2010/</guid><description>SharePoint 2010 service pack 2 came out a few months ago from now. It brings lot of new things, I’ll blog about that in further posts.
One of these new things is the repackaging of language packs.
Indeed you may have missed it but it is not required anymore to do a progressive installation in order to support MUI in SharePoint 2010 when setting up a new farm.
Before, when one wanted to install language packs (let’s take for example French English and Spanish), one had to:</description></item><item><title>March Update of Visual Studio tools for Office</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/march-update-of-visual-studio/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 03:20:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/march-update-of-visual-studio/</guid><description>Microsoft recently publishing an update for Office development tools.
This update integrates SP1’s benefits. It also allows you to develop app for PowerPoint and Access, enhances/add creation/configuration wizards for projects elements and includes more data sources types.
You can find the detailed description of the update here https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/office/dn610877.aspx
It’s very simple to update your installation, open Visual Studio, tools, Extensions and updates.
Have fun coding!</description></item><item><title>Managing Resources, how to make your SharePoint solutions “globally deployed”</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/managing-resources-how-to-make/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 03:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/managing-resources-how-to-make/</guid><description>Introduction I wanted to publish this article months ago, back to the time I found this solution. But I did not mostly because of a lack of free time. Sebastien LEVERT, a top SharePoint developer and a member of Montreal’s SharePoint community, recently published a post about the same subject. Read it (sorry it’s in French), I’ll write my post so it is complementary. https://www.pimpmysharepoint.com/2014/01/09/deployer-des-fichiers-de-ressources-simplement/
Reminders To quickly summarize, when you develop SharePoint solutions and you want to support multiple languages (localize it) you need to use .</description></item><item><title>Help me to speak at SP24 the first SharePoint (web) conference all around the world!</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/help-me-to-speak-at-sp24-the-f/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2014 22:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/help-me-to-speak-at-sp24-the-f/</guid><description>Some great SharePoint MVP’s are organizing an amazing event on April the 16th/17th : the SP24.
The idea is:
Amazing speakers
Amazing conferences
All around the world
2 tracks
48 sessions
A few thousands attendees
24 hours straight
You even get to choose the sessions!
And it’s free
Translating SharePoint 2013 from beginning to ending Really motivated by this great concept I decided to apply for a conference.</description></item><item><title>Boost your SharePoint solutions with distributed cache!–Part 2–Explanations tips and warnings</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/boost-your-sharepoint-solution-2013-12-15-12-06-00/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 12:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/boost-your-sharepoint-solution-2013-12-15-12-06-00/</guid><description>Explanations, tips, tricks and warnings Explanations This cache cluster is in facts made of appfabric hosts (caching services). One of the advantages is that hosts not members of the cluster but clients of it keep a local copy of objects. And this copy is automatically maintained up to date. The result is you do not need to implement a lazy loading pattern to avoid back and forth on the network.</description></item><item><title>Boost your SharePoint solutions with distributed cache!- Part 1–Introduction</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/boost-your-sharepoint-solution-2013-12-13-02-35-30/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2013 02:35:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/boost-your-sharepoint-solution-2013-12-13-02-35-30/</guid><description>Prelude I started to write this set of articles as one at the beginning, but I quickly realized that I had a lot of things to explain. Moreover, I’m a real chatterbox which does not help in that case. I finally decided to write a trilogy. I will publish one article every two days beginning today. The code sample will be delivered with last article so I ensure that you read everything ;-).</description></item><item><title>SharePoint Auto hosted app and ASP.NET MVC</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/sharepoint-auto-hosted-app-and/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 04:16:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/sharepoint-auto-hosted-app-and/</guid><description>Code apps they said, it will be easier they said…
Visual Studio 2013 comes with a new project model : SharePoint autohosted app ASP.NET MVC (Cool!)
I’m fond of SharePoint, I like MVC, why not mixing them?
Short reminder, SharePoint autohosted apps are only available for Office 365. Technically Office 365 will create an Azure website on demand when app is deployed. The potential cost overhead will be billed directly to the tenant owner.</description></item><item><title>Entity Framework and dataContext reference for a web application</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/entity-framework-and-dataconte/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2013 03:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/entity-framework-and-dataconte/</guid><description>When using the entity framework with a data context we often have this problematic:
What’s the best between performance and simplicity of usage or scalability?
(no? you do not ask yourself that kind of existential question?)
Here is a little explanation :
Static instance
In this first case you wrote a static reference to the context. Sometimes you also add some lazy loading and/or disposal management in global.asax (application end event)</description></item><item><title>Speaker at SharePoint Saturday Ottawa!</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaker-at-sharepoint-saturday/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2013 03:20:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaker-at-sharepoint-saturday/</guid><description>Hi everybody, I’m thrilled to announce that I’ll be speaking at SharePoint Saturday Ottawa. On Nov the 23rd!
My session: translating SharePoint 2013 from beginning to ending. We’ll cover all multilingualism provided by SharePoint.
With lot of examples and demonstrations we’ll see what are the tools provided to IT pro’s, power users and developers. The goal of this session is to give you some insight about how to get your SharePoint environment in multiple languages seamlessly.</description></item><item><title>(English) The name 'InitializeControl' does not exist in the current context Controles utilisateur, SharePoint 2013 and Ressources</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/the-name-initializecon/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2013 21:21:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/the-name-initializecon/</guid><description>This article is written for SharePoint developers who already developed multilingual webparts.
It is a good practice to localize an application when you develop for SharePoint, which will make the adding of a new language easier.
When we developed for SharePoint 2010 we used to put resources files in hive/config/resources (and then run a stsadm –o copyappbincontent or automate it via a timerjob when activating features)
Or we used to create an empty SharePoint solution element in which we added our files and indicated that the deployment target was the appglobalresources folder (see https://stackoverflow.</description></item></channel></rss>