<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>websites on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/websites/</link><description>Recent content in websites on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</managingEditor><webMaster>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/websites/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Error publishing asp.net 5 (core) websites to Azure</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/error-publishing-aspnet-5-core/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/error-publishing-aspnet-5-core/</guid><description>If you’re doing asp.net core development and if you’re trying to publish your website to an azure website you might run into the following error when implementing this documentation.
https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/Library/vs/alm/Build/azure/deploy-aspnet5?f=255&amp;amp;MSPPError=-2147217396
[error]Error: The specified credentials cannot be used with the authentication scheme &amp;lsquo;Basic&amp;rsquo;.
[error]Error: Default credentials cannot be supplied for the Basic authentication scheme.
[error]Parameter name: authType
This comes from the fact the provided script doesn’t support azure websies with multiple deployment slots.</description></item><item><title>Azure – Bug with azure web sites settings</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/azure-bug-with-azure-web-site/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 02:10:13 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/azure-bug-with-azure-web-site/</guid><description>Hi everybody,
For those who didn’t know it already, you can set the “appSettings” settings of your web application from the azure portal.
This technique has several advantages over the traditional xsl transformation:
Only the admin knows the settings, they are not on the source control Rich UI experience Settings can be “slot relative” (checkbox on the right), this allows you to have something like “this setting has this value in staging and that value in production which have to remain with each slot, even if I swap the deployments” I recnetly found a bug with that tool.</description></item></channel></rss>