<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>github on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/github/</link><description>Recent content in github on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>.Net Library for Alchemy API</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/net-library-for-alchemy-api/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/net-library-for-alchemy-api/</guid><description>It has been several months I’ve been “playing” with multiple semantic analysis services. I especially discovered www.alchemyapi.com in April. One interested thing about them being that IBM recently acquired them.
Semantic analysis What is semantic analysis? It’s analyzing text data (or sometimes pictures too) and trying to understand the meaning of the content in order to extract metadata from it. It’s a little lit if I were to give you a document and ask you to read it and say “what concepts is it about?</description></item><item><title>Availability of office 365 Samples and SDK on Github</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/availability-of-office-365-sam/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 16:53:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/availability-of-office-365-sam/</guid><description>For those who have not seen it yet Microsoft teams who work on Office 365 have created a hub on GitHub.
https://github.com/officedev
What are you going to find there?
Examples of code made by Microsoft and the community Demonstrations presented during the sessions from Microsoft and the community Part of the &amp;lsquo;documents&amp;rsquo; sources for the MSDN documentation SDK for &amp;lsquo;third&amp;rsquo; platforms (IOS, android&amp;hellip;) … The message behind that is Microsoft is investing in the community and wants to create a single place where developers (from any platform) can meet to participate in the projects together and share content.</description></item></channel></rss>