<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>saturday on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/saturday/</link><description>Recent content in saturday on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</managingEditor><webMaster>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/saturday/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Calgary 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-04-04-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-04-04-14-00-00/</guid><description>This year I have the privilege to speak at SPS Calgary (first time!!). I’ll give a speech about “Make Graph data useful for your company”.
We’ll see how we can leverage the new Microsoft Graph API and Machine Learning tools to build “clever” applications for our business.
If you’re in the area Saturday April the 23rd 2016 don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Montréal 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-03-30-15-36-54/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 15:36:54 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-03-30-15-36-54/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Montréal
I also had the occasion to help organize the event this year, it’s been an interesting experience so far and I’d like to thank Serge, Nico, Luc, Seb and Fabrice for their implication in that project, it’s much more work than what we think!
This time I’ll talk about setting up your release pipeline for SharePoint/Office 365 developments in Visual Studio Online (Team Foundation Services).</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Ottawa 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-11-10-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-11-10-14-00-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Ottawa. I’ll give a speech about the ALM capabilities for SharePoint/Office365 in Azure “Setting up your release pipeline for SharePoint in Azure”.
If you’re in the area Saturday November the 21st 2015 don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions. This is a good occasion to expand your network, learn a lot of things and to spend a good day.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday New Hampshire 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-10-23-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-10-23-14-00-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS New Hampshire. I’ll give a speech about the multilingualism capabilities of SharePoint “Translating SharePoint from beginning to ending”.
We’ll talk about how you can successfully implement an multilingual intranet, team sites or public sites using SharePoint.
If you’re in the area Saturday October the 24th 2015 don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday New York City 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-05-25-01-11-00/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 01:11:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-05-25-01-11-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS NYC
https://www.spsevents.org/city/nyc/nyc2015
My session will be about the importance of metadata in your company.
We’ll start by some reminders around the theory and describe what are the advantages and disadvantages of different types of each. Then we’ll see what’s currently supported by SharePoint and what are the available tools. Finally we’ll talk about why it is so important that you set this up in your companies, how it can improve findability of content and how it will help you to move to the Graph.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Montréal 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-05-21-00-50-33/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:50:33 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-05-21-00-50-33/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Montréal
/montreal-sharepoint-saturday-2
I also had the occasion to help organize the event this year, it’s been an interesting experience so far and I’d like to thank Serge, Nico, Luc, Philippe, Seb, Fabrice and Alain for their implication in that project, it’s much more work than what we think!
My session will be about the importance of metadata in your company.</description></item><item><title>Montreal SharePoint Saturday 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/montreal-sharepoint-saturday-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 23:17:50 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/montreal-sharepoint-saturday-2/</guid><description>Montreal will have a SharePoint Saturday this year too!
Just as a reminder SharePoint Saturdays are:
Free events Happening all around the world Dedicated to SharePoint/Office 365 On Saturdays With great sessions and awesome speakers Practical information This year’s edition will be on May the 23rd at “college maisonneuse”. You just have to register here https://www.spsevents.org/city/montreal/montreal2015
Last year the SPS MTL brought together 200 persons. This year will try to have even more people with 4 tracks (20 sessions total).</description></item><item><title>Selected for SharePoint Saturday New York City</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/selected-for-sharepoint-saturd/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2014 03:43:34 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/selected-for-sharepoint-saturd/</guid><description>Hi Everybody!
I’m pleased to announce you that I’ll be speaking at SharePoint Saturday New York City.
The event is free and will occur at Microsoft New York City’s office, on time square.
Check it out, is a very good opportunity to learn plenty of things if you can be there.
https://www.spsevents.org/city/NYC/NYC2014/sessions
See you soon!</description></item><item><title>Speaker at SharePoint Saturday Ottawa!</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaker-at-sharepoint-saturday/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2013 03:20:22 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaker-at-sharepoint-saturday/</guid><description>Hi everybody, I’m thrilled to announce that I’ll be speaking at SharePoint Saturday Ottawa. On Nov the 23rd!
My session: translating SharePoint 2013 from beginning to ending. We’ll cover all multilingualism provided by SharePoint.
With lot of examples and demonstrations we’ll see what are the tools provided to IT pro’s, power users and developers. The goal of this session is to give you some insight about how to get your SharePoint environment in multiple languages seamlessly.</description></item></channel></rss>