<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Multilingualism on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/multilingualism/</link><description>Recent content in Multilingualism on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</managingEditor><webMaster>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 16:56:03 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/multilingualism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday New Hampshire 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-10-23-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-10-23-14-00-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS New Hampshire. I’ll give a speech about the multilingualism capabilities of SharePoint “Translating SharePoint from beginning to ending”.
We’ll talk about how you can successfully implement an multilingual intranet, team sites or public sites using SharePoint.
If you’re in the area Saturday October the 24th 2015 don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions.</description></item><item><title>Localizing JavaScript of a Full Trust solution</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/localizing-javascript-of-a-ful/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2014 03:58:16 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/localizing-javascript-of-a-ful/</guid><description>Introduction We, SharePoint developers of ancient times when &amp;ldquo;full trust&amp;rdquo; solutions ruled, have understood one thing: using JavaScript improves by far our solutions.
Indeed this allows to reduce the load of the servers and makes the user experience more &amp;ldquo;responsive&amp;rdquo;.
But what if you want to display messages in different languages depending on the user? In .NET (understand server-side) it is quite simple, just use of resources. (see one of my posts on the subject)</description></item></channel></rss>