<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>montreal on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/montreal/</link><description>Recent content in montreal on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</managingEditor><webMaster>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/montreal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Less than three weeks before the #SPSMontreal 2018!</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/less-than-three-weeks-before-t/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/less-than-three-weeks-before-t/</guid><description>This year again I have the privilege to be part of the organizing committee for SharePoint Saturday Montréal 2018 taking place June the 2nd at Cégep du vieux Montréal.
It’s free, it’s the occasion to learn a lot, not only about SharePoint but also about Office 365 and Azure.
This year in a few numbers:
25 sessions (in English and French) 1 Keynote by the Great Serge Tremblay 16 Microsoft MVP (Most Valuable Professional) 1 MSP (Microsoft Student Partner) 5 MCT (Microsoft Certified Trainers) 9 partners 200 attendees (planned) Besides the content, it’s also the occasion to develop your network, eat some Schwartz (smoked meat) and “SharePint” (Share a pint) !</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Montréal 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-03-30-15-36-54/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 15:36:54 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-03-30-15-36-54/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Montréal
I also had the occasion to help organize the event this year, it’s been an interesting experience so far and I’d like to thank Serge, Nico, Luc, Seb and Fabrice for their implication in that project, it’s much more work than what we think!
This time I’ll talk about setting up your release pipeline for SharePoint/Office 365 developments in Visual Studio Online (Team Foundation Services).</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Montréal 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-05-21-00-50-33/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:50:33 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-05-21-00-50-33/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Montréal
/montreal-sharepoint-saturday-2
I also had the occasion to help organize the event this year, it’s been an interesting experience so far and I’d like to thank Serge, Nico, Luc, Philippe, Seb, Fabrice and Alain for their implication in that project, it’s much more work than what we think!
My session will be about the importance of metadata in your company.</description></item><item><title>Montreal SharePoint Saturday 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/montreal-sharepoint-saturday-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 23:17:50 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/montreal-sharepoint-saturday-2/</guid><description>Montreal will have a SharePoint Saturday this year too!
Just as a reminder SharePoint Saturdays are:
Free events Happening all around the world Dedicated to SharePoint/Office 365 On Saturdays With great sessions and awesome speakers Practical information This year’s edition will be on May the 23rd at “college maisonneuse”. You just have to register here https://www.spsevents.org/city/montreal/montreal2015
Last year the SPS MTL brought together 200 persons. This year will try to have even more people with 4 tracks (20 sessions total).</description></item></channel></rss>