<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Devops on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/devops/</link><description>Recent content in Devops on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 11:06:28 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Speaking at the European SharePoint Conference 2019 - SPFx &amp; DevOps</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-european-share-2019-10-01-18-14-00/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 18:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-european-share-2019-10-01-18-14-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>The ESPC is one of the biggest technology events in Europe and the biggest with focus on Office 365, SharePoint and Azure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An interesting particularity of this event, they move to a different European capital each year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This years edition will be from &lt;strong>December 2nd to 5th in Prague&lt;/strong> and I&amp;rsquo;m honored to be invited to speak again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting two sessions:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>How to do DevOps with the SharePoint Framework and why it matters?&lt;/strong> This session will be an introduction to DevOps practices and an application of the core principles in a SharePoint Framework context.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SharePoint Framework and DevOps Practices: New Documentation, New Samples</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/sharepoint-framework-and-devop/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/sharepoint-framework-and-devop/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="tl-dr">TL; DR;&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>With the release of Azure DevOps, there’s some &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/sharepoint/dev/spfx/toolchain/implement-ci-cd-with-azure-devops">new SPFX documentation&lt;/a> to set up your CI/CD pipeline in Azure DevOps.  Have a look and share your thoughts.  Your feedback is always welcome! The Patterns and Practices Initiative also includes a newly reorganized DevOps repository for tools and samples around &lt;a href="https://github.com/SharePoint/sp-dev-build-extensions">SharePoint Framework Build and Deploy Practices&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-long-story">The long story&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="my-journey-into-the-sharepoint-devops-world">My journey into the SharePoint DevOps world&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I have been working around Application Lifecycle Management (ALM), Continuous Integration (CI), Continuous Deployment (CD) and DevOps practices in the SharePoint/Azure/Office 365 ecosystem for several years.  In my experience, whether you’re working alone or as part of a team, adopting proper ALM practices is crucial if you want to produce high quality code.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Presenting at the Microsoft Ignite Tour Toronto</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/presenting-at-the-microsoft-ig/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/presenting-at-the-microsoft-ig/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Microsoft Ignite tour is a series of events that take place in cities around the world. This series of events is organized by Microsoft and presenters are picked among Microsoft Employees, Regional Directors and MVPs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll have the opportunity to present one session “&lt;strong>How to do DevOps with the SharePoint Framework and why it matters?&lt;/strong>”. During this session we will explore together how you can setup your continuous integration and continuous deployment pipeline leveraging Azure DevOps (formerly Visual Studio Team Services).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday New England 2018</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-08-27-05-00-00/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-08-27-05-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS New England.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll give a speech about “&lt;strong>Improving DevOps using Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Business Productivity Tools and more&lt;/strong>” and I&amp;rsquo;ll be co-presenting the session with my friend &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HCroitoru">Haniel Croitoru&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>We&amp;rsquo;ll explore together how DevOps practices impact and improve solutions delivery for your customers and for the best. With real life scenarios and experience for the field we&amp;rsquo;ll show you how you can get started and what to expect out of it.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Pittsburgh 2018</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-08-23-05-00-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-08-23-05-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>I Have the pleasure to announce I have been selected to speak at SPS Pittsburgh 2018.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll give a speech about the graph “&lt;strong>How to do Dev-Ops with the SharePoint Framework and why it matters&lt;/strong>”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Together we’ll see why it’s important to follow the DevOps processes, methodologies, and philosophy and how to implement it for the SharePoint Framework with Visual Studio Team Services (or TFS). Go from the original idea to production automating as much as possible!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Charlotte 2018</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-08-06-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-08-06-08-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>I Have the pleasure to announce I have been selected to speak at SPS Charlotte 2018.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll give a speech about the graph “&lt;strong>How to do Dev-Ops with the SharePoint Framework and why it matters&lt;/strong>”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Together we’ll see why it’s important to follow the DevOps processes, methodologies, and philosophy and how to implement it for the SharePoint Framework with Visual Studio Team Services (or TFS). Go from the original idea to production automating as much as possible!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Git: fork/import/manual copy, keep it clean</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/git-forkimportmanual-copy-keep/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/git-forkimportmanual-copy-keep/</guid><description>&lt;p>Part of my role at 2toLead is to help set guidance around best source management practices either internally or for our customers. One of the questions I get often is: Should I fork this repository or do something else with it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s hard to get clear and simple guidance on the web so I thought I’d take a stab at it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As we’re using Visual Studio Team Services, my examples and screenshots will be based on it, but it really applies to any git service like Github or internal git servers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Detroit 2017</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-11-16-17-26-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 17:26:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-11-16-17-26-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Detroit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll give a speech about “&lt;strong>Improving DevOps using Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Business Productivity Tools and more&lt;/strong>” and I&amp;rsquo;ll be &lt;strong>co-presenting the session with my friend &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HCroitoru" title="twitter profile">Haniel Croitoru&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>We&amp;rsquo;ll explore together how DevOps practices impact and improve solutions delivery for your customers and for the best. With real life scenarios and experience for the field we&amp;rsquo;ll show you how you can get started and what to expect out of it.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using PnP PowerShell on Visual Studio Team Services (VSTS) Hosted Agent</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/using-pnp-powershell-on-visual/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/using-pnp-powershell-on-visual/</guid><description>&lt;p>Visual Studio Team Services (VSTS) provides great Continuous Integration (CI) and Continuous Deployment (CD) functionalities you can leverage to implement DevOps pipelines and automation with your custom developments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If your custom solutions rely on PnP PowerShell during their build and/or deployment processes, you will need PnP PowerShell to be installed on the agent.
Unfortunately the &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/vsts/build-release/concepts/agents/hosted">Hosted Agents&lt;/a> do not have PnP PowerShell installed by default.
&lt;em>Note: that documentation only applies to the Hosted and Hosted 2017 agents, the Linux Hosted Agent is not supported at the moment&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Determine your technical debt using SonarQube - Conclusion</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-10-06-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-10-06-08-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>Installing and setting up SonarQube may seem quite complex and tedious.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I hope that this series has helped you to go faster implementing it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, you can clearly identify your technical debt and take actions to improve the quality of your developments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is obvious that when a thousand problems appear in the code at once, it can be discouraging, just keep this in mind:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>There are false positives, make a first pass to ignore/exclude those&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Determine your technical debt using SonarQube - Bonus SonarLint extension configuration</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-10-04-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-10-04-08-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="tl-dr">TL; DR&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can display SonarQube static analysis results live in Visual Studio error and information console using the same rules set as the SonarQube project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Installing the extension&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just go to &lt;a href="https://www.sonarlint.org/VisualStudio/index.html">https://www.sonarlint.org/VisualStudio/index.html&lt;/a> and proceed with the installation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="binding-the-visual-studio-solution-to-the-sonarqube-analysis">Binding the Visual Studio solution to the SonarQube analysis&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-10-04-08-00-00/19.png" alt="19.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the Team Explorer click SonarQube&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-10-04-08-00-00/20.png" alt="20.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click on connect.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(if you obtain a certificate error, you must install the self-signed certificate of the SonarQube server on your machine)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Determine your technical debt using SonarQube - Monitoring the results</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-10-02-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-10-02-08-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="tl-dr">TL; DR&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Static analysis errors will appear as of the warnings in the compilation section. A static analysis badge will also appear on the build report and you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to have detailed and comprehensive information from SonarQube.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="information-incorporated-with-the-build">Information incorporated with the build&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When displaying the details of a build, you&amp;rsquo;ll now find a new section dedicated to SonarQube. Within that section, besides the quality badge, you&amp;rsquo;ll also find a link to the static analysis results details. Also under the build section, all static analysis critical issues will show up as warnings.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Determine your technical debt using SonarQube - Creating the SonarQube project</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-29-08-00-00qwqw/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-29-08-00-00qwqw/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="tl-dr">TL; DR&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>SonarQube allows you to create projects. These projects will hold your code analysis results. You can configure a SQ project for each code repository or even for each branch to have different deltas. (ex my master builds every month, I want to see changes to the monthly and my dev builds daily so I want to see evolution on a day by day basis).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="creating-the-project">Creating the project&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Go to &amp;ldquo;configuration&amp;rdquo;-&amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;Projects&amp;rdquo;-&amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;Management&amp;rdquo; then &amp;ldquo;create project&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Determine your technical debt using SonarQube - Updating your build definitions</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-29-08-00-00labd/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-29-08-00-00labd/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="tl-dr">TL; DR&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Static analysis will be executed when building your source base using the central build machine. You have two options to set this up with VSTS:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Your project is &amp;ldquo;Visual Studio&amp;quot; related and leverages sln and cs/vb proj files: in that case you can leverage integrated pre and post build tasks provided by the SonarQube VSTS extension.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Your project is not build using msbuild: in that case you must leverage the SonarQube CLI task. It&amp;rsquo;s a little bit more complicated so I&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate only the first case for now.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="adding-tasks-to-the-build-definition">Adding tasks to the build definition&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ll go under the assumption that you&amp;rsquo;re already using build 2015/vNext and you have working with build definitions for at least one project.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Determine your technical debt using SonarQube - Creating and configuring a service account for VSTS in SonarQube</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-27-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-27-08-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="tl-dr">TL; DR&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To prevent anyone from sending analysis results to our SonarQube installation, we need to secure the access to its services. To do so, we&amp;rsquo;ll configure a service account.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="creating-the-service-account">Creating the service account&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>From SonarQube, go to administration, security, users, and add an account.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next click on the &amp;ldquo;tokens&amp;quot; cell for the account we just created an generate a new personal access token.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can also refer to that documentation if you&amp;rsquo;re not sure how to generate a PAT &lt;a href="https://docs.sonarqube.org/display/SONAR/User&amp;#43;Token">https://docs.SonarQube.org/display/SONAR/User+Token&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Determine your technical debt using SonarQube - Setting up Azure Active directory for authentication</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-25-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-25-08-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="tl-dr">TL; DR&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We will install and configure an add-on to delegate authentication to Azure Active Directory. This will allow our developers to use the same account between Visual Studio Team Services and SonarQube.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Configuration of the authentication module&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since version 5.4 SonarQube provides an additional plugin relying on the OAuth protocol to communicate with AAD. This will allow the users to leverage their corporate account to access SonarQube, providing SSO and simplifying the administrators job by having a central identity repository.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Determine your technical debt using SonarQube - Opening SonarQube’s ports</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-20-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-20-08-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="tl-dr">TL; DR&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Open ports 22, 9000, 80 and 443 inbound on the VM.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="details-of-the-opening-of-ports">Details of the opening of ports&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Rather than repeating what is already documented, I will provide you with the link&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/baywet/azure-docker-sonarqube#step-2-opening-firewall-ports">https://Github.com/baywet/azure-docker-SonarQube#step-2-opening-firewall-ports&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is necessary to open the ports 22, 80, 443 and 9000 allowing respectively to access the machine remote shell, load http and https content, and access the management console.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Determine your technical debt using SonarQube - Installing the machine</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-18-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-18-08-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="tl-dr">TL; DR&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We will update the machine, install docker, and provision the containers we need.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="installation-of-docker-and-updating-the-machine">Installation of docker and updating the machine&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Connect to the machine using SSH (Putty is a very good client for windows) and run the following commands:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/baywet/azure-docker-sonarqube#step-4-Setup-docker">https://Github.com/baywet/azure-docker-SonarQube#step-4-Setup-docker&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="setting-up-containers-creating-the-certificates">Setting up containers, creating the certificates&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The containers are the components of our system managing the web traffic and providing the SonarQube service.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To secure connections, we will also generate self-signed SSL certificates which is not the easiest thing to do when someone is not used to working with linux environments. It&amp;rsquo;s most likely to be the case for developers using Visual Studio Team Services (or TFS) because they come mostly from the Windows world.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Determine your technical debt using SonarQube - Creating the database</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-15-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-15-08-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="tl-dr">TL; DR&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Create a db sql azure with collation set to SQL_Latin1_General_CP1_CS_AS.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="details-of-the-database-creation">Details of the database creation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The SQL Azure database creation steps are already well described, crucial detail: use the following collation: SQL_Latin1_General_CP1_CS_AS. (and use a blank template)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/baywet/azure-docker-sonarqube#step-3-create-the-azure-SQL-database">https://Github.com/baywet/azure-docker-SonarQube#step-3-create-the-azure-SQL-database&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Keep the database access settings (FQDN of the server, username, password, the database name) somewhere, we will need those later.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to open the firewall of the SQL Server for connections from Azure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Determine your technical debt using SonarQube - Provisioning the SonarQube VM</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-13-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-13-08-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="tl-dr">TL; DR&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ll provision a ubuntu server in Azure, and install Putty and WinSCP on your local machine&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="details-of-provisioning">Details of provisioning&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Here is a link to a documentation explaining how to do it&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/baywet/azure-docker-sonarqube#step-1-create-the-virtual-machine-in-Azure">https://Github.com/baywet/azure-docker-SonarQube#step-1-create-the-virtual-machine-in-Azure&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is! the machine is being provisioned!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Meanwhile take the opportunity to download a SSH terminal if you don&amp;rsquo;t have one, I recommend &lt;a href="https://www.PuTTY.org/">https://www.PuTTY.org/&lt;/a>  (you can also install WinSCP that will also provide a GUI to transfer files)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Determine your technical debt using SonarQube - What parts to use?</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-11-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-11-08-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="tl-dr">TL; DR&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Planning, Sources, Build, deployment, testing: VSTS. Analysis: Azure VM (SonarQube), Azure SQL.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="parts-of-our-software-factory">Parts of our software factory&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Because we use a maximum of services cloud at 2toLead I realized the following installation:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Source control: VSTS (git or tfsvc, doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Build system: build 2015 VSTS&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Build machine: provided by VSTS as a service&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SonarQube machine: Ubuntu Server hosted in Azure&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Data SonarQube: Azure SQL Database, 10 DTU&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Note that to facilitate the management of the SonarQube &amp;ldquo;box&amp;quot; we are going to install Docker on the ubuntu machine. Once docker installed, we&amp;rsquo;ll hydrate two containers, nginx and SonarQube.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Determine your technical debt using SonarQube - Static analysis</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-08-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-08-08-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="tl-dr">TL; DR&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Static analysis allows you to understand weaknesses of your code based on a set of rules. You can have it run automatically on a server or from the IDE.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="introduction-to-static-analysis">Introduction to static analysis&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The principle of static analysis is to take advantage of rules set more or less complex, those will detect patterns in the code that are problematic, categorize their importance and suggest a resolution.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few examples:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Determine your technical debt using SonarQube - Introduction</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-06-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-06-08-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="tl-dr">TL; DR&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This series will explain *how to set up an automated code quality analysis* which is almost free of charge with Visual Studio Team Services, Docker, Azure, and SonarQube.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="preamble">Preamble&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There is bad quality code in every development project. This goes from the quick and dirty hack we are not proud of, to the long-forgotten code written by a developer who quit the company.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The problem with this code is that it will eventually accumulate and slow down the pace of new features delivery. The reasons are various, a lot of time spent in bug fixes, refactoring, support&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday New York City 2017</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-07-06-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-07-06-08-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS NYC.
I’ll give a speech about the SharePoint Framework and devops methodologies “Is it possible to do devops with the SharePoint framework?”.
You had it all right with solutions and add-ins. Your release pipeline was set up. Do new technologies and methodologies mean starting over?
Don’t panic I’m here to help! Together we’ll see how to set up a devops pipeline for SPFX developments with:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at Techorama Belgium 2017</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-techorama-belgium/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-techorama-belgium/</guid><description>&lt;p>Techorama is a 2-day event that takes place in Antwerp, Belgium from May 22nd to May 24th.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They lined up great speakers from Microsoft and other big industry players, checkout the agenda here &lt;a href="https://techorama.be/agenda/">https://techorama.be/agenda/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have the pleasure to announce I’ve been selected and I’ll be giving two sessions:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Set up your DevOps process for SharePoint/Office365&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Migrate your custom components to the SharePoint framework&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Tickets are still available so if you are in the area or can travel there I would strongly suggest you check-it out! &lt;a href="https://techorama.be/tickets/">https://techorama.be/tickets/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Vancouver 2017</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-03-09-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-03-09-14-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Vancouver.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll give a speech about the SharePoint Framework and devops methodologies “Is it possible to do devops with the SharePoint framework?”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You had it all right with solutions and add-ins. Your release pipeline was set up. Do new technologies and methodologies mean starting over?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Don’t panic I’m here to help! Together we’ll see how to set up a devops pipeline for SPFX developments with:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Update: continuous integration for dot net core</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/update-continuous-integration/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/update-continuous-integration/</guid><description>&lt;p>A few months ago I published articles about continuous integration for dot net core projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Obviously it was really early in this “new framework” lifecycle (we were still on a beta version back then) and the tooling plus processes evolved a lot since.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good news is you don’t need anymore a complex and often crashing powershell script. You don’t need anymore special tasks either other than standard command line and azure publishing tasks.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Brussels 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-09-22-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-09-22-14-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year I have the privilege to speak at SPS Brussels&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll give a speech about “setting up your release pipeline for office 365/SharePoint”. (aka devops)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We’ll see together how you can leverage azure and visual studio team services to implement devops processes and increase quality and save time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re in the area on Oct the 15th don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions. This is a good occasion to expand your network, learn a lot of things and to spend a good day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Oslo 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-09-15-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-09-15-14-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year I have the privilege to speak at SPS Oslo&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll give a speech about “setting up your release pipeline for office 365/SharePoint”. (aka devops)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We’ll see together how you can leverage azure and visual studio team services to implement devops processes and increase quality and save time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re in the area on Oct the 22nd don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions. This is a good occasion to expand your network, learn a lot of things and to spend a good day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Detroit 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-09-09-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-09-09-14-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year I have the privilege to speak at SPS Detroit&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll give a speech about “setting up your release pipeline for office 365/SharePoint”. (aka devops)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We’ll see together how you can leverage azure and visual studio team services to implement devops processes and increase quality and save time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re in the area On Sept the 10th don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions. This is a good occasion to expand your network, learn a lot of things and to spend a good day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New tasks to build/release dotnetcore project with vsts</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/new-tasks-to-buildrelease-dotn/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 14:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/new-tasks-to-buildrelease-dotn/</guid><description>&lt;p>A few months ago I wrote a series of articles on how to set up a release pipeline for dnx/dotnetcore projects with vsts targeting azure web apps.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This series would require you to use a few scripts to build and publish the website executing them using powershell tasks in the build definition.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You don’t need to do that anymore because two new extensions are available on the marketplace:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://baywet.github.io/new-tasks-to-buildrelease-dotn/59.png" alt="59.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve been able to replace most of my scripts using VSTS DNX Tasks&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday New York City 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-07-30-09-28-00/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2016 09:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-07-30-09-28-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year I have the privilege to speak at SPS New York City.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll give a speech about “setting up your release pipeline for office 365/SharePoint”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We’ll see together how you can leverage azure and visual studio team services to implement devops processes and increase quality and save time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll also be giving Sebastien Levert&amp;rsquo;s session “deep dive in Microsoft graph” as he can&amp;rsquo;t make it to the event.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re in the area today (I know it&amp;rsquo;s short notice) don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions. This is a good occasion to expand your network, learn a lot of things and to spend a good day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Git Migration – cleaning up TFS references</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/git-migration-cleaning-up-tfs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/git-migration-cleaning-up-tfs/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently had to migrate multiple source repositories from TFS to GIT (Git on vsonline). To do so I used Git Tfs &lt;a href="https://github.com/git-tfs/git-tfs">https://github.com/git-tfs/git-tfs&lt;/a> which does the job and is well documented &lt;a href="https://github.com/git-tfs/git-tfs/blob/master/doc/usecases/migrate_tfs_to_git.md">https://github.com/git-tfs/git-tfs/blob/master/doc/usecases/migrate_tfs_to_git.md&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There’s one step where they instruct you to remove *.vspscc and *.vssscc files and to clean up *.sln and *.*proj files from TFS references.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This will prevent Visual Studio from trying to reconnect to TFS every time you open the project/solution.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>