<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>App on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/app/</link><description>Recent content in App on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</managingEditor><webMaster>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 16:56:03 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Auto-hosted applications are deprecated</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/auto-hosted-applications-are-d/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2014 19:31:16 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/auto-hosted-applications-are-d/</guid><description>Reminders Auto-hosted apps are only available for SharePoint online (office 365), it bundles and provisions at each installation an azure web site(and eventually a sql azure database).
That made hosting, tenancy management (isolating customers’ data) and authenticationway easier because most of the configuration part was automated.
Announce We’ve been wondering how these apps were going to evolve for a while. Indeed SharePoint 2013 came out more than a year ago in production on office 365 and we still were not able to:</description></item><item><title>Anonymous access for SharePoint autohosted apps</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/anonymous-access-for-sharepoin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 17:03:38 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/anonymous-access-for-sharepoin/</guid><description>These days I’ve been working on an auto hosted app for SharePoint (office 365 actually).
I had to grant an anonymous access to one of the pages without requiring clients to give anonymous access to their SharePoint site. But I still needed to read a few properties from the App Web web site (the SPWeb provisioned by SharePoint when installing an app)
I had to play around a lot but I finally found the solution:</description></item><item><title>SharePoint Auto hosted app and ASP.NET MVC</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/sharepoint-auto-hosted-app-and/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 04:16:32 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/sharepoint-auto-hosted-app-and/</guid><description>Code apps they said, it will be easier they said…
Visual Studio 2013 comes with a new project model : SharePoint autohosted app ASP.NET MVC (Cool!)
I’m fond of SharePoint, I like MVC, why not mixing them?
Short reminder, SharePoint autohosted apps are only available for Office 365. Technically Office 365 will create an Azure website on demand when app is deployed. The potential cost overhead will be billed directly to the tenant owner.</description></item></channel></rss>