<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>News on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/news/</link><description>Recent content in News on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 11:06:28 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Joining Microsoft as a Program Manager on the Microsoft Graph</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/joining-microsoft-as-a-program/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 11:22:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/joining-microsoft-as-a-program/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="tl-dr">TL; DR&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I’ll be starting at Microsoft as a Program Manager on the Microsoft Graph in January. This is an exiting change and I’d like to take the time to thank 2toLead for the amazing last few years.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="new-role">New role&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I’m exited to announce I’ll be starting at Microsoft in January as a Program Manager on the Microsoft Graph (and other Microsoft Identity Platform topics). I’ll be part of the MIP organization and in the extended team of brilliant people like Yina Arenas, Jeremy Thake, Darrel Miller and many more.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Outstanding announcements of the SharePoint Conference 2014 for Office 365</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/outstanding-announcements-of-t/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2014 02:38:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/outstanding-announcements-of-t/</guid><description>&lt;p>Microsoft has given much information during the SharePoint Conference 2014. It is sometimes difficult to not miss something, so I made a summary of information that marked me.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="storage-evolution-1-tb-and-beyond">Storage evolution 1 TB and beyond!&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>During the SharePoint Conference 2014 Microsoft announced a significant change in the limitations of SharePoint Online Storage: 1 TB Max per site collection (including the &amp;ldquo;mysite&amp;rdquo; or onedrive for business) and unlimited storage (understanding billed per GB) by tenant.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>