<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>update on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/update/</link><description>Recent content in update on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</managingEditor><webMaster>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/update/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Controlled update of SQL databases Schema with Entity Framework Code First in a continous delivery process</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/controlled-update-of-sql-datab/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/controlled-update-of-sql-datab/</guid><description>Introduction Entity Framework is a well-known technology in the ORM domain for the .NET world.
Note: Object Relational Mapping, this is the part between data persistence unit and some more “high level” code.
When you start a new entity framework project you have a few different ways to do it, one of which being “code first”. It means our code will drive the SQL Schema evolution (which simplifies a lot of things and allows you to focus on business and not technical implementation).</description></item><item><title>Office developers tools november 2014 update</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/office-developers-tools-novemb/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 01:56:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/office-developers-tools-novemb/</guid><description>If you work in SharePoint development you probably already have noticed that the tools are getting a new update.
With previous versions Microsoft.SharePoint.Client.Search and Microsoft.SharePoint.Client.Search.Applications dll’s were not included (it most likely has been forgotten)
You then had two solutions:
Ensure that all developers had SharePoint binaries installed on their machines Embed a copy of the dll taken from a SharePoint machine Both solutions were not very practical.
These dlls are now included for version 15 and 16 located here C:\Program Files\Common Files\microsoft shared\Web Server Extensions\</description></item><item><title>Operating system compatibility of SharePoint 2010/2013 has evolved</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/operating-system-compatibility/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 02:40:21 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/operating-system-compatibility/</guid><description>Service pack 2 for SharePoint 2010 and Service pack 1 for SharePoint 2013 recently came out.
A support of 2012R2 at last ! Both service packs bring support for Windows Server 2012R2. This is a recurrent problematic for IT services. How to reduce the number of different versions of an operating system in order to make maintenance cheaper and easier?
Warning: “in place” upgrade of operating system for SharePoint 2013 is not supported by Microsoft.</description></item></channel></rss>