<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>event on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/event/</link><description>Recent content in event on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</managingEditor><webMaster>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 12:20:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/event/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Speaking at the API specification conference 2022</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-api-specification-conf-2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 12:20:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-api-specification-conf-2022/</guid><description>I’m extremely pleased to announce I’ll be speaking at the API specification conference 2022 in San Francisco, Sept 19-21st. During “Lessons learned from client generation, gaps and suggestions to address them”, we’ll be reviewing my 2 years experience building an OpenAPI based client generator and trying to identify solutions to ease up code generation, leading to better clients.
The API specification conference is the first in person event I’ll be presenting at in almost 3 years, I’m really excited and a bit nervous (do I even remember how to do this anymore?</description></item><item><title>Speaking at Microsoft 365 Saturday Ottawa 2020</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sps-ottawa-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sps-ottawa-2020/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the Microsoft 365 (formerly SPS) Ottawa and I&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting &amp;ldquo;Introduction To The Microsoft Graph: Getting Started Quickly &amp;amp; Getting The Most Out Of It&amp;rdquo;.
Together we will cover the basics of Microsoft Graph, the Microsoft Identity Platform, the value it provides to developers and how to get started.
Because of the ongoing pandemic, the event will be digital only and held on Microsoft Teams.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at the European SharePoint Conference 2019 - SPFx &amp; DevOps</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-european-share-2019-10-01-18-14-00/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 18:14:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-european-share-2019-10-01-18-14-00/</guid><description>The ESPC is one of the biggest technology events in Europe and the biggest with focus on Office 365, SharePoint and Azure.
An interesting particularity of this event, they move to a different European capital each year.
This years edition will be from December 2nd to 5th in Prague and I&amp;rsquo;m honored to be invited to speak again.
I&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting two sessions:
How to do DevOps with the SharePoint Framework and why it matters?</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Ottawa 2019</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2019-10-01-14-12-00/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 14:12:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2019-10-01-14-12-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Ottawa and I&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting &amp;ldquo;Introduction To The Microsoft Graph: Getting Started Quickly &amp;amp; Getting The Most Out Of It&amp;rdquo;.
Together we will cover the basics of the Microsoft Graph, the Microsoft Identity Platform, the value it provides to developers and how to get started.
If you’re in the area Saturday October the 5th 2019 don’t hesitate to register to the event.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Fest DC 2019</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-fest-dc-2019-04-18-07-35-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 07:35:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-fest-dc-2019-04-18-07-35-00/</guid><description>SharePoint Fest Washington DC 2018 is happening from April 29th to May the 3rd. This event will feature 2 days pre-conference workshops and 3 days of conference. You can find more information about it on the website. I&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting three sessions:
DEV104 - Migrate your custom components to the SharePoint Framework
Migrate your custom components to the SharePoint Framework.
It’s the 3rd model Microsoft has come with to customize SharePoint in less than 5 years.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Houston 2019</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2019-04-02-02-00-00/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2019-04-02-02-00-00/</guid><description>It is the second time in a few years I have the ooportunity to speak at the SharePoint Saturday Houston.
I’ll give a speech about &amp;ldquo;Automating Provisioning For Your Digital Workplace: With Azure Durable Functions &amp;amp; Microsoft Graph&amp;rdquo;
Together we will see how you can improve your provisioning workflows and automate most of it leveragingAzure Durable Functions and the Microsoft Graph. This session is geared mostly towards developers but also for IT pros and deciders that want to gain insights on how to combine business processes and provisioning.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Toronto 2018</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-11-20-09-00-00/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-11-20-09-00-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Toronto.
I’ll give a speech about “Migrate your custom components to the SharePoint Framework”.
Together we will see how you can transition from either the server-side object model or the add-ins development fashions to the modern SharePoint Framework approach. This session is mostly meant for developers and technical architects who are curious about getting started on the new model and that might have legacy applications.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Ottawa 2018</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-10-10-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-10-10-08-00-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Ottawa. It has become a regular event for me. This SPS is really dear to me because not only I get to see a lot of Canadian MVPs friends but it also was the first event ever I was presenting in (a broken) English a long time ago.
This year I&amp;rsquo;ll present &amp;ldquo;The Microsoft Graph and SharePoint Framework under steroids with Azure functions&amp;rdquo; or how these three technologies really represent a power trio to build customizations in Office 365.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday New England 2018</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-08-27-05-00-00/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-08-27-05-00-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS New England.
I’ll give a speech about “Improving DevOps using Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Business Productivity Tools and more” and I&amp;rsquo;ll be co-presenting the session with my friend Haniel Croitoru.
We&amp;rsquo;ll explore together how DevOps practices impact and improve solutions delivery for your customers and for the best. With real life scenarios and experience for the field we&amp;rsquo;ll show you how you can get started and what to expect out of it.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Fest Seattle 2018</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-fest-se/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-fest-se/</guid><description>SharePoint Fest Seattle 2018 is happening from August 20th to 24th. This event will feature 2 days pre-conference workshops and 3 days of conference. You can find more information about it on the website. I’ve been selected amongst 74 other speakers (including people from Microsoft product teams!!) to present this year two sessions:
AZR203 - Azure Functions In The Real World: Lessons Learned &amp;amp; Best Practices “Azure Functions is one of the most powerful new solutions provided by Microsoft.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Charlotte 2018</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-08-06-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-08-06-08-00-00/</guid><description>I Have the pleasure to announce I have been selected to speak at SPS Charlotte 2018.
I’ll give a speech about the graph “How to do Dev-Ops with the SharePoint Framework and why it matters”.
Together we’ll see why it’s important to follow the DevOps processes, methodologies, and philosophy and how to implement it for the SharePoint Framework with Visual Studio Team Services (or TFS). Go from the original idea to production automating as much as possible!</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday New York City 2018</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-06-27-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-06-27-08-00-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS NYC.
I’ll give a speech about “Migrate your custom components to the SharePoint Framework”.
Together we will see how you can transition from either the server-side object model or the add-ins development fashions to the modern SharePoint Framework approach. This session is mostly meant for developers and technical architects who are curious about getting started on the new model and that might have legacy applications.</description></item><item><title>Less than three weeks before the #SPSMontreal 2018!</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/less-than-three-weeks-before-t/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/less-than-three-weeks-before-t/</guid><description>This year again I have the privilege to be part of the organizing committee for SharePoint Saturday Montréal 2018 taking place June the 2nd at Cégep du vieux Montréal.
It’s free, it’s the occasion to learn a lot, not only about SharePoint but also about Office 365 and Azure.
This year in a few numbers:
25 sessions (in English and French) 1 Keynote by the Great Serge Tremblay 16 Microsoft MVP (Most Valuable Professional) 1 MSP (Microsoft Student Partner) 5 MCT (Microsoft Certified Trainers) 9 partners 200 attendees (planned) Besides the content, it’s also the occasion to develop your network, eat some Schwartz (smoked meat) and “SharePint” (Share a pint) !</description></item><item><title>Speaking at Techorama Belgium 2017</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-techorama-belgium/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-techorama-belgium/</guid><description>Techorama is a 2-day event that takes place in Antwerp, Belgium from May 22nd to May 24th.
They lined up great speakers from Microsoft and other big industry players, checkout the agenda here https://techorama.be/agenda/
I have the pleasure to announce I’ve been selected and I’ll be giving two sessions:
Set up your DevOps process for SharePoint/Office365
Migrate your custom components to the SharePoint framework
Tickets are still available so if you are in the area or can travel there I would strongly suggest you check-it out!</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Vancouver 2017</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-03-09-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-03-09-14-00-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Vancouver.
I’ll give a speech about the SharePoint Framework and devops methodologies “Is it possible to do devops with the SharePoint framework?”.
You had it all right with solutions and add-ins. Your release pipeline was set up. Do new technologies and methodologies mean starting over?
Don’t panic I’m here to help! Together we’ll see how to set up a devops pipeline for SPFX developments with:</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Calgary 2017</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-03-07-16-00-00/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-03-07-16-00-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Calgary.
I’ll give a speech about the Azure functions and Microsoft flow “Introduction to Azure Functions and Flow”.
Flow and Azure Functions are two new tools you now have for rapid applications development. It’s a revolution that changes the way of building and delivering modern applications. Instead of shipping a monolithic bloc, which can take up to a few months, we’ll now deliver each feature as a part of the solution.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Brussels 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-09-22-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-09-22-14-00-00/</guid><description>This year I have the privilege to speak at SPS Brussels
I’ll give a speech about “setting up your release pipeline for office 365/SharePoint”. (aka devops)
We’ll see together how you can leverage azure and visual studio team services to implement devops processes and increase quality and save time.
If you’re in the area on Oct the 15th don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Oslo 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-09-15-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-09-15-14-00-00/</guid><description>This year I have the privilege to speak at SPS Oslo
I’ll give a speech about “setting up your release pipeline for office 365/SharePoint”. (aka devops)
We’ll see together how you can leverage azure and visual studio team services to implement devops processes and increase quality and save time.
If you’re in the area on Oct the 22nd don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Detroit 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-09-09-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-09-09-14-00-00/</guid><description>This year I have the privilege to speak at SPS Detroit
I’ll give a speech about “setting up your release pipeline for office 365/SharePoint”. (aka devops)
We’ll see together how you can leverage azure and visual studio team services to implement devops processes and increase quality and save time.
If you’re in the area On Sept the 10th don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday New York City 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-07-30-09-28-00/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2016 09:28:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-07-30-09-28-00/</guid><description>This year I have the privilege to speak at SPS New York City.
I’ll give a speech about “setting up your release pipeline for office 365/SharePoint”.
We’ll see together how you can leverage azure and visual studio team services to implement devops processes and increase quality and save time.
I&amp;rsquo;ll also be giving Sebastien Levert&amp;rsquo;s session “deep dive in Microsoft graph” as he can&amp;rsquo;t make it to the event.
If you’re in the area today (I know it&amp;rsquo;s short notice) don’t hesitate to register to the event.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Vancouver 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-02-10-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-02-10-14-00-00/</guid><description>This year I have the privilege to speak at SPS Vancouver (first time!!). I’ll give a speech about the importance of metadata in your company (therefore in SharePoint/Office 365)
If you’re in the area Saturday March the 12th 2016 don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions. This is a good occasion to expand your network, learn a lot of things and to spend a good day.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Ottawa 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-11-10-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-11-10-14-00-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Ottawa. I’ll give a speech about the ALM capabilities for SharePoint/Office365 in Azure “Setting up your release pipeline for SharePoint in Azure”.
If you’re in the area Saturday November the 21st 2015 don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions. This is a good occasion to expand your network, learn a lot of things and to spend a good day.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday New Hampshire 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-10-23-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-10-23-14-00-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS New Hampshire. I’ll give a speech about the multilingualism capabilities of SharePoint “Translating SharePoint from beginning to ending”.
We’ll talk about how you can successfully implement an multilingual intranet, team sites or public sites using SharePoint.
If you’re in the area Saturday October the 24th 2015 don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Toronto 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-09-11-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-09-11-14-00-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Toronto. I’ll give a speech about the graph “Making Graph data useful to your company”.
We’ll talk about the Graph, delve, yammer, machine learning and a lot of other interesting concepts and the conversation will be aimed towards developers.
If you’re in the area Saturday September the 19th 2015 don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions.</description></item><item><title>New Microsoft Conference: the AzureCon</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/new-microsoft-conference-the-a/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/new-microsoft-conference-the-a/</guid><description>Hi everybody!
Short post to let you know that Microsoft recently announced a new event: the AzureCon. First edition on Sept the 29th.
This free online event will focus on Microsoft’s cloud technologies (mostly Azure) and will be about news and things to come on the platform.
Great speakers, awesome content, this is the occasion for you to learn a lot about Azure technologies and their usage.
This conference should happen multiple times a year (approximately 4), main reason being: ”with releases and updates every 3 weeks for each service, we simply couldn’t wait for an annual event to announce everything like we do with Ignite and Build” (Microsoft Azure Product Manager)</description></item><item><title>Speaker at Collab365</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaker-at-collab365/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaker-at-collab365/</guid><description>I’ve been greatly honored being selected to be speaker at collab 365.
This event directly comes from the sp24 with the spbiz which happened a few months from now. It’s a free online event which will take place on October the 8th during 24 hours all around the globe.
Adding to the fact I’ll be speaking at this event among other great speakers, I also have the great privilege to give 4 sessions (oh yeah!</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Montréal 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-05-21-00-50-33/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:50:33 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-05-21-00-50-33/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Montréal
/montreal-sharepoint-saturday-2
I also had the occasion to help organize the event this year, it’s been an interesting experience so far and I’d like to thank Serge, Nico, Luc, Philippe, Seb, Fabrice and Alain for their implication in that project, it’s much more work than what we think!
My session will be about the importance of metadata in your company.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SPBizConf</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-spbizconf/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 22:58:08 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-spbizconf/</guid><description>The SPBizConf (https://www.spbizconf.com/ ) will happen on June 17th and 18th of 2015.
This conference is mostly oriented towards business users (with a bit of technical content) and is free and online.
Don’t wait to sign up!
I’ll have the opportunity to give a session about the Graph. We’ll have a theoretical part to ensure everybody has got basis, a part talking about Microsoft’s Graph and Microsoft’s vision around the Graph to wrap up with a part with real business cases and explain how you could use it in your company.</description></item><item><title>MVP Virtual Conference</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/mvp-virtual-conference/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 22:34:11 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/mvp-virtual-conference/</guid><description>American (US, Canada, Latin…) Microsoft MVP’s are organizing a two days free online conference on May the 14th and the 15th.
If you want to know which sessions will be available you can click here
https://mvp.microsoft.com/en-us/virtualconference-agenda.aspx
To register to the event https://mvp.microsoft.com/en-us/virtualconference-sessions.aspx
I’ll be the moderator for Sébastien Levert’s session “introduction to AngularJS applications in Office 365”
It’s a great opportunity to connect with experts from all around the world.</description></item><item><title>Montreal SharePoint Saturday 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/montreal-sharepoint-saturday-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 23:17:50 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/montreal-sharepoint-saturday-2/</guid><description>Montreal will have a SharePoint Saturday this year too!
Just as a reminder SharePoint Saturdays are:
Free events Happening all around the world Dedicated to SharePoint/Office 365 On Saturdays With great sessions and awesome speakers Practical information This year’s edition will be on May the 23rd at “college maisonneuse”. You just have to register here https://www.spsevents.org/city/montreal/montreal2015
Last year the SPS MTL brought together 200 persons. This year will try to have even more people with 4 tracks (20 sessions total).</description></item><item><title>Speaking at the SharePoint Saturday Ottawa 2014 !</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-sharepoint-sat-2014-10-08-23-40-00/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 23:40:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-sharepoint-sat-2014-10-08-23-40-00/</guid><description>I’m proud to announce I’ll be speaking at the SharePoint Saturday Ottawa 2014. The event will be held close to Ottawa on November the 18th and you can get all the details here https://www.spsevents.org/city/ottawa/ottawa2014
I will be presenting this session with Fabrice Vaxelaire (AKA Great Venerable) and we’ll be talking about building your business portal in Office 365: Nowadays we have business tools and portals everywhere in the company, what are the benefits of having everything at one place?</description></item><item><title>Speaking at the SharePoint Saturday New Hampshire 2014 !</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-sharepoint-sat-2014-10-01-23-34-03/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 23:34:03 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-sharepoint-sat-2014-10-01-23-34-03/</guid><description>I’m proud to announce I’ll be speaking at the SharePoint Saturday New Hampshire 2014. The event will be held in Nashua on October the 18th and you can get all the details here https://bit.ly/spsnh2014
I will be presenting this session with Fabrice Vaxelaire (AKA Great Venerable) and we’ll be talking about building your business portal in Office 365: Nowadays we have business tools and portals everywhere in the company, what are the benefits of having everything at one place?</description></item><item><title>Selected for SharePoint Saturday New York City</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/selected-for-sharepoint-saturd/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2014 03:43:34 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/selected-for-sharepoint-saturd/</guid><description>Hi Everybody!
I’m pleased to announce you that I’ll be speaking at SharePoint Saturday New York City.
The event is free and will occur at Microsoft New York City’s office, on time square.
Check it out, is a very good opportunity to learn plenty of things if you can be there.
https://www.spsevents.org/city/NYC/NYC2014/sessions
See you soon!</description></item><item><title>Help me to speak at SP24 the first SharePoint (web) conference all around the world!</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/help-me-to-speak-at-sp24-the-f/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2014 22:05:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/help-me-to-speak-at-sp24-the-f/</guid><description>Some great SharePoint MVP’s are organizing an amazing event on April the 16th/17th : the SP24.
The idea is:
Amazing speakers
Amazing conferences
All around the world
2 tracks
48 sessions
A few thousands attendees
24 hours straight
You even get to choose the sessions!
And it’s free
Translating SharePoint 2013 from beginning to ending Really motivated by this great concept I decided to apply for a conference. Please help me to speak to this great event and vote now!</description></item><item><title>Speaker at SharePoint Saturday Ottawa!</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaker-at-sharepoint-saturday/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2013 03:20:22 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaker-at-sharepoint-saturday/</guid><description>Hi everybody, I’m thrilled to announce that I’ll be speaking at SharePoint Saturday Ottawa. On Nov the 23rd!
My session: translating SharePoint 2013 from beginning to ending. We’ll cover all multilingualism provided by SharePoint.
With lot of examples and demonstrations we’ll see what are the tools provided to IT pro’s, power users and developers. The goal of this session is to give you some insight about how to get your SharePoint environment in multiple languages seamlessly.</description></item></channel></rss>