<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Community on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/community/</link><description>Recent content in Community on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 07:59:57 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>One year as a Software Developer at Microsoft</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/one-year-developer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/one-year-developer/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="one-year-as-a-software-developer-at-microsoft">One year as a Software Developer at Microsoft&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Back in September 2020, I published a &lt;a href="https://baywet.github.io/pm-experience-dev-sdk/">blog post about my experience as a Program Manager at Microsoft that was well received&lt;/a>. It made me realize that the community was curious and interested about this role. In this post, I will share my insights as a developer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before we begin, &lt;strong>keep in mind this is my personal experience&lt;/strong>, which may differ a lot from team to team, product to product and depend on other circumstances (being remote, culture, etc…).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Revamping the Microsoft Graph Java SDK: a recipe to revive open-source repositories</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/github-repo-revival/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/github-repo-revival/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Back in August 2020 I became the main maintainer of the &lt;a href="https://github.com/microsoftgraph/msgraph-sdk-java">Microsoft Graph Java SDK&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The team had to deprioritize this SDK in favor of other languages due to a lack of staff. About 100+ issues were open, as well as 15 pull requests from the community. Dependencies and tooling had not been updated, the Android story was unclear, no innovation had been done in a long time, the repository felt abandoned and caused a lot of frustrations…&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Moving to a new location and celebrating a decade of blogging</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/new-blog-location/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/new-blog-location/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="welcome-to-my-new-blog">Welcome to my new blog!&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Welcome to my new blog on github.io, powered by open source. I&amp;rsquo;ll be shutting down the old one so make sure you update your RSS subscriptions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="10-years-of-blogging">10 years of blogging&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Can you believe it? I&amp;rsquo;ve been blogging for 10 years now! At the time I was almost a Microsoft Student Partner and my first blog post (in French) was about &lt;a href="https://baywet.github.io/fr/le-cloud-computing-oui-mais-p/">cloud computing&lt;/a> (which was a new thing back then).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Joining Microsoft as a Program Manager on the Microsoft Graph</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/joining-microsoft-as-a-program/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 11:22:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/joining-microsoft-as-a-program/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="tl-dr">TL; DR&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I’ll be starting at Microsoft as a Program Manager on the Microsoft Graph in January. This is an exiting change and I’d like to take the time to thank 2toLead for the amazing last few years.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="new-role">New role&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I’m exited to announce I’ll be starting at Microsoft in January as a Program Manager on the Microsoft Graph (and other Microsoft Identity Platform topics). I’ll be part of the MIP organization and in the extended team of brilliant people like Yina Arenas, Jeremy Thake, Darrel Miller and many more.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Recording available: Microsoft Graph September Community call - Provisioning demo</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/recording-available-microsoft/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 14:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/recording-available-microsoft/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last September I was invited to speak again on the Microsoft Graph Community call. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know about it, this free online monthly call brings together Microsoft Product Team members and Community members demonstrating new capabilities and real world examples.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is a great way to catch up on the latest news and I highly recommend you attend it if you work with the Microsoft Graph or would like to. (see attached link)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SharePoint Framework and DevOps Practices: New Documentation, New Samples</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/sharepoint-framework-and-devop/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/sharepoint-framework-and-devop/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="tl-dr">TL; DR;&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>With the release of Azure DevOps, there’s some &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/sharepoint/dev/spfx/toolchain/implement-ci-cd-with-azure-devops">new SPFX documentation&lt;/a> to set up your CI/CD pipeline in Azure DevOps.  Have a look and share your thoughts.  Your feedback is always welcome! The Patterns and Practices Initiative also includes a newly reorganized DevOps repository for tools and samples around &lt;a href="https://github.com/SharePoint/sp-dev-build-extensions">SharePoint Framework Build and Deploy Practices&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-long-story">The long story&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="my-journey-into-the-sharepoint-devops-world">My journey into the SharePoint DevOps world&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I have been working around Application Lifecycle Management (ALM), Continuous Integration (CI), Continuous Deployment (CD) and DevOps practices in the SharePoint/Azure/Office 365 ecosystem for several years.  In my experience, whether you’re working alone or as part of a team, adopting proper ALM practices is crucial if you want to produce high quality code.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Availability of office 365 Samples and SDK on Github</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/availability-of-office-365-sam/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 16:53:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/availability-of-office-365-sam/</guid><description>&lt;p>For those who have not seen it yet Microsoft teams who work on Office 365 have created a hub on GitHub.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/officedev">https://github.com/officedev&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What are you going to find there?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Examples of code made by Microsoft and the community&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Demonstrations presented during the sessions from Microsoft and the community&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Part of the &amp;lsquo;documents&amp;rsquo; sources for the MSDN documentation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SDK for &amp;rsquo;third&amp;rsquo; platforms (IOS, android&amp;hellip;)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>…&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The message behind that is Microsoft is investing in the community and wants to create a single place where developers (from any platform) can meet to participate in the projects together and share content. Therefore do not hesitate to have a look and to submit content / patches / projects.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The former MSP becomes MVP</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/the-former-msp-becomes-mvp/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2014 01:37:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/the-former-msp-becomes-mvp/</guid><description>&lt;p>SharePoint MVP&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://baywet.github.io/the-former-msp-becomes-mvp/clip_5F00_image002_5F00_thumb_5F00_2DFB8F5C.png" alt="clip_5F00_image002_5F00_thumb_5F00_2DFB8F5C.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>You may already have heard about it on social network, I’m a SharePoint Server MVP since April the 1st.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m really proud to be a part of this awesome community counting Microsoft technologies best professionals and great communities’ contributors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This incoming year will be full of events, community activities and projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I would like to thank:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Jean-Sébastien DUCHENE&lt;/strong>: Enterprise Client Management French MVP for his advises and for encouraging me to become an MVP (I thought I was not good enough to make it).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>