<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Job on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/job/</link><description>Recent content in Job on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</managingEditor><webMaster>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 15:51:13 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/job/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My personal experience as a Program Manager and switching back to development</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/pm-experience-dev-sdk/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/pm-experience-dev-sdk/</guid><description>Switching back to the light side of the force: becoming a developer again I recently transitioned from Program Manager on Microsoft Graph to Software Developer in the Microsoft Graph SDKs team. I&amp;rsquo;d like to thank my previous team for welcoming me these last 7 months and allowing me to experiment with the role of Program Manager.
I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share with you some of my experience and learnings as a Program Manager.</description></item><item><title>Joining Microsoft as a Program Manager on the Microsoft Graph</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/joining-microsoft-as-a-program/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 11:22:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/joining-microsoft-as-a-program/</guid><description>TL; DR I’ll be starting at Microsoft as a Program Manager on the Microsoft Graph in January. This is an exiting change and I’d like to take the time to thank 2toLead for the amazing last few years.
New role I’m exited to announce I’ll be starting at Microsoft in January as a Program Manager on the Microsoft Graph (and other Microsoft Identity Platform topics). I’ll be part of the MIP organization and in the extended team of brilliant people like Yina Arenas, Jeremy Thake, Darrel Miller and many more.</description></item></channel></rss>