<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Conference on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/conference/</link><description>Recent content in Conference on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 20:13:02 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/conference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Speaking at Caribbean Developer Conference 2022</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-cdc-2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 12:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-cdc-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I’m honoured to announce that I’ve been selected to speak at the &lt;a href="https://cdc.dev/"&gt;Caribbean Developer Conference 2022&lt;/a&gt; happening in Punta Cana Nov 3-5th. This is the first time I’ll be speaking at this event, but I’ve heard lots of good things about it from people who previously spoke there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll be presenting “Turbocharge your API integration with Microsoft Kiota” where I’ll be introducing through lots of demonstrations how you can generate a client generated for any OpenAPI described API using &lt;a href="https://microsoft.github.io/kiota"&gt;Microsoft Kiota&lt;/a&gt; and other tools.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Speaking at CollabDays Belgium 2022</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-collabdays-belgium-2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 12:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-collabdays-belgium-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I’m honoured to announce that I’ve been selected to speak at the &lt;a href="https://www.collabdays.org/2022-belgium/"&gt;CollabDays Belgium 2022&lt;/a&gt; (formerly SPS Events, aka SharePoint Saturday) happening in Brussels Saturday 15th of October. This event is dear to my heart as it’s one of the first international events I ever got to speak at, it always attracts a great crowd and brings together internationally regarded speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll be presenting “Turbocharge your API integration with Microsoft Kiota” where I’ll be introducing through lots of demonstrations how you can generate a client generated for any OpenAPI described API using &lt;a href="https://microsoft.github.io/kiota"&gt;Microsoft Kiota&lt;/a&gt; and other tools.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Speaking at the API specification conference 2022</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-api-specification-conf-2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 12:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-api-specification-conf-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I’m extremely pleased to announce I’ll be speaking at the &lt;a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/openapi-asc"&gt;API specification conference 2022 in San Francisco, Sept 19-21st&lt;/a&gt;. During “&lt;a href="https://sched.co/1AgrE"&gt;Lessons learned from client generation, gaps and suggestions to address them&lt;/a&gt;”, we’ll be reviewing my 2 years experience building an &lt;a href="https://microsoft.github.io/kiota"&gt;OpenAPI based client generator&lt;/a&gt; and trying to identify solutions to ease up code generation, leading to better clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The API specification conference is the first in person event I’ll be presenting at in almost 3 years, I’m really excited and a bit nervous (do I even remember how to do this anymore?). This conference focuses on the standards (HTTP, OpenAPI, JSON Schema&amp;hellip;) and practices revolving around building APIs, it is organized in partnership with the Linux Foundation and the lineup is impressive!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Build 2020 Microsoft Graph session recordings available</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/msbuild-msgraph-whatsnew/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/msbuild-msgraph-whatsnew/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In case you missed it (and yes I know this post is really late), Microsoft Build 2020 produced hundreds of sessions with great content. The recordings are available on YouTube for free and if you are working with Microsoft Graph, it&amp;rsquo;s a great way to learn about new features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had the opportunity to co-present &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s new with Microsoft Graph?&amp;rdquo; with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elisenyang"&gt;Elise Yang&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"&gt;
 &lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6CIZWac0TBE?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you checkout the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/Microsoft365Developer/playlists?view=50&amp;amp;sort=dd&amp;amp;shelf_id=18"&gt;Microsoft 365 developer build 2020 playlist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Counting Down to ESPC20 Online</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-espc2020/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-espc2020/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="thecountdown-ison-to-espc20-online--only-7-weeks-to-go"&gt;The countdown is on to ESPC20 Online – only 7 weeks to go!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ESPC20 Online is a new virtual conference offering you affordable, world-class Microsoft 365 learning at your fingertips, from wherever you are in the world. Tune in live Oct 14th &amp;amp; 15th or catch up on-demand across 100+ sessions from SharePoint, Office 365 &amp;amp; Azure experts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join me for my ESPC20 Online session: &lt;strong&gt;Build Responsive Applications at Scale using Microsoft Graph Change Notifications with Resource Data&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Speaking at the European SharePoint Conference 2019 - SPFx &amp; DevOps</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-european-share-2019-10-01-18-14-00/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 18:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-european-share-2019-10-01-18-14-00/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The ESPC is one of the biggest technology events in Europe and the biggest with focus on Office 365, SharePoint and Azure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An interesting particularity of this event, they move to a different European capital each year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This years edition will be from &lt;strong&gt;December 2nd to 5th in Prague&lt;/strong&gt; and I&amp;rsquo;m honored to be invited to speak again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting two sessions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to do DevOps with the SharePoint Framework and why it matters?&lt;/strong&gt; This session will be an introduction to DevOps practices and an application of the core principles in a SharePoint Framework context.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Fest DC (Washington) 2018</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-fest-dc-2018-01-05-09-00-00/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-fest-dc-2018-01-05-09-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SharePoint Fest DC (Washington) 2018 is happening from March 26th to March 30th&lt;/strong&gt;. This event will feature 2 days pre-conference workshops and 3 days of conference. &lt;a href="https://www.sharepointfest.com/DC/"&gt;You can find more information about it on the website&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve been selected amongst 44 other speakers to present this year two sessions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="azr204--microsoft-graph-and-sharepoint-framework-under-steroids-with-azure-functions"&gt;AZR204 – Microsoft Graph and SharePoint framework under steroids with Azure Functions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;Modern development means client side first, backend second. However, there are still cases where you might need some backend processing, for long running operations, heavy computing consuming tasks or security concerns.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Ottawa 2017</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-09-07-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-09-07-08-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Ottawa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll give a speech about the graph “Migrate your custom components to the SharePoint Framework ”. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how you can migrate your existing investments in SharePoint development (either full trust solutions or add-ins) to the new SharePoint framework. Migrating these components will not only help you make sure you stay ahead of the technology but will also improve users experience and help migrating to Office 365.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Speaking at Aos Tours Ottawa and Toronto</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-aos-tours-ottawa-a/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2017 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-aos-tours-ottawa-a/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I’ll have the privilege to speak at next AOS (Azure, Office 365, SharePoint) in Ottawa (8th) and Toronto (10th).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll present in English: &lt;strong&gt;Introduction to Azure Functions and Flow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flow and Azure Functions are two new tools you now have for rapid applications development. It’s a revolution that changes the way of building and delivering modern applications. Instead of shipping a monolithic bloc, which can take up to a few months, we’ll now deliver each feature as a part of the solution.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Houston 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-04-01-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-04-01-14-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This year I have the privilege to speak at SPS Houston (first time!!). I’ll give a speech about “Setting up your release pipeline for SharePoint and Office 365 developments”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll see how you can automate all the things to make your development team more productive and more efficient. For that we’ll see how to set up build and release definitions and how you can leverage both azure and on premises environments&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Ottawa 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-11-10-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-11-10-14-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Ottawa. I’ll give a speech about the ALM capabilities for SharePoint/Office365 in Azure “Setting up your release pipeline for SharePoint in Azure”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re in the area Saturday November the 21st 2015 don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions. This is a good occasion to expand your network, learn a lot of things and to spend a good day.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday New Hampshire 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-10-23-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-10-23-14-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS New Hampshire. I’ll give a speech about the multilingualism capabilities of SharePoint “Translating SharePoint from beginning to ending”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll talk about how you can successfully implement an multilingual intranet, team sites or public sites using SharePoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re in the area Saturday October the 24th 2015 don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions. This is a good occasion to expand your network, learn a lot of things and to spend a good day.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>New Microsoft Conference: the AzureCon</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/new-microsoft-conference-the-a/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/new-microsoft-conference-the-a/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Hi everybody!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short post to let you know that Microsoft recently announced a new event: the AzureCon. First edition on Sept the 29th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This free online event will focus on Microsoft’s cloud technologies (mostly Azure) and will be about news and things to come on the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great speakers, awesome content, this is the occasion for you to learn a lot about Azure technologies and their usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This conference should happen multiple times a year (approximately 4), main reason being: ”with releases and updates every 3 weeks for each service, we simply couldn’t wait for an annual event to announce everything like we do with Ignite and Build” (Microsoft Azure Product Manager)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SPBizConf</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-spbizconf/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 22:58:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-spbizconf/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The SPBizConf (&lt;a href="https://www.spbizconf.com/"&gt;https://www.spbizconf.com/&lt;/a&gt; ) will happen on June 17th and 18th of 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This conference is mostly oriented towards business users (with a bit of technical content) and is free and online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t wait to sign up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll have the opportunity to give a session about the Graph. We’ll have a theoretical part to ensure everybody has got basis, a part talking about Microsoft’s Graph and Microsoft’s vision around the Graph to wrap up with a part with real business cases and explain how you could use it in your company.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>MVP Virtual Conference</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/mvp-virtual-conference/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 22:34:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/mvp-virtual-conference/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;American (US, Canada, Latin…) Microsoft MVP’s are organizing a two days free online conference on May the 14th and the 15th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to know which sessions will be available you can click here&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://mvp.microsoft.com/en-us/virtualconference-agenda.aspx"&gt;https://mvp.microsoft.com/en-us/virtualconference-agenda.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To register to the event &lt;a href="https://mvp.microsoft.com/en-us/virtualconference-sessions.aspx"&gt;https://mvp.microsoft.com/en-us/virtualconference-sessions.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll be the moderator for Sébastien Levert’s session “introduction to AngularJS applications in Office 365”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a great opportunity to connect with experts from all around the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>