<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Toronto on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/toronto/</link><description>Recent content in Toronto on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 07:59:57 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/toronto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Guest of the Intrazone podcast</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/guest-of-the-intrazone-podcast/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/guest-of-the-intrazone-podcast/</guid><description>&lt;p>As 2018 is concluding (we’ll be in 2019 by the time this blog post is published), I’ve taken a few days off to rest, spend time with the family, play video games, read, watch movies and… catch up on my blog posts writing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Almost a month ago now I was presenting at the &lt;a href="https://www.spsevents.org/city/toronto/toronto2018">SharePoint Saturday Toronto&lt;/a>, huge thanks to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RIZinsights">Eric Riz&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/kkhipple">Kanwal Khipple&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nkhamis">Noorez Khamiz&lt;/a> for organizing the event! More importantly, they had to find a new venue at the last minute because the original one was forced to closed done for a few days and they pulled it off!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Presenting at the Microsoft Ignite Tour Toronto</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/presenting-at-the-microsoft-ig/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/presenting-at-the-microsoft-ig/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Microsoft Ignite tour is a series of events that take place in cities around the world. This series of events is organized by Microsoft and presenters are picked among Microsoft Employees, Regional Directors and MVPs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll have the opportunity to present one session “&lt;strong>How to do DevOps with the SharePoint Framework and why it matters?&lt;/strong>”. During this session we will explore together how you can setup your continuous integration and continuous deployment pipeline leveraging Azure DevOps (formerly Visual Studio Team Services).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Toronto 2018</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-11-20-09-00-00/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-11-20-09-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Toronto.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll give a speech about “&lt;strong>Migrate your custom components to the SharePoint Framework&lt;/strong>”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Together we will see how you can transition from &lt;strong>either the server-side object model or the add-ins development fashions to the modern SharePoint Framework approach&lt;/strong>. This session is mostly meant for developers and technical architects who are curious about getting started on the new model and that might have legacy applications.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at Aos Tours Ottawa and Toronto</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-aos-tours-ottawa-a/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2017 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-aos-tours-ottawa-a/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ll have the privilege to speak at next AOS (Azure, Office 365, SharePoint) in Ottawa (8th) and Toronto (10th).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll present in English: &lt;strong>Introduction to Azure Functions and Flow&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Flow and Azure Functions are two new tools you now have for rapid applications development. It’s a revolution that changes the way of building and delivering modern applications. Instead of shipping a monolithic bloc, which can take up to a few months, we’ll now deliver each feature as a part of the solution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Toronto 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-09-11-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-09-11-14-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Toronto. I’ll give a speech about the graph “Making Graph data useful to your company”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We’ll talk about the Graph, delve, yammer, machine learning and a lot of other interesting concepts and the conversation will be aimed towards developers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re in the area Saturday September the 19th 2015 don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions. This is a good occasion to expand your network, learn a lot of things and to spend a good day.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>