<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Session on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/session/</link><description>Recent content in Session on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</managingEditor><webMaster>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 15:51:13 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/session/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Detroit 2017</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-11-16-17-26-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 17:26:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-11-16-17-26-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Detroit.
I’ll give a speech about “Improving DevOps using Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Business Productivity Tools and more” and I&amp;rsquo;ll be co-presenting the session with my friend Haniel Croitoru.
We&amp;rsquo;ll explore together how DevOps practices impact and improve solutions delivery for your customers and for the best. With real life scenarios and experience for the field we&amp;rsquo;ll show you how you can get started and what to expect out of it.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at Techorama Belgium 2017</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-techorama-belgium/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-techorama-belgium/</guid><description>Techorama is a 2-day event that takes place in Antwerp, Belgium from May 22nd to May 24th.
They lined up great speakers from Microsoft and other big industry players, checkout the agenda here https://techorama.be/agenda/
I have the pleasure to announce I’ve been selected and I’ll be giving two sessions:
Set up your DevOps process for SharePoint/Office365
Migrate your custom components to the SharePoint framework
Tickets are still available so if you are in the area or can travel there I would strongly suggest you check-it out!</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Vancouver 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-02-10-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-02-10-14-00-00/</guid><description>This year I have the privilege to speak at SPS Vancouver (first time!!). I’ll give a speech about the importance of metadata in your company (therefore in SharePoint/Office 365)
If you’re in the area Saturday March the 12th 2016 don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions. This is a good occasion to expand your network, learn a lot of things and to spend a good day.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Ottawa 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-11-10-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-11-10-14-00-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Ottawa. I’ll give a speech about the ALM capabilities for SharePoint/Office365 in Azure “Setting up your release pipeline for SharePoint in Azure”.
If you’re in the area Saturday November the 21st 2015 don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions. This is a good occasion to expand your network, learn a lot of things and to spend a good day.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Montréal 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-05-21-00-50-33/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:50:33 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-05-21-00-50-33/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Montréal
/montreal-sharepoint-saturday-2
I also had the occasion to help organize the event this year, it’s been an interesting experience so far and I’d like to thank Serge, Nico, Luc, Philippe, Seb, Fabrice and Alain for their implication in that project, it’s much more work than what we think!
My session will be about the importance of metadata in your company.</description></item><item><title>Help me to speak at SP24 the first SharePoint (web) conference all around the world!</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/help-me-to-speak-at-sp24-the-f/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2014 22:05:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/help-me-to-speak-at-sp24-the-f/</guid><description>Some great SharePoint MVP’s are organizing an amazing event on April the 16th/17th : the SP24.
The idea is:
Amazing speakers
Amazing conferences
All around the world
2 tracks
48 sessions
A few thousands attendees
24 hours straight
You even get to choose the sessions!
And it’s free
Translating SharePoint 2013 from beginning to ending Really motivated by this great concept I decided to apply for a conference. Please help me to speak to this great event and vote now!</description></item></channel></rss>