<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Csom on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/csom/</link><description>Recent content in Csom on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</managingEditor><webMaster>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 16:56:03 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/csom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SystemUpdate method available in CSOM at last!!!</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/systemupdate-method-available/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/systemupdate-method-available/</guid><description>That’s good news for SharePoint developers, the SystemUpdate method is finally available in Client Side Object Model.
Indeed, Microsoft has recently released an update for nugget packages and the method is part of the new stuff.
https://dev.office.com/blogs/new-sharepoint-csom-version-released-for-Office-365-august-2016-updated
It’s an important method because it allows you to update a list item without changing modification date, author, publishing and versioning information.
Moreover, we’re numerous SharePoint developers migrating a lot of full trust solutions to SharePoint Add-ins, some of which were using this method and in some cases we have only an app-only context.</description></item><item><title>Programmatically add permissions to “everyone” in SharePoint Online</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/programmatically-add-permissio/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/programmatically-add-permissio/</guid><description>At some point you may want to add permissions to the “everyone” “groupe” of SharePoint.
Indeed this will allow you to set permissions to all users already having access to this site (because they are already members of other groups or already have permissions). This “group” is different of “NT AUTHORITY\authenticated users » which represents successfully identified users (bigger group).
The only thing is that “group” is in fact a user, so it’s helpless to iterate on every group of the site collection hoping to find it.</description></item><item><title>unable to find version '3.1.2' of package 'appforsharepointonlinewebtoolkit'</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/unable-to-find-version-312-of/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/unable-to-find-version-312-of/</guid><description>With office development tools for visual studio 2015 (and probably with august 2015 update for vs 2013 too, but I haven’t tried it), you may run into the following error:
unable to find version &amp;lsquo;3.1.2&amp;rsquo; of package &amp;lsquo;appforsharepointonlinewebtoolkit&amp;rsquo;
And so while doing an “update-package” in nuget console or if you have a restore packages step in your build process. (mandatory if like me you don’t include the packages folder into source control).</description></item></channel></rss>