<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vhd on Le blog de baywet</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/fr/tags/vhd/</link><description>Recent content in Vhd on Le blog de baywet</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>fr</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 11:06:28 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/fr/tags/vhd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The VHD must be stored as a page blob. Upload a vhd to azure</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/fr/the-vhd-must-be-stored-as-a-pa-2014-03-05-01-45-11/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 01:45:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/fr/the-vhd-must-be-stored-as-a-pa-2014-03-05-01-45-11/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://baywet.github.io/fr/the-vhd-must-be-stored-as-a-pa-2014-03-05-01-45-11/clip_5F00_image002_5F00_thumb_5F00_223A25CA.jpg" alt="clip_5F00_image002_5F00_thumb_5F00_223A25CA.jpg">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="context">Context&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I recently had to setup a SharePoint farm on Azure. It’s a great tool in terms of provisioning delays and simplicity of usage. In order to setup my farm I needed ISO files (installation media). The most recommended way to do that according to the documentation is to locally create a vhd file and upload it to azure to then attach it to your machine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a fellow developer I thought right away “azure has a great tooling inside Visual Studio, we have a storage explorer, let’s use it”. If you did not know it, it is located in the server explorer window on the left.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The VHD must be stored as a page blob. Uploader un vhd vers azure</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/fr/the-vhd-must-be-stored-as-a-pa-2014-03-05-01-40-57/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 01:40:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/fr/the-vhd-must-be-stored-as-a-pa-2014-03-05-01-40-57/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://baywet.github.io/fr/the-vhd-must-be-stored-as-a-pa-2014-03-05-01-40-57/clip_5F00_image002_5F00_thumb_5F00_234C3B1E.jpg" alt="clip_5F00_image002_5F00_thumb_5F00_234C3B1E.jpg">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="mise-en-contexte">Mise en contexte&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Récemment j’ai dû monter une ferme SharePoint sur Windows Azure. C’est très pratique en termes de délais de provisionnement et de simplicité d’utilisation. Pour monter ma ferme, j’avais besoin de fichiers ISO (de sources d’installation). En lisant la documentation j’apprends que la manière la plus recommandée d’effectuer cela est de tout mettre dans un vhd en local, de pousser ce vhd sur azure puis de l’attacher à la vm en question.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>