<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>best practices on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/best-practices/</link><description>Recent content in best practices on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</managingEditor><webMaster>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2014 03:58:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/best-practices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Localizing JavaScript of a Full Trust solution</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/localizing-javascript-of-a-ful/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2014 03:58:16 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/localizing-javascript-of-a-ful/</guid><description>Introduction We, SharePoint developers of ancient times when &amp;ldquo;full trust&amp;rdquo; solutions ruled, have understood one thing: using JavaScript improves by far our solutions.
Indeed this allows to reduce the load of the servers and makes the user experience more &amp;ldquo;responsive&amp;rdquo;.
But what if you want to display messages in different languages depending on the user? In .NET (understand server-side) it is quite simple, just use of resources. (see one of my posts on the subject)</description></item><item><title>Why should you not include telerik controls in your SharePoint products?</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/why-should-you-not-include-tel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 03:32:04 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/why-should-you-not-include-tel/</guid><description>First and foremost this article is a feedback from the field of a very particular case of SharePoint development. Telerik products and components are very good and accelerate your developments (SharePoint or not) providing you advanced and customizable controls.
Some of you already know it, I work in a team that develops products for SharePoint (www.oceanik.com and the others one do not have yet dedicated sites, we still have work on the marketing).</description></item></channel></rss>