<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Flow on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/flow/</link><description>Recent content in Flow on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</managingEditor><webMaster>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 16:56:03 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/flow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Brussels 2017</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-07-13-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-07-13-08-00-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Brussels.
I’ll give a speech about the Azure functions and Microsoft flow “Introduction to Azure Functions and Flow”. Flow and Azure Functions are two new tools you now have for rapid applications development. It’s a revolution that changes the way of building and delivering modern applications. Instead of shipping a monolithic bloc, which can take up to a few months, we’ll now deliver each feature as a part of the solution.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Calgary 2017</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-03-07-16-00-00/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-03-07-16-00-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Calgary.
I’ll give a speech about the Azure functions and Microsoft flow “Introduction to Azure Functions and Flow”.
Flow and Azure Functions are two new tools you now have for rapid applications development. It’s a revolution that changes the way of building and delivering modern applications. Instead of shipping a monolithic bloc, which can take up to a few months, we’ll now deliver each feature as a part of the solution.</description></item></channel></rss>