<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2015 on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/2015/</link><description>Recent content in 2015 on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 11:06:28 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/2015/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Ottawa 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-11-10-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-11-10-14-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Ottawa. I’ll give a speech about the ALM capabilities for SharePoint/Office365 in Azure “Setting up your release pipeline for SharePoint in Azure”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re in the area Saturday November the 21st 2015 don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions. This is a good occasion to expand your network, learn a lot of things and to spend a good day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Toronto 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-09-11-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-09-11-14-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Toronto. I’ll give a speech about the graph “Making Graph data useful to your company”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We’ll talk about the Graph, delve, yammer, machine learning and a lot of other interesting concepts and the conversation will be aimed towards developers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re in the area Saturday September the 19th 2015 don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions. This is a good occasion to expand your network, learn a lot of things and to spend a good day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaker at Collab365</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaker-at-collab365/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaker-at-collab365/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://baywet.github.io/speaker-at-collab365/83.jpg" alt="83.jpg">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve been greatly honored being selected to be speaker at collab 365.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This event directly comes from the sp24 with the spbiz which happened a few months from now. It’s a free online event which will take place on October the 8th during 24 hours all around the globe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Adding to the fact I’ll be speaking at this event among other great speakers, I also have the great privilege to give 4 sessions (oh yeah!).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday New York City 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-05-25-01-11-00/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 01:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-05-25-01-11-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS NYC&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.spsevents.org/city/nyc/nyc2015">https://www.spsevents.org/city/nyc/nyc2015&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My session will be about the importance of metadata in your company.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We’ll start by some reminders around the theory and describe what are the advantages and disadvantages of different types of each. Then we’ll see what’s currently supported by SharePoint and what are the available tools. Finally we’ll talk about why it is so important that you set this up in your companies, how it can improve findability of content and how it will help you to move to the Graph.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Montréal 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-05-21-00-50-33/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:50:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-05-21-00-50-33/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Montréal&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://baywet.github.io/../montreal-sharepoint-saturday-2">/montreal-sharepoint-saturday-2&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also had the occasion to help organize the event this year, it’s been an interesting experience so far and I’d like to thank Serge, Nico, Luc, Philippe, Seb, Fabrice and Alain for their implication in that project, it’s much more work than what we think!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My session will be about the importance of metadata in your company. (In French)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Montreal SharePoint Saturday 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/montreal-sharepoint-saturday-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 23:17:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/montreal-sharepoint-saturday-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Montreal will have a SharePoint Saturday this year too!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just as a reminder SharePoint Saturdays are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Free events&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Happening all around the world&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dedicated to SharePoint/Office 365&lt;/li>
&lt;li>On Saturdays&lt;/li>
&lt;li>With great sessions and awesome speakers&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="practical-information">Practical information&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This year’s edition will be on May the 23rd at “college maisonneuse”. You just have to register here &lt;a href="https://www.spsevents.org/city/montreal/montreal2015">https://www.spsevents.org/city/montreal/montreal2015&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last year the SPS MTL brought together 200 persons. This year will try to have even more people with 4 tracks (20 sessions total).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>