<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Speaking on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/speaking/</link><description>Recent content in Speaking on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 07:59:57 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/speaking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Speaking at Microsoft 365 Saturday Ottawa 2020</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sps-ottawa-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sps-ottawa-2020/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the Microsoft 365 (formerly SPS) Ottawa and I&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong>Introduction To The Microsoft Graph: Getting Started Quickly &amp;amp; Getting The Most Out Of It&lt;/strong>&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Together we will cover the basics of Microsoft Graph, the Microsoft Identity Platform, the value it provides to developers and how to get started.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because of the ongoing pandemic, the event will be digital only and held on Microsoft Teams. This means you can attend the event for free from anywhere in the world! The organizing team had been putting a lot of efforts into making sure attendees get the most of this digital format.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Microsoft Build 2020 Microsoft Graph session recordings available</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/msbuild-msgraph-whatsnew/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/msbuild-msgraph-whatsnew/</guid><description>&lt;p>In case you missed it (and yes I know this post is really late), Microsoft Build 2020 produced hundreds of sessions with great content. The recordings are available on YouTube for free and if you are working with Microsoft Graph, it&amp;rsquo;s a great way to learn about new features.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I had the opportunity to co-present &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s new with Microsoft Graph?&amp;rdquo; with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elisenyang">Elise Yang&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
 &lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6CIZWac0TBE?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video">&lt;/iframe>
 &lt;/div>

&lt;p>Make sure you checkout the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/Microsoft365Developer/playlists?view=50&amp;amp;sort=dd&amp;amp;shelf_id=18">Microsoft 365 developer build 2020 playlist&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Counting Down to ESPC20 Online</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-espc2020/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-espc2020/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="thecountdown-ison-to-espc20-online--only-7-weeks-to-go">The countdown is on to ESPC20 Online – only 7 weeks to go!&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>ESPC20 Online is a new virtual conference offering you affordable, world-class Microsoft 365 learning at your fingertips, from wherever you are in the world. Tune in live Oct 14th &amp;amp; 15th or catch up on-demand across 100+ sessions from SharePoint, Office 365 &amp;amp; Azure experts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Join me for my ESPC20 Online session: &lt;strong>Build Responsive Applications at Scale using Microsoft Graph Change Notifications with Resource Data&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New tutorial: build your custom provisioning solution for Office 365</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/new-tutorial-build-your-custom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 11:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/new-tutorial-build-your-custom/</guid><description>&lt;p>I couple of days ago I had the opportunity to animate a workshop with the amazing Franck Cornu at the Modern Workplace Conference Paris.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We decided to make all the labs available under PnP for you to learn new technologies and patterns.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you follow the steps described in the labs, you will learn about technologies like Azure Logic Apps, Azure Functions, the Microsoft Graph, Azure Durable Functions, SharePoint WebHook, PnP Provisioning and much more.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Recording available PnP Call December 5th - Office 365 CLI externalize</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/recording-available-pnp-call-d/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 10:56:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/recording-available-pnp-call-d/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was invited to demonstrate the new Office 365 CLI externalize command during on the of recent PnP calls.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can watch the full call &lt;a href="https://developer.microsoft.com/en-us/office/blogs/sharepoint-framework-community-call-recording-5th-of-december-2019/">here&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a reminder this new command allows you to scan a SPFx project and get the external configuration automatically.
Doing this reduces greatly the size of your solutions, improving performances for end users.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can watch the command in action below and read the documentation &lt;a href="https://pnp.github.io/office365-cli/cmd/spfx/project/project-externalize/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at the European SharePoint Conference 2019 - SPFx &amp; DevOps</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-european-share-2019-10-01-18-14-00/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 18:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-european-share-2019-10-01-18-14-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>The ESPC is one of the biggest technology events in Europe and the biggest with focus on Office 365, SharePoint and Azure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An interesting particularity of this event, they move to a different European capital each year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This years edition will be from &lt;strong>December 2nd to 5th in Prague&lt;/strong> and I&amp;rsquo;m honored to be invited to speak again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting two sessions:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>How to do DevOps with the SharePoint Framework and why it matters?&lt;/strong> This session will be an introduction to DevOps practices and an application of the core principles in a SharePoint Framework context.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Recording available: Microsoft Graph September Community call - Provisioning demo</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/recording-available-microsoft/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 14:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/recording-available-microsoft/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last September I was invited to speak again on the Microsoft Graph Community call. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know about it, this free online monthly call brings together Microsoft Product Team members and Community members demonstrating new capabilities and real world examples.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is a great way to catch up on the latest news and I highly recommend you attend it if you work with the Microsoft Graph or would like to. (see attached link)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Ottawa 2019</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2019-10-01-14-12-00/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 14:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2019-10-01-14-12-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Ottawa and I&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong>Introduction To The Microsoft Graph: Getting Started Quickly &amp;amp; Getting The Most Out Of It&lt;/strong>&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Together we will cover the basics of the Microsoft Graph, the Microsoft Identity Platform, the value it provides to developers and how to get started.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re in the area &lt;strong>Saturday October the 5th 2019&lt;/strong> don’t hesitate to register to the event.
Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at Microsoft Build 2019</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-microsoft-build-20/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-microsoft-build-20/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am deeply honoured and humbled to announce I have been selected to speak at the Microsoft Build 2019, which will be happening from May 6th to 8th in Seattle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The subject is going to be a bit different from my usual speaking area however, we will be talking about&lt;strong>IoT, health and wellbeing.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-microsoft-build-20/3.png" alt="3.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here is the abstract of the session.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Using IoT to improve people’s health and brain power&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Fest DC 2019</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-fest-dc-2019-04-18-07-35-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 07:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-fest-dc-2019-04-18-07-35-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>SharePoint Fest Washington DC 2018 is happening from April 29th to May the 3rd&lt;/strong>. This event will feature 2 days pre-conference workshops and 3 days of conference. &lt;a href="https://www.sharepointfest.com/DC/">You can find more information about it on the website&lt;/a>. I&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting three sessions:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DEV104 - Migrate your custom components to the SharePoint Framework&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Migrate your custom components to the SharePoint Framework.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s the 3rd model Microsoft has come with to customize SharePoint in less than 5 years. You may still have add-ins/apps or even solutions running in production and you’re asking yourself what to do about all that?
Do you have to start all over again? And for how long that new model will last?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Houston 2019</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2019-04-02-02-00-00/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2019-04-02-02-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>It is the second time in a few years I have the ooportunity to speak at the SharePoint Saturday Houston.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll give a speech about &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong>Automating Provisioning For Your Digital Workplace: With Azure Durable Functions &amp;amp; Microsoft Graph&lt;/strong>&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Together we will see how you can improve your provisioning workflows and automate most of it leveraging&lt;strong>Azure Durable Functions and the Microsoft Graph&lt;/strong>. This session is geared mostly towards developers but also for IT pros and deciders that want to gain insights on how to combine business processes and provisioning.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Guest of the Intrazone podcast</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/guest-of-the-intrazone-podcast/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/guest-of-the-intrazone-podcast/</guid><description>&lt;p>As 2018 is concluding (we’ll be in 2019 by the time this blog post is published), I’ve taken a few days off to rest, spend time with the family, play video games, read, watch movies and… catch up on my blog posts writing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Almost a month ago now I was presenting at the &lt;a href="https://www.spsevents.org/city/toronto/toronto2018">SharePoint Saturday Toronto&lt;/a>, huge thanks to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RIZinsights">Eric Riz&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/kkhipple">Kanwal Khipple&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nkhamis">Noorez Khamiz&lt;/a> for organizing the event! More importantly, they had to find a new venue at the last minute because the original one was forced to closed done for a few days and they pulled it off!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Presenting at the Microsoft Ignite Tour Toronto</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/presenting-at-the-microsoft-ig/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/presenting-at-the-microsoft-ig/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Microsoft Ignite tour is a series of events that take place in cities around the world. This series of events is organized by Microsoft and presenters are picked among Microsoft Employees, Regional Directors and MVPs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll have the opportunity to present one session “&lt;strong>How to do DevOps with the SharePoint Framework and why it matters?&lt;/strong>”. During this session we will explore together how you can setup your continuous integration and continuous deployment pipeline leveraging Azure DevOps (formerly Visual Studio Team Services).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at Granite State SharePoint Users Group</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-granite-state-shar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-granite-state-shar/</guid><description>&lt;p>On January the 3rd I’ve been invited to speak (virtually) at the Granite State SharePoint Users group. I’ll be presenting the session “&lt;strong>The Microsoft Graph and the SharePoint Framework on steroids with Azure Functions&lt;/strong>”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This session will demonstrate how you can tap into a wealth of data and insights from the Microsoft Graph, interact with the user using the SharePoint Framework and extend components with complex line of business logic leveraging serverless Azure Functions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday New England 2018</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-08-27-05-00-00/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-08-27-05-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS New England.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll give a speech about “&lt;strong>Improving DevOps using Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Business Productivity Tools and more&lt;/strong>” and I&amp;rsquo;ll be co-presenting the session with my friend &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HCroitoru">Haniel Croitoru&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>We&amp;rsquo;ll explore together how DevOps practices impact and improve solutions delivery for your customers and for the best. With real life scenarios and experience for the field we&amp;rsquo;ll show you how you can get started and what to expect out of it.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at the European SharePoint Conference 2018 and free discount for you!</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-european-share-2018-08-26-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-european-share-2018-08-26-08-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-european-share-2018-08-26-08-00-00/4.png" alt="4.png">
I am delighted to announce I have been selected to speak at the European SharePoint Conference 2018. &lt;strong>This event will take place in Copenhagen, Denmark from the 26th to the 29th of November.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I will be speaking about “&lt;strong>Migrate your custom components to the SharePoint Framework&lt;/strong>”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“&lt;em>It’s the 3rd model Microsoft has come with to customize SharePoint in less than 5 years. You may still have add-ins/apps or even solutions running in production and you’re asking yourself what to do about all that?&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Pittsburgh 2018</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-08-23-05-00-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-08-23-05-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>I Have the pleasure to announce I have been selected to speak at SPS Pittsburgh 2018.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll give a speech about the graph “&lt;strong>How to do Dev-Ops with the SharePoint Framework and why it matters&lt;/strong>”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Together we’ll see why it’s important to follow the DevOps processes, methodologies, and philosophy and how to implement it for the SharePoint Framework with Visual Studio Team Services (or TFS). Go from the original idea to production automating as much as possible!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Fest Seattle 2018</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-fest-se/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-fest-se/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>SharePoint Fest Seattle 2018 is happening from August 20th to 24th&lt;/strong>. This event will feature 2 days pre-conference workshops and 3 days of conference. &lt;a href="https://www.sharepointfest.com/Seattle/">You can find more information about it on the website&lt;/a>. I’ve been selected amongst 74 other speakers (including people from Microsoft product teams!!) to present this year two sessions:&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="azr203---azure-functions-in-the-real-world-lessons-learned--best-practices">AZR203 - Azure Functions In The Real World: Lessons Learned &amp;amp; Best Practices&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>“Azure Functions is one of the most powerful new solutions provided by Microsoft. Customers are leveraging it, and it has generally been available for a year now quietly delivering value across hundreds of projects. Many of you are probably asking yourself questions like “are functions mature enough?” or “are they production ready?” or even “is the right tooling here yet?” when considering this option for your projects.”&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Charlotte 2018</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-08-06-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-08-06-08-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>I Have the pleasure to announce I have been selected to speak at SPS Charlotte 2018.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll give a speech about the graph “&lt;strong>How to do Dev-Ops with the SharePoint Framework and why it matters&lt;/strong>”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Together we’ll see why it’s important to follow the DevOps processes, methodologies, and philosophy and how to implement it for the SharePoint Framework with Visual Studio Team Services (or TFS). Go from the original idea to production automating as much as possible!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Guest on the Microsoft Graph Community call (June): The Online Meeting Solution</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/guest-on-the-microsoft-graph-c/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/guest-on-the-microsoft-graph-c/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://baywet.github.io/guest-on-the-microsoft-graph-c/5.PNG" alt="5.PNG">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I must admit I’ve not been on page lately for the blog posts. However, I had the privilege (among other great speakers) to present during the Microsoft Graph Community call for the month of June.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Microsoft Graph Community calls are online webinar organized by the Microsoft Graph Team. The Team usually presents announcements and then allows time for community speakers to presents discoveries, real life solutions and lessons learnt with the Microsoft Graph. Those call are free to attend and if you’re not already registered, &lt;a href="https://developer.microsoft.com/en-us/office/events/?filterBy=Webcasts">here is all the information you need&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Guest on the Microsoft 365 Dev Podcast: Microsoft Graph Open Extensions and Calendering</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/guest-on-the-microsoft-365-dev/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/guest-on-the-microsoft-365-dev/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last week I had the honor to be a guest on the Microsoft 365 Dev Podcast hosted by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jthake">Jeremy Thake&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/paulschaeflein">Paul Schaeflein&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was the second time I was invited on a podcast (t&lt;a href="https://baywet.github.io/default/b/vincent/posts/entrevue-avec-le-visual-studio-talk-show---sonarqube">he first one being in French about devops&lt;/a>), this is a fun exercise where the content is delivered as a discussion between the hosts and the guests.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During this episode we discussed about two main topics:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The Microsoft Graph open extensions (currently starting a project using those at 2toLead)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Calendar capabilities in the Microsoft Graph (and I shared a few tricks that might interested you if you plan on using those APIs)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I’d like to thank Jeremy and Paul for giving me this opportunity and for the good conversations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday New York City 2018</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-06-27-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-06-27-08-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-06-27-08-00-00/8.jpg" alt="8.jpg">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS NYC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll give a speech about “&lt;strong>Migrate your custom components to the SharePoint Framework&lt;/strong>”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Together we will see how you can transition from either the server-side object model or the add-ins development fashions to the modern SharePoint Framework approach. This session is mostly meant for developers and technical architects who are curious about getting started on the new model and that might have legacy applications.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at the #Techorama Belgium 2018 about the #MicrosoftGraph</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-techorama-belg/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-techorama-belg/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-techorama-belg/11.png" alt="11.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This year again I have the honour to be selected to speak at the Techorama Belgium 2018.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is a &lt;strong>paid event&lt;/strong> taking place at the Kinepolis Antwerp (attending/speaking in a cinema theater is really cool!) &lt;strong>from May 23rd and 24th&lt;/strong>. They have a great content, great speakers (many folks from Microsoft or other MVPs) and if you haven’t booked your ticket yet, I suggest you do!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll be giving two sessions that are related:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Fest DC (Washington) 2018</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-fest-dc-2018-01-05-09-00-00/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-fest-dc-2018-01-05-09-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>SharePoint Fest DC (Washington) 2018 is happening from March 26th to March 30th&lt;/strong>. This event will feature 2 days pre-conference workshops and 3 days of conference. &lt;a href="https://www.sharepointfest.com/DC/">You can find more information about it on the website&lt;/a>. I’ve been selected amongst 44 other speakers to present this year two sessions:&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="azr204--microsoft-graph-and-sharepoint-framework-under-steroids-with-azure-functions">AZR204 – Microsoft Graph and SharePoint framework under steroids with Azure Functions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>“&lt;em>Modern development means client side first, backend second. However, there are still cases where you might need some backend processing, for long running operations, heavy computing consuming tasks or security concerns.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Ottawa 2017</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-09-07-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-09-07-08-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Ottawa.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll give a speech about the graph “Migrate your custom components to the SharePoint Framework ”. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how you can migrate your existing investments in SharePoint development (either full trust solutions or add-ins) to the new SharePoint framework. Migrating these components will not only help you make sure you stay ahead of the technology but will also improve users experience and help migrating to Office 365.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Brussels 2017</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-07-13-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-07-13-08-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Brussels.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll give a speech about the Azure functions and Microsoft flow “&lt;strong>Introduction to Azure Functions and Flow&lt;/strong>”.
Flow and Azure Functions are two new tools you now have for rapid applications development. It’s a revolution that changes the way of building and delivering modern applications. Instead of shipping a monolithic bloc, which can take up to a few months, we’ll now deliver each feature as a part of the solution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday New York City 2017</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-07-06-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-07-06-08-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS NYC.
I’ll give a speech about the SharePoint Framework and devops methodologies “Is it possible to do devops with the SharePoint framework?”.
You had it all right with solutions and add-ins. Your release pipeline was set up. Do new technologies and methodologies mean starting over?
Don’t panic I’m here to help! Together we’ll see how to set up a devops pipeline for SPFX developments with:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SharePoint Framework in my own words</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/sharepoint-framework-in-my-own/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/sharepoint-framework-in-my-own/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re following the SharePoint community, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard of the &amp;ldquo;SharePoint framework in his own words&amp;rdquo; video series. &lt;a href="https://www.voitanos.io/">https://www.voitanos.io/&lt;/a> is behind that initiative&lt;/p>
&lt;p>( &lt;a href="https://www.twitter.com/andrewconnell">@andrewconnell&lt;/a> founded voitanos recently)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The idea is to get the thoughts from the community and people who have been around the SharePoint development for a few years. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know that series I&amp;rsquo;d encourage you to check it out and I also hope that the product team behind the framework is listening the that super valuable feedback.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at Techorama Belgium 2017</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-techorama-belgium/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-techorama-belgium/</guid><description>&lt;p>Techorama is a 2-day event that takes place in Antwerp, Belgium from May 22nd to May 24th.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They lined up great speakers from Microsoft and other big industry players, checkout the agenda here &lt;a href="https://techorama.be/agenda/">https://techorama.be/agenda/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have the pleasure to announce I’ve been selected and I’ll be giving two sessions:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Set up your DevOps process for SharePoint/Office365&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Migrate your custom components to the SharePoint framework&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Tickets are still available so if you are in the area or can travel there I would strongly suggest you check-it out! &lt;a href="https://techorama.be/tickets/">https://techorama.be/tickets/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Calgary 2017</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-03-07-16-00-00/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-03-07-16-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Calgary.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll give a speech about the Azure functions and Microsoft flow “Introduction to Azure Functions and Flow”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Flow and Azure Functions are two new tools you now have for rapid applications development. It’s a revolution that changes the way of building and delivering modern applications. Instead of shipping a monolithic bloc, which can take up to a few months, we’ll now deliver each feature as a part of the solution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Ottawa 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-11-29-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-11-29-14-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Ottawa.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll give a speech about the graph “Making Graph data useful to your company”. We’ll talk about the Graph, delve, yammer, machine learning and a lot of other interesting concepts and the conversation will be aimed towards developers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re in the area Saturday December the 3rd 2016 don’t hesitate to register to the event.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Brussels 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-09-22-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-09-22-14-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year I have the privilege to speak at SPS Brussels&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll give a speech about “setting up your release pipeline for office 365/SharePoint”. (aka devops)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We’ll see together how you can leverage azure and visual studio team services to implement devops processes and increase quality and save time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re in the area on Oct the 15th don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions. This is a good occasion to expand your network, learn a lot of things and to spend a good day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Oslo 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-09-15-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-09-15-14-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year I have the privilege to speak at SPS Oslo&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll give a speech about “setting up your release pipeline for office 365/SharePoint”. (aka devops)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We’ll see together how you can leverage azure and visual studio team services to implement devops processes and increase quality and save time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re in the area on Oct the 22nd don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions. This is a good occasion to expand your network, learn a lot of things and to spend a good day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Detroit 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-09-09-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-09-09-14-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year I have the privilege to speak at SPS Detroit&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll give a speech about “setting up your release pipeline for office 365/SharePoint”. (aka devops)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We’ll see together how you can leverage azure and visual studio team services to implement devops processes and increase quality and save time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re in the area On Sept the 10th don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions. This is a good occasion to expand your network, learn a lot of things and to spend a good day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday New York City 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-07-30-09-28-00/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2016 09:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-07-30-09-28-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year I have the privilege to speak at SPS New York City.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll give a speech about “setting up your release pipeline for office 365/SharePoint”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We’ll see together how you can leverage azure and visual studio team services to implement devops processes and increase quality and save time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll also be giving Sebastien Levert&amp;rsquo;s session “deep dive in Microsoft graph” as he can&amp;rsquo;t make it to the event.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re in the area today (I know it&amp;rsquo;s short notice) don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions. This is a good occasion to expand your network, learn a lot of things and to spend a good day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Calgary 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-04-04-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-04-04-14-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year I have the privilege to speak at SPS Calgary (first time!!). I’ll give a speech about “Make Graph data useful for your company”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We’ll see how we can leverage the new Microsoft Graph API and Machine Learning tools to build “clever” applications for our business.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re in the area Saturday April the 23rd 2016 don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions. This is a good occasion to expand your network, learn a lot of things and to spend a good day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Houston 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-04-01-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-04-01-14-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year I have the privilege to speak at SPS Houston (first time!!). I’ll give a speech about “Setting up your release pipeline for SharePoint and Office 365 developments”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We’ll see how you can automate all the things to make your development team more productive and more efficient. For that we’ll see how to set up build and release definitions and how you can leverage both azure and on premises environments&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Montréal 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-03-30-15-36-54/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 15:36:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-03-30-15-36-54/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Montréal&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also had the occasion to help organize the event this year, it’s been an interesting experience so far and I’d like to thank Serge, Nico, Luc, Seb and Fabrice for their implication in that project, it’s much more work than what we think!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time I’ll talk about setting up your release pipeline for SharePoint/Office 365 developments in Visual Studio Online (Team Foundation Services). (In French)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at the SharePoint Saturday Ottawa 2014 !</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-sharepoint-sat-2014-10-08-23-40-00/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 23:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-sharepoint-sat-2014-10-08-23-40-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m proud to announce I’ll be speaking at the SharePoint Saturday Ottawa 2014. The event will be held close to Ottawa on November the 18th and you can get all the details here &lt;a href="https://www.spsevents.org/city/ottawa/ottawa2014">https://www.spsevents.org/city/ottawa/ottawa2014&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I will be presenting this session with Fabrice Vaxelaire (AKA Great Venerable) and we’ll be talking about building your business portal in Office 365: Nowadays we have business tools and portals everywhere in the company, what are the benefits of having everything at one place? How can we bring core business applications to Office 365? Etc…&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at the SharePoint Saturday New Hampshire 2014 !</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-sharepoint-sat-2014-10-01-23-34-03/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 23:34:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-sharepoint-sat-2014-10-01-23-34-03/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m proud to announce I’ll be speaking at the SharePoint Saturday New Hampshire 2014. The event will be held in Nashua on October the 18th and you can get all the details here &lt;a href="https://bit.ly/spsnh2014">https://bit.ly/spsnh2014&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I will be presenting this session with Fabrice Vaxelaire (AKA Great Venerable) and we’ll be talking about building your business portal in Office 365: Nowadays we have business tools and portals everywhere in the company, what are the benefits of having everything at one place? How can we bring core business applications to Office 365? Etc…&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>