<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 07:59:57 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Moving to a new location and celebrating a decade of blogging</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/new-blog-location/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/new-blog-location/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="welcome-to-my-new-blog">Welcome to my new blog!&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Welcome to my new blog on github.io, powered by open source. I&amp;rsquo;ll be shutting down the old one so make sure you update your RSS subscriptions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="10-years-of-blogging">10 years of blogging&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Can you believe it? I&amp;rsquo;ve been blogging for 10 years now! At the time I was almost a Microsoft Student Partner and my first blog post (in French) was about &lt;a href="https://baywet.github.io/fr/le-cloud-computing-oui-mais-p/">cloud computing&lt;/a> (which was a new thing back then).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Old English posts migrated to this blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/old-english-posts-migrated-to/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/old-english-posts-migrated-to/</guid><description>&lt;p>Everything is in the title. My French blog has been running for more than six years now (gee, I’m getting old).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From 2013 to 2014, before I decided to open an English dedicated blog, I was posting every blog entry in English and in French.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over time it got messy for both communities so I decided to open this blog. But I couldn’t move the old content to this new blog without having to spend hours doing so.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The former MSP becomes MVP</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/the-former-msp-becomes-mvp/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2014 01:37:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/the-former-msp-becomes-mvp/</guid><description>&lt;p>SharePoint MVP&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://baywet.github.io/the-former-msp-becomes-mvp/clip_5F00_image002_5F00_thumb_5F00_2DFB8F5C.png" alt="clip_5F00_image002_5F00_thumb_5F00_2DFB8F5C.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>You may already have heard about it on social network, I’m a SharePoint Server MVP since April the 1st.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m really proud to be a part of this awesome community counting Microsoft technologies best professionals and great communities’ contributors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This incoming year will be full of events, community activities and projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I would like to thank:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Jean-Sébastien DUCHENE&lt;/strong>: Enterprise Client Management French MVP for his advises and for encouraging me to become an MVP (I thought I was not good enough to make it).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>