<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ci on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/ci/</link><description>Recent content in ci on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</managingEditor><webMaster>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/ci/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>GitHub Actions: Automatic conflicting pull request tagging and comment</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/pull-request-conflict-github-workflow/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/pull-request-conflict-github-workflow/</guid><description>Open-source repositories enable tremendous productivity in software development. Growth in user base usually translates in growth in contributors, which in turns translates in a better solution bringing more users and so on&amp;hellip; Maintaining large open-source repositories can be time-consuming as you spend more and more time reviewing contributions. Don&amp;rsquo;t take me wrong, that time spent reviewing pull requests is mostly well spent as it represents a factor of scale efficiency gain: for minutes spent reviewing any given pull request, the codebase benefits hours of development efforts invested by the contributor.</description></item><item><title>Automatically increment SharePoint feature version number during build with build 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/automatically-increment-sharep/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/automatically-increment-sharep/</guid><description>A few months ago Microsoft released a new automated build system with visual studio online /tfs 2015.
This new mechanism is way more open than previous XAML builds, tasks based and easier to customize.
One of the available tasks allows you to run a powershell script.
Let’s say that for one reason you want to increment automatically the version number of your SharePoint features when building.
If you have a quick look at the “.</description></item></channel></rss>