<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ottawa on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/ottawa/</link><description>Recent content in Ottawa on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 20:13:02 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/ottawa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Speaking at Microsoft 365 Saturday Ottawa 2020</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sps-ottawa-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sps-ottawa-2020/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the Microsoft 365 (formerly SPS) Ottawa and I&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction To The Microsoft Graph: Getting Started Quickly &amp;amp; Getting The Most Out Of It&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together we will cover the basics of Microsoft Graph, the Microsoft Identity Platform, the value it provides to developers and how to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of the ongoing pandemic, the event will be digital only and held on Microsoft Teams. This means you can attend the event for free from anywhere in the world! The organizing team had been putting a lot of efforts into making sure attendees get the most of this digital format.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Ottawa 2019</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2019-10-01-14-12-00/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 14:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2019-10-01-14-12-00/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Ottawa and I&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction To The Microsoft Graph: Getting Started Quickly &amp;amp; Getting The Most Out Of It&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together we will cover the basics of the Microsoft Graph, the Microsoft Identity Platform, the value it provides to developers and how to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re in the area &lt;strong&gt;Saturday October the 5th 2019&lt;/strong&gt; don’t hesitate to register to the event.
Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Ottawa 2018</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-10-10-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-10-10-08-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Ottawa. It has become a regular event for me. This SPS is really dear to me because not only I get to see a lot of Canadian MVPs friends but it also was the first event ever I was presenting in (a broken) English a long time ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year I&amp;rsquo;ll present &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;The Microsoft Graph and SharePoint Framework under steroids with Azure functions&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; or how these three technologies really represent a &lt;strong&gt;power trio to build customizations in Office 365&lt;/strong&gt;. Together we&amp;rsquo;ll see how to leverage the&lt;strong&gt;Graph to access your company&amp;rsquo;s data, how to leverage the SharePoint Framework to access the Graph&lt;/strong&gt; and build user centric applications as well as how to leverage Microsoft Graph connected &lt;strong&gt;Azure Functions via the SharePoint Framework to implement your line of business logic&lt;/strong&gt; with backend processing capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Ottawa 2017</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-09-07-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-09-07-08-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Ottawa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll give a speech about the graph “Migrate your custom components to the SharePoint Framework ”. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how you can migrate your existing investments in SharePoint development (either full trust solutions or add-ins) to the new SharePoint framework. Migrating these components will not only help you make sure you stay ahead of the technology but will also improve users experience and help migrating to Office 365.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Speaking at Aos Tours Ottawa and Toronto</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-aos-tours-ottawa-a/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2017 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-aos-tours-ottawa-a/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I’ll have the privilege to speak at next AOS (Azure, Office 365, SharePoint) in Ottawa (8th) and Toronto (10th).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll present in English: &lt;strong&gt;Introduction to Azure Functions and Flow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flow and Azure Functions are two new tools you now have for rapid applications development. It’s a revolution that changes the way of building and delivering modern applications. Instead of shipping a monolithic bloc, which can take up to a few months, we’ll now deliver each feature as a part of the solution.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Ottawa 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-11-29-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-11-29-14-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Ottawa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll give a speech about the graph “Making Graph data useful to your company”. We’ll talk about the Graph, delve, yammer, machine learning and a lot of other interesting concepts and the conversation will be aimed towards developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re in the area Saturday December the 3rd 2016 don’t hesitate to register to the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Ottawa 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-11-10-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-11-10-14-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Ottawa. I’ll give a speech about the ALM capabilities for SharePoint/Office365 in Azure “Setting up your release pipeline for SharePoint in Azure”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re in the area Saturday November the 21st 2015 don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions. This is a good occasion to expand your network, learn a lot of things and to spend a good day.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Speaking at the SharePoint Saturday Ottawa 2014 !</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-sharepoint-sat-2014-10-08-23-40-00/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 23:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-the-sharepoint-sat-2014-10-08-23-40-00/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I’m proud to announce I’ll be speaking at the SharePoint Saturday Ottawa 2014. The event will be held close to Ottawa on November the 18th and you can get all the details here &lt;a href="https://www.spsevents.org/city/ottawa/ottawa2014"&gt;https://www.spsevents.org/city/ottawa/ottawa2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be presenting this session with Fabrice Vaxelaire (AKA Great Venerable) and we’ll be talking about building your business portal in Office 365: Nowadays we have business tools and portals everywhere in the company, what are the benefits of having everything at one place? How can we bring core business applications to Office 365? Etc…&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Speaker at SharePoint Saturday Ottawa!</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaker-at-sharepoint-saturday/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2013 03:20:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaker-at-sharepoint-saturday/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://kyubung13.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/ottawacanada336122803554032601.jpeg" alt="parliament hill in winter"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi everybody, I’m thrilled to announce that I’ll be speaking at SharePoint Saturday Ottawa. On Nov the 23rd!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My session: translating SharePoint 2013 from beginning to ending. We’ll cover all multilingualism provided by SharePoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With lot of examples and demonstrations we’ll see what are the tools provided to IT pro’s, power users and developers. The goal of this session is to give you some insight about how to get your SharePoint environment in multiple languages seamlessly.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>