<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dotnet on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/dotnet/</link><description>Recent content in Dotnet on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</managingEditor><webMaster>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 15:51:13 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/dotnet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Installing the dotnet SDK on Ubuntu under WSL</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/installing-dotnet-sdk-wsl-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/installing-dotnet-sdk-wsl-ubuntu/</guid><description>Introduction Over the past few months I found myself struggling to get a working installation of the dotnet SDK on Ubuntu running off Windows Subsystems for Linux (WSL). This is partly due to the fact new installation methods have been added over the years, others have been deprecated, and it&amp;rsquo;s really easy to inadvertently update from one installation method to another, messing up everything by the same occasion.
The documentation overview on the topic currently suggests the following methods:</description></item><item><title>Determine your technical debt using SonarQube - Adding modules</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-22-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/determine-your-technical-debt-2017-09-22-08-00-00/</guid><description>TL; DR Static analysis works by leveraging rules. These rules are grouped by language or language categories in modules that you can install. In addition to providing support for the subsequent languages, these modules can extend the native capabilities of SonarQube.
Most of them are free, some are subject to commercial licenses.
Installing Add-ons Open SonarQube and go to configuration, system, search for and install the modules that you&amp;rsquo;re interested in.</description></item></channel></rss>