<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sharepoint Framework on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/sharepoint-framework/</link><description>Recent content in Sharepoint Framework on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 20:13:02 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/sharepoint-framework/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Recording available PnP Call December 5th - Office 365 CLI externalize</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/recording-available-pnp-call-d/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 10:56:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/recording-available-pnp-call-d/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I was invited to demonstrate the new Office 365 CLI externalize command during on the of recent PnP calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can watch the full call &lt;a href="https://developer.microsoft.com/en-us/office/blogs/sharepoint-framework-community-call-recording-5th-of-december-2019/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a reminder this new command allows you to scan a SPFx project and get the external configuration automatically.
Doing this reduces greatly the size of your solutions, improving performances for end users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can watch the command in action below and read the documentation &lt;a href="https://pnp.github.io/office365-cli/cmd/spfx/project/project-externalize/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Fest DC 2019</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-fest-dc-2019-04-18-07-35-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 07:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-fest-dc-2019-04-18-07-35-00/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SharePoint Fest Washington DC 2018 is happening from April 29th to May the 3rd&lt;/strong&gt;. This event will feature 2 days pre-conference workshops and 3 days of conference. &lt;a href="https://www.sharepointfest.com/DC/"&gt;You can find more information about it on the website&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting three sessions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DEV104 - Migrate your custom components to the SharePoint Framework&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Migrate your custom components to the SharePoint Framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s the 3rd model Microsoft has come with to customize SharePoint in less than 5 years. You may still have add-ins/apps or even solutions running in production and you’re asking yourself what to do about all that?
Do you have to start all over again? And for how long that new model will last?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Houston 2019</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2019-04-02-02-00-00/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2019-04-02-02-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It is the second time in a few years I have the ooportunity to speak at the SharePoint Saturday Houston.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll give a speech about &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Automating Provisioning For Your Digital Workplace: With Azure Durable Functions &amp;amp; Microsoft Graph&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together we will see how you can improve your provisioning workflows and automate most of it leveraging&lt;strong&gt;Azure Durable Functions and the Microsoft Graph&lt;/strong&gt;. This session is geared mostly towards developers but also for IT pros and deciders that want to gain insights on how to combine business processes and provisioning.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>SharePoint Framework 1.8.0 and unit testing: bad Karma</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/sharepoint-framework-180-and-u/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/sharepoint-framework-180-and-u/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Sorry, I had to make the pun…. When the SharePoint Framework originally shipped, the tooling included &lt;a href="https://github.com/karma-runner/karma"&gt;KarmaJS&lt;/a&gt;to write unit tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KarmaJS received a lot of complaints about performance, capabilities, modern JavaScript support… This especially if you use is in combination with &lt;a href="https://github.com/ariya/phantomjs"&gt;PhantomJS&lt;/a&gt;, a headless web browser project that has been abandoned a long time ago now which also shipped with SPFx.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While some people&lt;a href="https://github.com/SharePoint/sp-dev-docs/issues/736"&gt;have been arguing for a choice in unit testing framework with SPFx&lt;/a&gt; like we (almost) have choice in web frameworks, we saw little movement on that front over the last years.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>SharePoint Framework and DevOps Practices: New Documentation, New Samples</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/sharepoint-framework-and-devop/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/sharepoint-framework-and-devop/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="tl-dr"&gt;TL; DR;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the release of Azure DevOps, there’s some &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/sharepoint/dev/spfx/toolchain/implement-ci-cd-with-azure-devops"&gt;new SPFX documentation&lt;/a&gt; to set up your CI/CD pipeline in Azure DevOps.  Have a look and share your thoughts.  Your feedback is always welcome! The Patterns and Practices Initiative also includes a newly reorganized DevOps repository for tools and samples around &lt;a href="https://github.com/SharePoint/sp-dev-build-extensions"&gt;SharePoint Framework Build and Deploy Practices&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-long-story"&gt;The long story&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="my-journey-into-the-sharepoint-devops-world"&gt;My journey into the SharePoint DevOps world&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been working around Application Lifecycle Management (ALM), Continuous Integration (CI), Continuous Deployment (CD) and DevOps practices in the SharePoint/Azure/Office 365 ecosystem for several years.  In my experience, whether you’re working alone or as part of a team, adopting proper ALM practices is crucial if you want to produce high quality code.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Presenting at the Microsoft Ignite Tour Toronto</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/presenting-at-the-microsoft-ig/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/presenting-at-the-microsoft-ig/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The Microsoft Ignite tour is a series of events that take place in cities around the world. This series of events is organized by Microsoft and presenters are picked among Microsoft Employees, Regional Directors and MVPs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll have the opportunity to present one session “&lt;strong&gt;How to do DevOps with the SharePoint Framework and why it matters?&lt;/strong&gt;”. During this session we will explore together how you can setup your continuous integration and continuous deployment pipeline leveraging Azure DevOps (formerly Visual Studio Team Services).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Speaking at Granite State SharePoint Users Group</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-granite-state-shar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-granite-state-shar/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;On January the 3rd I’ve been invited to speak (virtually) at the Granite State SharePoint Users group. I’ll be presenting the session “&lt;strong&gt;The Microsoft Graph and the SharePoint Framework on steroids with Azure Functions&lt;/strong&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This session will demonstrate how you can tap into a wealth of data and insights from the Microsoft Graph, interact with the user using the SharePoint Framework and extend components with complex line of business logic leveraging serverless Azure Functions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Toronto 2018</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-11-20-09-00-00/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-11-20-09-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Toronto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll give a speech about “&lt;strong&gt;Migrate your custom components to the SharePoint Framework&lt;/strong&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together we will see how you can transition from &lt;strong&gt;either the server-side object model or the add-ins development fashions to the modern SharePoint Framework approach&lt;/strong&gt;. This session is mostly meant for developers and technical architects who are curious about getting started on the new model and that might have legacy applications.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Ottawa 2018</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-10-10-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2018-10-10-08-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Ottawa. It has become a regular event for me. This SPS is really dear to me because not only I get to see a lot of Canadian MVPs friends but it also was the first event ever I was presenting in (a broken) English a long time ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year I&amp;rsquo;ll present &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;The Microsoft Graph and SharePoint Framework under steroids with Azure functions&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; or how these three technologies really represent a &lt;strong&gt;power trio to build customizations in Office 365&lt;/strong&gt;. Together we&amp;rsquo;ll see how to leverage the&lt;strong&gt;Graph to access your company&amp;rsquo;s data, how to leverage the SharePoint Framework to access the Graph&lt;/strong&gt; and build user centric applications as well as how to leverage Microsoft Graph connected &lt;strong&gt;Azure Functions via the SharePoint Framework to implement your line of business logic&lt;/strong&gt; with backend processing capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>New SharePoint Framework PnP Samples available: using the Skype UCWA Web SDK to subscribe to people’s status</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/new-sharepoint-framework-pnp-s/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/new-sharepoint-framework-pnp-s/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="tldr"&gt;TL;DR;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I added two new SharePoint framework WebParts PnP sample to demonstrate how to use the Unified Communications Web API JavaScript SDK from Skype for business. This SDK allows you to do things like subscribe to a person status, start instant messaging conversations, calls…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://baywet.github.io/new-sharepoint-framework-pnp-s/16.gif" alt="16.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get a look:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href="https://github.com/SharePoint/sp-dev-fx-webparts/tree/master/samples/js-skype-status"&gt;plain JS sample&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href="https://github.com/SharePoint/sp-dev-fx-webparts/tree/master/samples/react-skype-status"&gt;reactJS + Office UI Fabric React sample&lt;/a&gt;(persona card)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="long-version"&gt;Long version&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently had the occasion to make my first contribution to PnP (besides creating issues and helping investigate those). In these two new samples I show you how to you how to leverage the Skype UCWA SDK to subscribe and display people skype status.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Full version of lodash now available in the SharePoint Framework</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/full-version-of-lodash-now-ava/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/full-version-of-lodash-now-ava/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="tl-dr"&gt;TL; DR;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft replaced @types/es6-collections by the es2015.collection library in version &lt;a href="https://github.com/SharePoint/sp-dev-docs/wiki/Release-Notes-for-SPFx-Package-Version-1.4"&gt;1.4.0&lt;/a&gt; of the packages. Those had a conflicting definition of weakmap which caused issues with packages like &lt;a href="https://lodash.com/"&gt;lodash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="long-version"&gt;Long version&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft recently release v1.4.0 of the SharePoint Framwork and it’s packages. It contains a lot of improvements and one of those probably went unnoticed by many of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;@types/es6-collections has been replaced by es2015.collection library (native, comes with the compiler/JS Engines). That package had a “special” definition of WeakMap (among other things) which was causing numerous packages not to work properly, include one of my favorites: lodash.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Ottawa 2017</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-09-07-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-09-07-08-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Ottawa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll give a speech about the graph “Migrate your custom components to the SharePoint Framework ”. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how you can migrate your existing investments in SharePoint development (either full trust solutions or add-ins) to the new SharePoint framework. Migrating these components will not only help you make sure you stay ahead of the technology but will also improve users experience and help migrating to Office 365.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday New York City 2017</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-07-06-08-00-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-07-06-08-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS NYC.
I’ll give a speech about the SharePoint Framework and devops methodologies “Is it possible to do devops with the SharePoint framework?”.
You had it all right with solutions and add-ins. Your release pipeline was set up. Do new technologies and methodologies mean starting over?
Don’t panic I’m here to help! Together we’ll see how to set up a devops pipeline for SPFX developments with:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>SharePoint Framework in my own words</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/sharepoint-framework-in-my-own/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/sharepoint-framework-in-my-own/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re following the SharePoint community, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard of the &amp;ldquo;SharePoint framework in his own words&amp;rdquo; video series. &lt;a href="https://www.voitanos.io/"&gt;https://www.voitanos.io/&lt;/a&gt; is behind that initiative&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;( &lt;a href="https://www.twitter.com/andrewconnell"&gt;@andrewconnell&lt;/a&gt; founded voitanos recently)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is to get the thoughts from the community and people who have been around the SharePoint development for a few years. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know that series I&amp;rsquo;d encourage you to check it out and I also hope that the product team behind the framework is listening the that super valuable feedback.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Update to _spPageContextInfo type definitions - new properties available</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/update-to-sppagecontextinfo-ty/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 07:07:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/update-to-sppagecontextinfo-ty/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re building modern SharePoint components (Framework or not), there&amp;rsquo;s a high chance you&amp;rsquo;re using TypeScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that case you&amp;rsquo;re probably using @types/SharePoint to provide auto-completion as well as some level of understanding for the compiler of what&amp;rsquo;s going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s one object in particular that SharePoint hydrates for us to give some understanding of where the user is and what he/she is doing: _spPageContextInfo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of properties were missing in those type definitions, old stuff like the web Id but also new things coming from SharePoint Online like canUserCreateMicrosoftForm.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Speaking at Techorama Belgium 2017</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-techorama-belgium/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-techorama-belgium/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Techorama is a 2-day event that takes place in Antwerp, Belgium from May 22nd to May 24th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They lined up great speakers from Microsoft and other big industry players, checkout the agenda here &lt;a href="https://techorama.be/agenda/"&gt;https://techorama.be/agenda/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have the pleasure to announce I’ve been selected and I’ll be giving two sessions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Set up your DevOps process for SharePoint/Office365&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Migrate your custom components to the SharePoint framework&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets are still available so if you are in the area or can travel there I would strongly suggest you check-it out! &lt;a href="https://techorama.be/tickets/"&gt;https://techorama.be/tickets/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Vancouver 2017</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-03-09-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2017-03-09-14-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Vancouver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll give a speech about the SharePoint Framework and devops methodologies “Is it possible to do devops with the SharePoint framework?”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You had it all right with solutions and add-ins. Your release pipeline was set up. Do new technologies and methodologies mean starting over?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t panic I’m here to help! Together we’ll see how to set up a devops pipeline for SPFX developments with:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>