<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mvp on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/mvp/</link><description>Recent content in Mvp on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 20:13:02 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/mvp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Not Office Servers and Services MVP anymore, becoming Office development MVP</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/not-office-servers-and-service/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/not-office-servers-and-service/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="6jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://baywet.github.io/not-office-servers-and-service/6.jpg" alt="6.jpg"&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id="renewed-as-mvp-and-changed-category"&gt;Renewed as MVP and changed category&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I have the pleasure to announce I’ve been renewed as a Microsoft MVP&lt;/strong&gt;, for the fifth year in a row (time flies, I’m getting old). A slight change this time, &lt;strong&gt;my award is Office development&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years I’ve been a SharePoint MVP, an Office Servers and Services MVP and now an Office development MVP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally Microsoft had it’s MVPs organized by products, which made a lot of sense in a on premises world which required a deep knowledge in something very specific. Also, it allowed MVP’s to be connected directly with the teams at Microsoft on their product. However, &lt;strong&gt;over the last decade the industry transitioned to a cloud first model and somebody who was working with SharePoint&lt;/strong&gt; (or Exchange, Skype…) &lt;strong&gt;is most likely to be working with Office 365 at large&lt;/strong&gt; (and some Azure as well). A couple of years ago (3?) Microsoft decided to reorganize the MVP program to have award categories (Azure, Office servers and services, Visual Studio and Team Services…) which regroup contribution areas (e.g. OSS: SharePoint, Exchange, Office 365, …)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Re-awarded Microsoft MVP for year 2017 2018</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/re-awarded-microsoft-mvp-for-y/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/re-awarded-microsoft-mvp-for-y/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;You may not know it but Microsoft has changed the organization of the MVP program during these last few years.
They used to nominate new MVP’s every 3 months and renew people every year on anniversary date.
One of the changes the brought to the program is around the renew and nomination cycles. New MVP’s are awarded every month and existing ones are renewed all together every year in July.
I used to be an “April MVP” and I was used to blogging about my renewal in April.
I’m pleased to announce I’ve been renewed MVP for year 2017-2018 on the Office Servers and Services category.
Let’s go for another year :)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Renewed as MVP for 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/renewed-as-mvp-for-2016/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/renewed-as-mvp-for-2016/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Hi,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those of you who do not follow me on social media and don’t know it yet, I honored to announce I’ve be renewed as a Microsoft MVP for year 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to recent modifications in the program, I’m transitioning to &lt;strong&gt;Office Servers and Services&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m really excited by this upcoming year of coding, sharing, conferences and meeting people!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you soon&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>MVP Virtual Conference</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/mvp-virtual-conference/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 22:34:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/mvp-virtual-conference/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;American (US, Canada, Latin…) Microsoft MVP’s are organizing a two days free online conference on May the 14th and the 15th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to know which sessions will be available you can click here&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://mvp.microsoft.com/en-us/virtualconference-agenda.aspx"&gt;https://mvp.microsoft.com/en-us/virtualconference-agenda.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To register to the event &lt;a href="https://mvp.microsoft.com/en-us/virtualconference-sessions.aspx"&gt;https://mvp.microsoft.com/en-us/virtualconference-sessions.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll be the moderator for Sébastien Levert’s session “introduction to AngularJS applications in Office 365”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a great opportunity to connect with experts from all around the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Presenting at the MVP Showcase 2014</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/presenting-at-the-mvp-showcase/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2014 03:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/presenting-at-the-mvp-showcase/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As some of you know, this is my first year as an MVP. Next week will be the MVP summit and I’m very exited about it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those whom don’t know it, Microsoft is actually bringing 1800+ persons from all around the world to their headquarters so they can share information with them and gather feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a huge week coming up, well I can’t really say anything more about it, pretty much everything is under NDA.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The former MSP becomes MVP</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/the-former-msp-becomes-mvp/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2014 01:37:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/the-former-msp-becomes-mvp/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;SharePoint MVP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://baywet.github.io/the-former-msp-becomes-mvp/clip_5F00_image002_5F00_thumb_5F00_2DFB8F5C.png" alt="clip_5F00_image002_5F00_thumb_5F00_2DFB8F5C.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You may already have heard about it on social network, I’m a SharePoint Server MVP since April the 1st.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m really proud to be a part of this awesome community counting Microsoft technologies best professionals and great communities’ contributors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This incoming year will be full of events, community activities and projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to thank:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jean-Sébastien DUCHENE&lt;/strong&gt;: Enterprise Client Management French MVP for his advises and for encouraging me to become an MVP (I thought I was not good enough to make it).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>