<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Open-Source on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/open-source/</link><description>Recent content in Open-Source on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 07:59:57 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Celebrating 5 years at Microsoft and new role</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/5-years-and-new-role/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/5-years-and-new-role/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="celebrations">Celebrations&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Back in January, I celebrated 5 years at Microsoft! It’s incredible how fast time can fly. I initially started working as a program manager II on Microsoft Graph Change Notifications (aka webhooks) and Change Tracking (aka delta queries). A transfer and a few promotions later I’m now a Principal Software Developer, working on Microsoft Graph client experiences (SDKs, kiota, copilot extensibility, OpenAPI…)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://baywet.github.io/5-years-and-new-role/5years-totem.jpg" alt="picture of the Microsoft 5 years chrystal totem">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shipping a product at Microsoft: Kiota</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/shipping-kiota-microsoft/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/shipping-kiota-microsoft/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We recently &lt;a href="https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/tailored-sdk-experiences-via-kiota-now-generally-available/">announced the general availability of Kiota&lt;/a>, an open source client generator for REST APIs with an OpenAPI description. I am the co-founder of this product, and this launch matches my 3 years anniversary at Microsoft, so I thought I would take the time to write about my experience of taking a product from idea to v1 at Microsoft.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Throughout my career, I have been involved with multiple “products”: a second-hand marketplace for industrial hardware, an enterprise social network solution, a localization and translation solution for SharePoint, and an IoT based temperature management optimization solution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>One year as a Software Developer at Microsoft</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/one-year-developer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/one-year-developer/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="one-year-as-a-software-developer-at-microsoft">One year as a Software Developer at Microsoft&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Back in September 2020, I published a &lt;a href="https://baywet.github.io/pm-experience-dev-sdk/">blog post about my experience as a Program Manager at Microsoft that was well received&lt;/a>. It made me realize that the community was curious and interested about this role. In this post, I will share my insights as a developer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before we begin, &lt;strong>keep in mind this is my personal experience&lt;/strong>, which may differ a lot from team to team, product to product and depend on other circumstances (being remote, culture, etc…).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Revamping the Microsoft Graph Java SDK: a recipe to revive open-source repositories</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/github-repo-revival/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/github-repo-revival/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Back in August 2020 I became the main maintainer of the &lt;a href="https://github.com/microsoftgraph/msgraph-sdk-java">Microsoft Graph Java SDK&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The team had to deprioritize this SDK in favor of other languages due to a lack of staff. About 100+ issues were open, as well as 15 pull requests from the community. Dependencies and tooling had not been updated, the Android story was unclear, no innovation had been done in a long time, the repository felt abandoned and caused a lot of frustrations…&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>