<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>OpenAPI on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/openapi/</link><description>Recent content in OpenAPI on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</managingEditor><webMaster>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 12:20:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/openapi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Speaking at CollabDays Belgium 2022</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-collabdays-belgium-2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 12:20:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-collabdays-belgium-2022/</guid><description>I’m honoured to announce that I’ve been selected to speak at the CollabDays Belgium 2022 (formerly SPS Events, aka SharePoint Saturday) happening in Brussels Saturday 15th of October. This event is dear to my heart as it’s one of the first international events I ever got to speak at, it always attracts a great crowd and brings together internationally regarded speakers.
I’ll be presenting “Turbocharge your API integration with Microsoft Kiota” where I’ll be introducing through lots of demonstrations how you can generate a client generated for any OpenAPI described API using Microsoft Kiota and other tools.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at the API specification conference 2022</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-api-specification-conf-2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 12:20:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-api-specification-conf-2022/</guid><description>I’m extremely pleased to announce I’ll be speaking at the API specification conference 2022 in San Francisco, Sept 19-21st. During “Lessons learned from client generation, gaps and suggestions to address them”, we’ll be reviewing my 2 years experience building an OpenAPI based client generator and trying to identify solutions to ease up code generation, leading to better clients.
The API specification conference is the first in person event I’ll be presenting at in almost 3 years, I’m really excited and a bit nervous (do I even remember how to do this anymore?</description></item></channel></rss>