<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Metadata on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/metadata/</link><description>Recent content in Metadata on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 07:59:57 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/metadata/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Vancouver 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-02-10-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-02-10-14-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year I have the privilege to speak at SPS Vancouver (first time!!). I’ll give a speech about the importance of metadata in your company (therefore in SharePoint/Office 365)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re in the area Saturday March the 12th 2016 don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions. This is a good occasion to expand your network, learn a lot of things and to spend a good day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday New York City 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-05-25-01-11-00/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 01:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-05-25-01-11-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS NYC&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.spsevents.org/city/nyc/nyc2015">https://www.spsevents.org/city/nyc/nyc2015&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My session will be about the importance of metadata in your company.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We’ll start by some reminders around the theory and describe what are the advantages and disadvantages of different types of each. Then we’ll see what’s currently supported by SharePoint and what are the available tools. Finally we’ll talk about why it is so important that you set this up in your companies, how it can improve findability of content and how it will help you to move to the Graph.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Montréal 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-05-21-00-50-33/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:50:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-05-21-00-50-33/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS Montréal&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://baywet.github.io/../montreal-sharepoint-saturday-2">/montreal-sharepoint-saturday-2&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also had the occasion to help organize the event this year, it’s been an interesting experience so far and I’d like to thank Serge, Nico, Luc, Philippe, Seb, Fabrice and Alain for their implication in that project, it’s much more work than what we think!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My session will be about the importance of metadata in your company. (In French)&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>