<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Apps on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/apps/</link><description>Recent content in Apps on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 11:06:28 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/apps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SystemUpdate method available in CSOM at last!!!</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/systemupdate-method-available/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/systemupdate-method-available/</guid><description>&lt;p>That’s good news for SharePoint developers, the SystemUpdate method is finally available in Client Side Object Model.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Indeed, Microsoft has recently released an update for nugget packages and the method is part of the new stuff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://dev.office.com/blogs/new-sharepoint-csom-version-released-for-Office-365-august-2016-updated">https://dev.office.com/blogs/new-sharepoint-csom-version-released-for-Office-365-august-2016-updated&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s an important method because it allows you to update a list item without changing modification date, author, publishing and versioning information.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moreover, we’re numerous SharePoint developers migrating a lot of full trust solutions to SharePoint Add-ins, some of which were using this method and in some cases we have only an app-only context. Usage of this method instead of the regular update method will avoid having documents last updated by “SharePoint App”.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>unable to find version '3.1.2' of package 'appforsharepointonlinewebtoolkit'</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/unable-to-find-version-312-of/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/unable-to-find-version-312-of/</guid><description>&lt;p>With office development tools for visual studio 2015 (and probably with august 2015 update for vs 2013 too, but I haven’t tried it), you may run into the following error:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>unable to find version &amp;lsquo;3.1.2&amp;rsquo; of package &amp;lsquo;appforsharepointonlinewebtoolkit&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And so while doing an “update-package” in nuget console or if you have a restore packages step in your build process. (mandatory if like me you don’t include the packages folder into source control).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SharePoint apps (add-ins) JavaScript disappeared</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/sharepoint-apps-add-ins-javasc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 04:09:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/sharepoint-apps-add-ins-javasc/</guid><description>&lt;p>At Negotium we recently came across a weird problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let’s assume you previously built a Provider hosted app for SharePoint.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now let’s assume you updated to the latest version of the SDK (April/May update)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally let’s assume your tenant has been updated recently (v16.0.4121.1212 or above)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s likely that you are loading SP.*.js files and MicrosoftAjax.js the way it used to be recommended by Microsoft per say: &amp;lt;HostWebUrl&amp;gt;/_layouts/15/jsfile.js or &amp;lt;AppWebUrl&amp;gt;/_layouts/15/jsfile.js.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>