<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>New York on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/new-york/</link><description>Recent content in New York on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</managingEditor><webMaster>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 10:13:42 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/new-york/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday New York City 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-07-30-09-28-00/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2016 09:28:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-07-30-09-28-00/</guid><description>This year I have the privilege to speak at SPS New York City.
I’ll give a speech about “setting up your release pipeline for office 365/SharePoint”.
We’ll see together how you can leverage azure and visual studio team services to implement devops processes and increase quality and save time.
I&amp;rsquo;ll also be giving Sebastien Levert&amp;rsquo;s session “deep dive in Microsoft graph” as he can&amp;rsquo;t make it to the event.
If you’re in the area today (I know it&amp;rsquo;s short notice) don’t hesitate to register to the event.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday New York City 2015</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-05-25-01-11-00/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 01:11:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2015-05-25-01-11-00/</guid><description>This year again I have the opportunity to speak at the SPS NYC
https://www.spsevents.org/city/nyc/nyc2015
My session will be about the importance of metadata in your company.
We’ll start by some reminders around the theory and describe what are the advantages and disadvantages of different types of each. Then we’ll see what’s currently supported by SharePoint and what are the available tools. Finally we’ll talk about why it is so important that you set this up in your companies, how it can improve findability of content and how it will help you to move to the Graph.</description></item><item><title>Selected for SharePoint Saturday New York City</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/selected-for-sharepoint-saturd/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2014 03:43:34 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/selected-for-sharepoint-saturd/</guid><description>Hi Everybody!
I’m pleased to announce you that I’ll be speaking at SharePoint Saturday New York City.
The event is free and will occur at Microsoft New York City’s office, on time square.
Check it out, is a very good opportunity to learn plenty of things if you can be there.
https://www.spsevents.org/city/NYC/NYC2014/sessions
See you soon!</description></item></channel></rss>