<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Washington on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/washington/</link><description>Recent content in Washington on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 07:59:57 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/washington/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Fest DC 2019</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-fest-dc-2019-04-18-07-35-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 07:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-fest-dc-2019-04-18-07-35-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>SharePoint Fest Washington DC 2018 is happening from April 29th to May the 3rd&lt;/strong>. This event will feature 2 days pre-conference workshops and 3 days of conference. &lt;a href="https://www.sharepointfest.com/DC/">You can find more information about it on the website&lt;/a>. I&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting three sessions:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DEV104 - Migrate your custom components to the SharePoint Framework&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Migrate your custom components to the SharePoint Framework.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s the 3rd model Microsoft has come with to customize SharePoint in less than 5 years. You may still have add-ins/apps or even solutions running in production and you’re asking yourself what to do about all that?
Do you have to start all over again? And for how long that new model will last?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Fest DC (Washington) 2018</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-fest-dc-2018-01-05-09-00-00/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-fest-dc-2018-01-05-09-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>SharePoint Fest DC (Washington) 2018 is happening from March 26th to March 30th&lt;/strong>. This event will feature 2 days pre-conference workshops and 3 days of conference. &lt;a href="https://www.sharepointfest.com/DC/">You can find more information about it on the website&lt;/a>. I’ve been selected amongst 44 other speakers to present this year two sessions:&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="azr204--microsoft-graph-and-sharepoint-framework-under-steroids-with-azure-functions">AZR204 – Microsoft Graph and SharePoint framework under steroids with Azure Functions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>“&lt;em>Modern development means client side first, backend second. However, there are still cases where you might need some backend processing, for long running operations, heavy computing consuming tasks or security concerns.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>