<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>powershell on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/powershell/</link><description>Recent content in powershell on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</managingEditor><webMaster>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 06:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/powershell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using PnP PowerShell on Visual Studio Team Services (VSTS) Hosted Agent</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/using-pnp-powershell-on-visual/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/using-pnp-powershell-on-visual/</guid><description>Visual Studio Team Services (VSTS) provides great Continuous Integration (CI) and Continuous Deployment (CD) functionalities you can leverage to implement DevOps pipelines and automation with your custom developments.
If your custom solutions rely on PnP PowerShell during their build and/or deployment processes, you will need PnP PowerShell to be installed on the agent. Unfortunately the Hosted Agents do not have PnP PowerShell installed by default. Note: that documentation only applies to the Hosted and Hosted 2017 agents, the Linux Hosted Agent is not supported at the moment</description></item><item><title>Customizing page layouts, master pages and image renditions in SharePoint Online</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/customizing-page-layouts-maste/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/customizing-page-layouts-maste/</guid><description>Microsoft recently made changes around look and feel customizations for SharePoint Online.
If you create a new site collection and try to edit page layouts, master pages or even image renditions, there’s a high chance you’ll get an access denied error message. That even if you’re site collection administrator.
Investigating further and checking your permissions on the master page gallery library, you will notice that every and each user has a “deny” permission for “Add and Customize Pages”.</description></item></channel></rss>