<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Microsoft on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/microsoft/</link><description>Recent content in Microsoft on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</managingEditor><webMaster>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 10:13:42 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/microsoft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Microsoft Graph’s journey to HTTP/2</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/microsoft-graph-http2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 15:41:45 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/microsoft-graph-http2/</guid><description>For years Microsoft Graph has been serving billions of requests a day as one of the main REST APIs of Microsoft services. The service has become key infrastructure for Microsoft’s own applications, line of business solutions and third-party commercial solutions.
Any critical piece of infrastructure comes along with rigorous responsibilities: maintain, support, and secure. And sometimes this infrastructure needs to be “upgraded” to the latest standards which improve the value provided to its users through better safety, better interoperability, and better performance.</description></item><item><title>Shipping a product at Microsoft: Kiota</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/shipping-kiota-microsoft/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/shipping-kiota-microsoft/</guid><description>Introduction We recently announced the general availability of Kiota, an open source client generator for REST APIs with an OpenAPI description. I am the co-founder of this product, and this launch matches my 3 years anniversary at Microsoft, so I thought I would take the time to write about my experience of taking a product from idea to v1 at Microsoft.
Throughout my career, I have been involved with multiple “products”: a second-hand marketplace for industrial hardware, an enterprise social network solution, a localization and translation solution for SharePoint, and an IoT based temperature management optimization solution.</description></item><item><title>One year as a Software Developer at Microsoft</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/one-year-developer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/one-year-developer/</guid><description>One year as a Software Developer at Microsoft Introduction Back in September 2020, I published a blog post about my experience as a Program Manager at Microsoft that was well received. It made me realize that the community was curious and interested about this role. In this post, I will share my insights as a developer.
Before we begin, keep in mind this is my personal experience, which may differ a lot from team to team, product to product and depend on other circumstances (being remote, culture, etc…).</description></item><item><title>Joining Microsoft as a Program Manager on the Microsoft Graph</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/joining-microsoft-as-a-program/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 11:22:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/joining-microsoft-as-a-program/</guid><description>TL; DR I’ll be starting at Microsoft as a Program Manager on the Microsoft Graph in January. This is an exiting change and I’d like to take the time to thank 2toLead for the amazing last few years.
New role I’m exited to announce I’ll be starting at Microsoft in January as a Program Manager on the Microsoft Graph (and other Microsoft Identity Platform topics). I’ll be part of the MIP organization and in the extended team of brilliant people like Yina Arenas, Jeremy Thake, Darrel Miller and many more.</description></item><item><title>Re-awarded Microsoft MVP for year 2017 2018</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/re-awarded-microsoft-mvp-for-y/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/re-awarded-microsoft-mvp-for-y/</guid><description>You may not know it but Microsoft has changed the organization of the MVP program during these last few years. They used to nominate new MVP’s every 3 months and renew people every year on anniversary date. One of the changes the brought to the program is around the renew and nomination cycles. New MVP’s are awarded every month and existing ones are renewed all together every year in July. I used to be an “April MVP” and I was used to blogging about my renewal in April.</description></item><item><title>New Microsoft Conference: the AzureCon</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/new-microsoft-conference-the-a/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>vbiret+blog@outlook.com (Vincent Biret)</author><guid>https://baywet.github.io/new-microsoft-conference-the-a/</guid><description>Hi everybody!
Short post to let you know that Microsoft recently announced a new event: the AzureCon. First edition on Sept the 29th.
This free online event will focus on Microsoft’s cloud technologies (mostly Azure) and will be about news and things to come on the platform.
Great speakers, awesome content, this is the occasion for you to learn a lot about Azure technologies and their usage.
This conference should happen multiple times a year (approximately 4), main reason being: ”with releases and updates every 3 weeks for each service, we simply couldn’t wait for an annual event to announce everything like we do with Ignite and Build” (Microsoft Azure Product Manager)</description></item></channel></rss>