<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Resources on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/resources/</link><description>Recent content in Resources on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 11:06:28 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Localizing JavaScript of a Full Trust solution</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/localizing-javascript-of-a-ful/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2014 03:58:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/localizing-javascript-of-a-ful/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>We, SharePoint developers of ancient times when &amp;ldquo;full trust&amp;rdquo; solutions ruled, have understood one thing: using JavaScript improves by far our solutions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Indeed this allows to reduce the load of the servers and makes the user experience more &amp;ldquo;responsive&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But what if you want to display messages in different languages depending on the user? In .NET (understand server-side) it is quite simple, just use of resources. (&lt;a href="../the-name-initializecon">see one of my posts on the subject&lt;/a>)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Managing Resources, how to make your SharePoint solutions “globally deployed”</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/managing-resources-how-to-make/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 03:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/managing-resources-how-to-make/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="clip_">&lt;img src="https://baywet.github.io/managing-resources-how-to-make/clip_5F00_image002_5F00_thumb_5F00_0FECB56F.jpg" alt="clip_5F00_image002_5F00_thumb_5F00_0FECB56F.jpg">&lt;/h3>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I wanted to publish this article months ago, back to the time I found this solution. But I did not mostly because of a lack of free time. Sebastien LEVERT, a top SharePoint developer and a member of Montreal’s SharePoint community, recently published a post about the same subject. Read it (sorry it’s in French), I’ll write my post so it is complementary. &lt;a href="https://www.pimpmysharepoint.com/2014/01/09/deployer-des-fichiers-de-ressources-simplement/">https://www.pimpmysharepoint.com/2014/01/09/deployer-des-fichiers-de-ressources-simplement/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="reminders">Reminders&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To quickly summarize, when you develop SharePoint solutions and you want to support multiple languages (localize it) you need to use .net resources. These resx files are a mechanism coming from asp.net and work as a dictionary (key/value). You have to create one file by supported language. Instead of writing texts in the code (which is a bad practice anyway), you now reference these by defined keys.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>(English) The name 'InitializeControl' does not exist in the current context Controles utilisateur, SharePoint 2013 and Ressources</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/the-name-initializecon/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2013 21:21:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/the-name-initializecon/</guid><description>&lt;p>This article is written for SharePoint developers who already developed multilingual webparts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is a good practice to localize an application when you develop for SharePoint, which will make the adding of a new language easier.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When we developed for SharePoint 2010 we used to put resources files in hive/config/resources (and then run a stsadm –o copyappbincontent or automate it via a timerjob when activating features)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Or we used to create an empty SharePoint solution element in which we added our files and indicated that the deployment target was the appglobalresources folder (see &lt;a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/296003/deploy-a-resource-file-to-app-globalresource-folder-on-activation">https://stackoverflow.com/questions/296003/deploy-a-resource-file-to-app-globalresource-folder-on-activation&lt;/a> for more details)&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>