<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Brussels on Baywet's blog</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/tags/brussels/</link><description>Recent content in Brussels on Baywet's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 20:13:02 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baywet.github.io/tags/brussels/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Speaking at CollabDays Belgium 2022</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-collabdays-belgium-2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 12:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-collabdays-belgium-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I’m honoured to announce that I’ve been selected to speak at the &lt;a href="https://www.collabdays.org/2022-belgium/"&gt;CollabDays Belgium 2022&lt;/a&gt; (formerly SPS Events, aka SharePoint Saturday) happening in Brussels Saturday 15th of October. This event is dear to my heart as it’s one of the first international events I ever got to speak at, it always attracts a great crowd and brings together internationally regarded speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll be presenting “Turbocharge your API integration with Microsoft Kiota” where I’ll be introducing through lots of demonstrations how you can generate a client generated for any OpenAPI described API using &lt;a href="https://microsoft.github.io/kiota"&gt;Microsoft Kiota&lt;/a&gt; and other tools.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday Brussels 2016</title><link>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-09-22-14-00-00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://baywet.github.io/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturda-2016-09-22-14-00-00/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This year I have the privilege to speak at SPS Brussels&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll give a speech about “setting up your release pipeline for office 365/SharePoint”. (aka devops)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll see together how you can leverage azure and visual studio team services to implement devops processes and increase quality and save time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re in the area on Oct the 15th don’t hesitate to register to the event. Just as a reminder SPS are free events organized by the community with lot of great sessions. This is a good occasion to expand your network, learn a lot of things and to spend a good day.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>